<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/siddhiH/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/siddhiH/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The object and the</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/siddhiH/articles/MT/2025-08-10_the-object-and-the-mirror/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/siddhiH/articles/MT/2025-08-10_the-object-and-the-mirror/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2025/08/10/the-object-and-the-mirror/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The object and the mirror&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;mlechcha-woman&#34;&gt;mlechcha woman&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Via an acquaintance, we ran into a middle-aged mleccha woman, who had survived a difficult health situation in her childhood. In premodern times, it might have been a death sentence, but she managed to survive to an age at which people would have often been dead in those times. But all was not naught, and she was left with a sahaja-dūradṛṣṭi-śakti and a bhūta-dṛṣṭi-śakti. The former capacity manifested in a peculiar fashion. She needed to first “connect’’ with some person in the dūrakṣetra in order for the śakti to manifest. Then the visions came in the form of flashes rather than a continuous film reel. They were like a series of static photographs that came one after the other. This strongly suggested to us that it was a left cerebral hemispheric process, perhaps mostly divorced from the right. Consistent with this, while she received the communications best when she closed her eyes, for the most intense connection, she had to turn her head as if visualizing something in her right visual field (the domain of the left cerebral hemisphere).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A nR^isiMha for obtaining siddhi-s</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/siddhiH/articles/MT/2009-04-11_a-nrisimha-for-obtaining-siddhi-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/siddhiH/articles/MT/2009-04-11_a-nrisimha-for-obtaining-siddhi-s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2009/04/11/a-nrisimha-for-obtaining-siddhi-s/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;R1’s father had been lead by a descendant of the famous medieval tAntrika lakShmIdhara to an extremely remote shrine of nR^isiMha amongst ruins in the kali~Nga country. This shrine is in a place known today as Sonepur and is not far away from a temple of the most exalted yoginI-jAla-shambara. R1’s father and the descendant of the said tantrika stated that they attained siddhi of several mantra-s from the pA~ncharAtra tantra-s when they performed brief japa before this lakShmI-nR^isiMha. I finally found a picture, albeit pretty hazy, of the same image.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A yogin and his dUtI</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/siddhiH/articles/MT/2008-11-04_a-yogin-and-his-duti/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/siddhiH/articles/MT/2008-11-04_a-yogin-and-his-duti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2008/11/04/a-yogin-and-his-duti/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Being fooled by the outward appearance of a prescription in a tantra, or by his instincts, or in modern times by pop culture, the common practitioner is incapable pairing with a dUtI for successful attainment of yoga. For such a common practitioner the kaula path, like the kula of vilAsinI-s, is not available. The kaula practice with a dUtI is only fruitful for the true yogin. For this yogin the dUtI truly manifests as his shakti. The yogin who is free from disease, who is possessed with the virility of 3 or more bulls, and who is in complete control of his retas and unmoved by the appearance of sundarI-s will alone be easily able to recognize a dUtI. To such a yogin the true dUtI will automatically appear as an abhisArikA. In a dark, quite place at night, ideally a shmashAna or a grove, he will meet her and mentally communicate without saying anything. The success in this communication will indicate the successful discovery of the dUtI. He will then go away and meet her again after a while, all the while controlling his senses. After this he is ready to rove in company of the dUtI to attain yogic perfection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
