<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Edward W on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/tao/articles/edwardw/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Edward W on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/tao/articles/edwardw/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Astrology</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/tao/articles/edwardw/astrology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/tao/articles/edwardw/astrology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1337074511959638019.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this most stimulating video, the learned Dr @JeffreyKotyk makes the case- iter alia- for considering astrology as part of religion, or indeed, a form of religion of itself. The argument he makes is roughly as such-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the earliest times, we find that the planets were treated as deities; even to this day we refer to the wandering stars by the name of Saturn, Jupiter, Venus etc. This is a common feature all across Eurasia&amp;ndash; India, Rome, Greece, even China, where the planets- which were initially perceived as simple manifestations of the 5 phases, eventually became treated as gods. &amp;lt;we shall provide one eg: a Daoist scripture, in which mantras for the 11 planets are found: &amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>continuous-revelation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/tao/articles/edwardw/continuous-revelation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/tao/articles/edwardw/continuous-revelation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.rattibha.com/thread/1644945620925546502&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was reading Goossaert&amp;rsquo;s excellent &lt;em&gt;Making the Gods speak&lt;/em&gt;, when an interesting thought came on me. Unlike Buddhism, the corpus of canonical texts for Daoism has never really closed. I was reading Goossaert&amp;rsquo;s excellent &lt;em&gt;Making the Gods speak&lt;/em&gt;, when an interesting thought came on me. Unlike Buddhism, the corpus of canonical texts for Daoism has never really closed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Making the Gods speak&lt;/em&gt; traces the history of divinely revealed texts through Chinese history- divinely composed texts that came to the mortal world. It could be as simple as a god/immortal handing a human being a sacred book (many examples) or a human encountering a god and receiving a revelation (as is the case with the beidou jing)- or indeed, practises like 扶乩 spirit writing which continue to this day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gods</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/tao/articles/edwardw/Gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/tao/articles/edwardw/Gods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1337074511959638019.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even then the definition of &amp;lsquo;god&amp;rsquo; ought to be used with caution in this case. James Miller&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;the way of highest clarity&amp;rdquo; is valuable in this regard, and worth citing in full.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Basically the gods of Shangqing daoism were not &amp;lsquo;personal&amp;rsquo; in the sense of possessing individual wills and personalities. Rather they are akin to bureaucrats; beings whose power does not derive from their own characteristics, but rather from their position in a hierarchy. He cites this example with the rite used when a person has successfully completed the various meditations to become an immortal. You basically encounter the gods and then tell them &amp;ldquo;I have done all that is required of me to become an immortal, please register me as one.&amp;rdquo; The god in this case has no individual will: they just register the applicant&amp;rsquo;s information as impersonally as a filing clerk registers documents.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
