<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Sallustus on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/sallustius/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Sallustus on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/sallustius/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On the Gods and The World by Sallustius</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/sallustius/on-the-gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/sallustius/on-the-gods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the Gods and The World by Sallustius&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Translation by Gilbert Murray in Five Stages of Greek Religion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-the-disciple-should-be-and-concerning-common-conceptions&#34;&gt;What the disciple should be; and concerning Common Conceptions&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Those who wish to hear about the Gods should have been well guided from childhood, and not habituated to foolish beliefs. They should also be in disposition good and sensible, that they may properly attend to the teaching.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;They ought also to know the common conceptions. Common conceptions are those to which all men agree as soon as they are asked; for instance, that all god [here and elsewhere, = godhood, divine nature] is good, free from passion, free from change. For whatever suffers change does so for the worse or the better; if for the worse, it is made bad; if for the better, it must have been bad at first.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/sallustius/summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/sallustius/summary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some of the Hermetic sage Sallustius&amp;rsquo;s views &lt;a href=&#34;../on-the-gods/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;On the Gods and the world&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; are extremely valuable in understanding the deva-s. Sallustius was a friend of the revered Roman emperor Caesar Julian the Apostate, who tried but ultimately failed to restore deva-dharma and was killed in a battle. Below are some pertinent quotes from a translation by Gilbert Murray in Five Stages of Greek Religion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gods-are-unchanging-unbegotten-eternal&#34;&gt;Gods are unchanging, unbegotten, eternal.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Neither are they separate from the first cause nor from one another, just as thoughts are not separate from mind nor acts of knowledge from the soul.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gods-are-incorporeal-and-not-in-space&#34;&gt;Gods are incorporeal, and not in space.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;To say that these objects are sacred to the Gods, like various herbs and stones and animals, is possible to sensible men, but to say that they are Gods is the notion of madmen - except, perhaps, in the sense in which both the orb of the sun and the ray which comes from the orb are colloquially called &amp;rsquo;the sun&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gods-are-effortless&#34;&gt;Gods are effortless&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;All this care for the world, we must believe, is taken by the Gods without any act of will or labor. As bodies which possess some power produce their effects by merely existing: e.g. the sun gives light and heat by merely existing; so, and far more so, the providence of the Gods acts without effort to itself and for the good of the objects of its forethought.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;myths-and-images&#34;&gt;Myths and images&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Summary: Myths are divine, are &amp;ldquo;like the Gods&amp;rdquo;, but are obviously not to be taken literally. They contain both commonly understandable declarations about the Gods and mysteries only understood by the wise. It&amp;rsquo;s paradoxes and uncouth elements mean also to alert us that their words are veils.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
