<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/jainaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/jainaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>More encounters with padmAvatI and the tantras of the jaina nAstikas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/jainaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-12-20_more-encounters-with-padmavati-and-the-tantras-of-the-jaina-nastikas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/jainaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2006-12-20_more-encounters-with-padmavati-and-the-tantras-of-the-jaina-nastikas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/12/20/more-encounters-with-padmavati-and-the-tantras-of-the-jaina-nastikas/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bp3.blogger.com/_ZhvcTTaaD_4/RYjoXe6AktI/AAAAAAAAAAM/ZAQDBiDjp9A/s1600-h/padubai.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/bp3.blogger.com/_ZhvcTTaaD_4/RYjoXe6AktI/AAAAAAAAAAM/ZAQDBiDjp9A/s320/padubai.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/bp3.blogger.com/_ZhvcTTaaD_4/RYjoXe6AktI/AAAAAAAAAAM/ZAQDBiDjp9A/s320/padubai.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Continuing with our encounters with padubai (padmAvatI), we come to that&#xA;expedition that opened to us the secrets of this deity. The our nAstIka&#xA;astronomer acquaintance of the 3rd varNa had mentioned that there was a&#xA;large idol of padmAvatI in the depression to the south of our city where&#xA;also lay an old temple of rudra. That leader amongst the shUdra-s told&#xA;us right then that he recalled that there also lay an old aniconic rock&#xA;of padubai. We desired to see this site and set out with our henchmen of&#xA;the 3rd and 4th varNa-s. We rode along on our “ashva-s” and reached the&#xA;said hamlet where vIrakals of old cattle herders, including perhaps the&#xA;ancestors of the Bhosles lay scattered. There shUdra-shreShTha led us to&#xA;a large scarlet-painted rock that was worshiped extensively by the local&#xA;tribesmen and cowherds as padubai. The vaiShya pointed us to a ruined&#xA;shrine where there was a large exquisite rock image of padmAvatI, which&#xA;he claimed was installed by a jinendra named pradyumna-sUri. We noted&#xA;that on the pedestal of the image of the devI was inscribed a peculiar&#xA;mantra:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;OM hrIM namo.astu bhagavati padmAvatI ehi ehi saM vauShaT ||&lt;br&gt;&#xA;There was something about the icon — one could feel the great goddess&#xA;with many arms, holding many weapons inspire a sense of awe. I had the&#xA;same feeling as what I felt only in the presence of another old idol of&#xA;the great mantrinI, who is sangIta-yoginI, at some other point in time.&#xA;I kept this in mind and was to learn more of it some months later.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The jaina view</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/jainaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2004-09-24_the-jaina-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/jainaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/2004-09-24_the-jaina-view/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/09/24/the-jaina-view/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The jainas possess some interesting divergent variants of the canonical Indo-Aryan myths. The harivaMsha of jinasena and the triShaShThi-salaka-puruSha charita of hemachandra is a rather rich source for such mythic material. The jaina view postulated the existance of 63 salaka-puruShas or notable figures who are like spokes in the wheel of time. Not unexpectedly the 63 includes the 24 tirthankaras. Other than these there are 12 chakravartins who start with the great bhArata. Then there are the 9 vAsudevas or the 9 nArAyaNas, 9 balabhadras and 9 prativAsudevas. In each epoch of the time wheel is born a vAsudeva or a nArAyaNa with an elder brother termed the balabhadra. A woman called a kR^itya is also born in each epoch to aid the vAsudeva in his acts. The evil in the world is spread by the prati-vAsudeva, who is finally killed in the show-down with the vAsudeva. Below are these entities:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nAstikas in ayodhy A</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/jainaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/nAstikas_in_ayodhyA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/jainaH/meta/MT_lekhAH/nAstikas_in_ayodhyA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There has been some talk on TL of the sanctity of ayodhyA for jaina-s. While the shruti mentions kurukShetra as a central spot of the Arya-s, the jaina jambudvIpa-praj~nApti talks of ayodhyA/sAketa as the central kShetra of the Arya-s. They hold that several of their ford-makers were born in the city. But their shrines to the ford-makers are not specifically associated with a shrine of rAmachandra aikShvAkava.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As for the bauddha-s their shrine of a tree growing out of the tathAgata&amp;rsquo;s toothbrush is said to be the south of the city. So, while their shrines are present, they are not specifically associated with that of rAma.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
