<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nyAya-vaisheShike/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nyAya-vaisheShike/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>maitreya’s atomism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nyAya-vaisheShike/articles/MT/2004-09-18_maitreyas-atomism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nyAya-vaisheShike/articles/MT/2004-09-18_maitreyas-atomism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/09/18/maitreyas-atomism/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The bhagavata purANa preserves the 5 anuShTubhs composed by glAva maitreya, the udgAtA of the kurus, when he was asked about the atomic doctrine by vidura vaichitravIrya. It contains a clear exposition of the atomic doctrine. It is interesting that these openly vaisheShika mantras are preserved along side the more theistic formulation of typical of the sAMkhya associated with pA~ncharatra. It may also suggest the source for the elements of atomism in vaiShNava tantras like the lakShmI tantraM.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consciousness - Hard problem</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nyAya-vaisheShike/articles/MT/consciousness-hard-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nyAya-vaisheShike/articles/MT/consciousness-hard-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After all the hard problem has more of a philosophical implication: if you ask an average person is another man conscious, they will say yes. If you next ask them is a fly is conscious then some would agree it is. If you as them if a plant is conscious even fewer might. If you ask them a stone is conscious most might say no. Now if you ask them the reason for their responses then some might invoke some aspect of biology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>vaisheShika-sUtras and science</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nyAya-vaisheShike/articles/MT/vaisheShika-sUtras_and_science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nyAya-vaisheShike/articles/MT/vaisheShika-sUtras_and_science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oocities.org/somasushma/atom.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The vaisheShika sUtras and the science of the ancient Hindus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Philosophical thought of the Indo-Aryans underwent considerable diversification in the Indian subcontinent towards the end of the vedic period and the periods that followed it. The rough temporal span of this development can be taken to be from 1000 BC to 850 AD and accompanied the political unification of greater India under various indigenous dynasties. Six principal spheres of thought or darshanas originating in this period are followed amidst the mainstream Hindus and include nyAya, vaisheShika, sAMkhya, yoga, mImAmsa and vedanta. In addition to these, there were more heterodox philosophical systems such as jaina, bauddha and charvAka that were excluded from mainstream Hindu thought due to lack of firm affliations to the classic vedic texts. The principle six claimed to be based on the vedas but strikingly differed from each other due to differential interpretation of the vedic texts. Of these systems nyAya and vaisheShika developed the atomic theory of matter and represent some of the most advanced sections of Hindu thought. Below, I briefly consider the development of the ideas on nature of matter that are expounded in the vaisheShika sUtras of kaNAda.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
