<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;03 The Liturgy of the Cosmos on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;03 The Liturgy of the Cosmos on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>12 Cult and Cosmos</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/12_Cult_and_Cosmos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/12_Cult_and_Cosmos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;God is the leader of these things…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iamblichus believed that theurgy was entirely compatible with Plato’s teachings on the soul and that it provided a practical solution to the problem of embodiment. Yet Iamblichus’s apology for theurgy did more than address the philosophical problem of the soul’s embodiment; more generally, it provided a defense of religious ritual against well-known arguments brought forward by Porphyry in his letter to Anebo and his treatise On the Abstinence of Animal Food. Far from being a mere propaideia to philosophy, Iamblichus argued that the concrete performance of ritual was the culmination of one’s philosophical development. Theurgy tied soteriology to cosmogony and allowed the soul to share in both.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Ritual and the Human Hierarchy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/13_Ritual_and_the_Human_Hierarchy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/13_Ritual_and_the_Human_Hierarchy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even the perfect soul is imperfect&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;when compared with divine&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;action.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;heurgic rites reflected the order of the gods and therefore played a role in cosmogenesis, but since human souls per-Tformed the rites their differences influenced the form and intensity of their theurgies. Given the variety of human beings it would be impossible to see how theurgic ritual mirrors cosmogony unless one first understands how Iamblichus conceived these differences. Not surprisingly, he divides human souls into three classes distinguished by their purposes for descending into bodies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Ritual as Cosmogony</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/14_Ritual_as_Cosmogony/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/14_Ritual_as_Cosmogony/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The omission, even of few things,&#xA;subverts the entire effect of&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;worship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To divide theurgists into three groups corresponding to three levels of the cosmos suggests a static structure, with each soul assigned a specific rank to worship a specific class of gods fixed in its rank. Although this schema is not inaccurate it overlooks the vitality of the structure, the dynamic character of theurgy as the unifying energeia of the gods. Cosmogonically theurgic action was philia, the demiurgic weaving of opposites (cf. In Nic. 73, 1–5), and it should be remembered that theurgic rites were performances that initiated human souls into the activity of the gods.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Material Sunthemata</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/15_Material_Sunthemata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/15_Material_Sunthemata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Immaterial beings are present in&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;material natures immaterially.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iamblichus used the terms sunthema, sumbolon, and semeia, to describe respectively the theurgic “token,” “symbol,” or “sign” that divinized the soul. Iamblichus’s use of the term sunthema probably derived from the Chaldean Oracles where it was synonymous with sumbolon. In fragment 108 of the Oracles, the sumbola are said to be “sown . . . throughout the cosmos” by the Paternal Demiurge,1 and Ruth Majercik explains that these symbols “can be equated with the Platonic Forms” ( CO, 182). The sunthemata of the Oracles had a cosmogonic role like the Forms of Middle Platonism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Intermediate Sunthemata— Seeing and Hearing the Gods</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/16_Intermediate_Sunthemata_Seeing_and_Hearing_the_Gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/16_Intermediate_Sunthemata_Seeing_and_Hearing_the_Gods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sounds and melodies are conse-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;crated to each one of the Gods…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ecause intermediate souls performed a combination of noetic and material rites, they necessarily employed material sunthe-B mata. Indeed, material sunthemata would not have been inap-propriate for purely noetic souls either since material rites were guided by the same gods and, by analogia, in the same way as noetic rites. Nevertheless, there are forms of worship discussed in the De Mysteriis that exhibit less material characteristics than those discussed previously, and for heuristic purposes the objects used in these rites will be designated as “intermediate sunthemata.” These were the visible and audible sunthemata that Iamblichus described in the De Mysteriis as hieratic characters, symbols, names, and musical compositions. Although the designation “intermediate” is my own, I believe the distinction is consistent with Iamblichus’s thought. Following Iamblichus’s principle that the law of worship derived from the order of the gods, the visible and audible symbols mediated between immaterial and material realms just as liberated gods mediated between the hypercosmic and encosmic realms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Intermediate *Sunthemata*— Naming the Gods</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/17_Intermediate_Sunthemata_Naming_the_Gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/17_Intermediate_Sunthemata_Naming_the_Gods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*We Egyptians do not use words, *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;but sounds…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ne might assume, with Porphyry, that since “names” fall within the order of discourse they would have discursive Omeanings, so he asked why theurgists recited “names without meaning” ( &lt;em&gt;ta asema onomata&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;DM&lt;/em&gt; 254, 15). Iamblichus replied contentiously that such names “are not meaningless” ( &lt;em&gt;ta de ouk&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;estin asema&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;DM&lt;/em&gt; 254, 16) even if they are “unknowable” ( &lt;em&gt;agnosta&lt;/em&gt;) to us: “to the Gods, however, they are all meaningful, but not in a way that can be described, or in a manner that is significant or indicative to men through their imaginations” ( &lt;em&gt;DM&lt;/em&gt; 254, 18–255, 3). These names, he continues, were revealed through the intellect of the gods or remained completely ineffable ( &lt;em&gt;aphthengtos&lt;/em&gt;) and intelligibly united with them ( &lt;em&gt;DM&lt;/em&gt; 255, 4–6). Therefore, Iamblichus says: It is necessary to remove all conceptions and logical deductions from divine names, and to remove as well the physical imitations of the voice naturally akin to the things in nature. Rather, it is the symbolic character of divine resemblance, intellectual and divine, that must be accepted in the case of divine names. [ &lt;em&gt;DM&lt;/em&gt; 255, 6–&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Noetic*Sunthemata*— Mathematics and the Soul</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/18_NoeticSunthemata_Mathematics_and_the_Soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/18_NoeticSunthemata_Mathematics_and_the_Soul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The soul contains in itself the&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*sum-total of mathematical reality. *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;n the &lt;em&gt;De Mysteriis&lt;/em&gt;, Iamblichus says he will not discuss noetic forms of worship; but to pursue the division of &lt;em&gt;sunthemata&lt;/em&gt; into Imaterial, intermediate, and noetic categories, I would argue that the soul’s noetic powers would have to be transformed by noetic objects, and that these would have been best exemplified in numbers. An implicit arithmetic influence is evident already in the intermediate &lt;em&gt;sunthemata&lt;/em&gt;, for a numerical framework determines the composition of theurgic incantations and melodies. Since Iamblichus was a Pythagorean, it seems likely that he would have given mathematics a central role in the highest form of worship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Noetic*Sunthemata*— The Theurgy of Numbers</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/19_NoeticSunthemata_The_Theurgy_of_Numbers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/19_NoeticSunthemata_The_Theurgy_of_Numbers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*A man of this kind is above all law. *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If, as I have argued, mathematics formed an essential part of the worship of the gods, Iamblichus left no practical guide for its theurgic use. Proclus and Damascius provide the only references to a theurgy of numbers and even they give little concrete detail. In &lt;em&gt;Platonic Theology&lt;/em&gt; IV where Proclus discusses the anagogic power of numbers he says:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The unifying numbers, in themselves, are unknowable. For they are more ancient than Beings and more unified than Forms, and since they are the generators of Forms they exist prior to those beings we call “intelligibles” ( &lt;em&gt;noeta&lt;/em&gt;). The most august of theurgies demonstrate this, since they make use of numbers capable of acting ineffably, and by means of them, they effect the greatest and most ineffable of operations.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 The *Sunthema* of the Sun</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/20_The_Sunthema_of_the_Sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/03_The_Liturgy_of_the_Cosmos/20_The_Sunthema_of_the_Sun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The theologians call the sun&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Fire, channel of Fire . . . and&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*dispenser of Fire.” *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*— * The Chaldean Oracles&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;he two kinds of descent outlined in the previous chapter may help shed light on Iamblichus’s distinction in the &lt;em&gt;De Anima&lt;/em&gt; Tbetween souls who voluntarily and involuntarily enter bodies. Iamblichus subdivided the former group into souls who were (a) already free and entered the corporeal realm to preserve it and (b) those who were imperfect but were working toward perfection ( &lt;em&gt;Stob&lt;/em&gt;. I, 380, 6–14). The descent of this latter type of soul was neither entirely a corruption nor a creative participation in genesis though it was moving toward the latter. The great majority of souls, however, were embodied involuntarily and were completely verged toward &lt;em&gt;to apeiron&lt;/em&gt;. Nevertheless, in Iamblichus’s estimation, even these souls could participate in cosmogenesis if they limited their passions with material theurgies. The material rites laid the foundation for the soul’s final exchange of a life shaped by the &lt;em&gt;perata&lt;/em&gt; of daimons, for a life bestowing &lt;em&gt;peras&lt;/em&gt; upon &lt;em&gt;apeiron&lt;/em&gt;, like the gods. The divinity appropriate to the soul guided each rite, and as the soul became increasingly aligned with cosmogonic measures, so did its awareness of the gods.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
