<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Linus: On nautre</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/MT/linus_on_nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/MT/linus_on_nature/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Linus: “On the nature of the world”&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So through discord all things are steered through all.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;From the whole are all things, all things form a whole,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;all things are one, each part of all, all in one;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;for from a single whole all these things came, and from them in due time will one return,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;that&amp;rsquo;s ever one and many&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Often the same will be again, no end will limit them, ever limited&amp;hellip;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;For so undying death+++(5)+++ invests all things,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;all dies that&amp;rsquo;s mortal,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;but the substrate was and is immortal ever, fashioned thus,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;yet with strange images and varied form&lt;br&gt;&#xA;will change and vanish from the sight of all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nonnus-purANa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/MT/nonnus-purANa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/MT/nonnus-purANa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: TW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IMO one of the last of the surviving yavana &amp;ldquo;purANa-s&amp;rdquo;, composed just before the destruction of Classical world by the preta, that of Nonnus the Egyptian on his chosen god Dionysus preserves several old strands. Its focus is the &amp;ldquo;holy war&amp;rdquo; waged by Dionysus on the Hindus to make them Bacchanalian wine-addicts. However, the account seems confused, melding African peoples, like Ethiopians, and West Asians with H.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Egyptian&amp;rsquo;s topos of India begins in West Asia itself. His conquest of India is alluded to in several Greek sources but this late version is perhaps an expression of what could be called a &amp;ldquo;wishful&amp;rdquo; figment existing in the yavana world longing for revenge for the defeats of the yavana-s in India &amp;amp; loss of the Alexandrian conquests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Soothsaying</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/MT/soothsaying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/MT/soothsaying/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A selection from the Orphic Argonautika showing elements of yavana soothsaying and ritual.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;And you have learned the ways of divination by beasts and birds,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and what the order of entrails,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and what is presaged in their dream-roaming paths by souls of mortals overcome in sleep;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;answers to signs and portents, the stars&amp;rsquo; courses, the purification rite, great blessing to men, placation of gods, and offerings poured out for the dead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
