<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/sauraH/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/sauraH/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some more observations on the saura mata</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/sauraH/MT_lekhAH/2006-10-21_some-more-observations-on-the-saura-mata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/sauraH/MT_lekhAH/2006-10-21_some-more-observations-on-the-saura-mata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/10/21/some-more-observations-on-the-saura-mata/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We had earlier compiled incomplete accounts of both the &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/11/21/saura-mata/&#34;&gt;saura&#xA;mata&lt;/a&gt; and&#xA;its offshoots like the worship of&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/08/31/the-deva-revanta-mythology-iconography-history-and-ritualism/&#34;&gt;revanta&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;We initially wanted to work on the final part of the incomplete revanta&#xA;essay dealing with the specific point of the evolution of shAstA from&#xA;revanta and the relationship between their tantric prayogas. Then we&#xA;realized we never put together the additional material from the various&#xA;purANas on the core saura mata that we originally intended. Since a few&#xA;interlocutors had brought up saura issues and the original essay was too&#xA;old we decided to put this part separately. This as such is common&#xA;knowledge amongst Hindus educated in purANa-s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>saura mata</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/sauraH/MT_lekhAH/2005-11-21_saura-mata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/sauraH/MT_lekhAH/2005-11-21_saura-mata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/11/21/saura-mata/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In bR^ihatsamhita 60.19 varAhamihira states that sUrya should be&#xA;worshipped by installing idols of his and they should be worshipped by&#xA;specialized priests called magAchAryas. This is corroborated by the&#xA;bhavishya purANa chapter 139 that narrates the following tale (a&#xA;critical reconstruction of it):&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;kR^ishNa, the hero of the yadus married jAMbavati, the daughter of the&#xA;bear-king jAmbavAn. Their son was the valiant sAmba. He went to the&#xA;banks of the river chandrabhAga and constructed temple in the honor of&#xA;sUrya. No local brAhmaNa knew of the mysteries of his worship and hence&#xA;could not take up priesthood at the temple. So sAMba sought help of&#xA;gauramukha, the adviser of the yadu chief, ugrasena. gauramukha asked&#xA;him to go to shakadvipa and obtain a special class of priests called&#xA;magAchAryas to worship sUrya. saMba said:” pray, tell me Oh brAhmaNa&#xA;what are the antecedents of these worshippers of the sun. gauramukha&#xA;narrated: “The first of the brahmins amidst the shakhas was called&#xA;sujihva. He founded a gotra termed the mihira gotra. He had a daughter&#xA;of the name nikShubhA. sUrya was enamoured by her and impregnated her.&#xA;Thus she gave birth to jarashabda who was the founding father of all the&#xA;magachAryas. They are distinguished by the sacred girdle called the&#xA;avyanga that they wear around their waist”. saMba there upon called on&#xA;kR^ishNa to send him garuDa and flying on his back he landed in shaka&#xA;dvIpa. He collected the magAchAryas, brought them back to bhArata and&#xA;installed them as priests of his sUrya temple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
