<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hindus on the hard problem</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/articles/MT/2006-10-02_hindus-on-the-hard-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/articles/MT/2006-10-02_hindus-on-the-hard-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/10/02/hindus-on-the-hard-problem/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We had earlier mentioned the interesting discussion we had with Marc and&#xA;kalashajA on what the western philosophers admit is the hard problem of&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://manollasa.blogspot.com/2004/06/we-are-zombies.html&#34;&gt;consciousness&lt;/a&gt;.&#xA;Our other acquaintance of the clan of the kAshyapa-s, had asked me if&#xA;the Indians had contributed anything to the problem. He intuitively felt&#xA;they had done so, but could not place a finger on it. Marc, R and I had&#xA;some further discussion, and realized I knew less of it than I thought I&#xA;did. As a result it was not certain that I had a defensive argument for&#xA;all my original stances on the matter, and definitely consider it an&#xA;area of my thought that is still shaping. However, in answer to the&#xA;kAshyapa’s queries, and for some discussions with our friend graced by&#xA;the wife of mahArudra, I tried to represent the Hindu approach to this&#xA;problem. To me it appears that the Hindus have made a deep foray into&#xA;this matter exploring areas that are not chartered by modern western&#xA;philosophers. To describe this domain of thought of the archaic Hindus&#xA;and to certain extant their yavana cousins I resort to the term&#xA;ekAntika, adapting it from the early pA~ncharAtrins of the sAttvata&#xA;region. ekAntika can be broadly said to include philosophical theories&#xA;such as: advaita, vishiShTAdvaita, samvit-prakAsha and allied&#xA;pA~ncharAtric thought, pratyabhij~na and the yavana monism. Here, I&#xA;seek not to discuss the entire history; at some point if we are alive,&#xA;time permitting, I will detail the history of Hindu philosophy from the&#xA;particular point of the action of mantra-tantra shAstra that is the&#xA;under-girding of the whole Hindu religious practice. Here we shall only&#xA;look at some Hindu ideas including advaita, which is one of the ekAntika&#xA;philosophical theories that is widely studied by hindus since its&#xA;expansive elucidation by sha~Nkara bhagavatpAda and his successors. I&#xA;do not want to even pretend being anything close to an expert on this&#xA;system, but only dwell on points relevant to the issue of consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antar-yAmitA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/articles/MT/antar-yAmitA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/articles/MT/antar-yAmitA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;mano [ha vai] devA manuShyasya+AjAnanti |&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A vedic saying from the shatapatha brAhmaNa which appears in the AV as:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;manasA saM kalpayati tad devAM api gachChati |&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To us, this has philosophical implications (especially for polytheists like us).&lt;br&gt;&#xA;As per the theory of the SYVs this cognition is passed to gods by tanU napAt manifesting as the metabolism comprised of prANa and udAna.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;So the gods do not precognize but the thought reaches them post-facto via an effect on metabolism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brit ghost sightings</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/articles/MT/brit-ghost-sightings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/articles/MT/brit-ghost-sightings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The next case is from General H., who, unfortunately, will not permit the publication of his name. The account was procured through the kindness of Miss A. A. Leith, of 8, Dorset Square, N.W.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November 11th, 1884. (226)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“In 1856 I was engaged on duty at a place called Roha, some 40 miles south of Bombay, and moving about in the districts (as it is termed in India). My only shelter was a tent, in which I lived for several months in the year. My parents, and only sister, about 22 years of age, were living at K., from which place letters used to take a week reaching me. My sister and I were regular correspondents, and the post generally arrived about 6 a.m., as I was starting to my work. It was on the 18th April of that year (a day never to be forgotten) that I received a letter from my mother, stating that my sister was not feeling well, but hoped to write to me the next day. There was nothing in the letter to make me feel particularly anxious. After my usual out-door work, I returned to my tent, and in due course set to my ordinary daily work. At 2 o&amp;rsquo;clock my clerk was with me, reading some native documents that required my attention, and I was in no way thinking of my sister, when all of a sudden I was startled by seeing my sister (as it appeared) walk in front of me from one door of the tent to the other, dressed in her nightdress.1 The apparition had such an effect upon me that I felt persuaded that my sister had died at that time. I wrote at once to my father, stating what I had seen, and in due time I also heard from him that my sister had died at that time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graha of Alma</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/articles/MT/graha_of_alma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/articles/MT/graha_of_alma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(The peculiar case of an American girl from 1895 CE, from a report by Mason in the JAMA. In H medicine the same might have been described as seizure by one of the skanda-graha-s or an agent of kubera.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alma Z. was an unusually healthy and intellectual girl, a strong and attractive character, a leading spirit in whatever she undertook, whether in study, sport, or society. From overwork in school, and overtaxed strength in a case of sickness at home, her health was completely broken down, and after two years of great suffering suddenly a second personality appeared. In a peculiar child-like and Indian-like dialect she announced herself as “Twoey,&amp;quot; and that she had come to help “Number One” in her suffering. The condition of “Number One” was at this time most deplorable; there was great pain, extreme debility, frequent attacks of syncope+++(=fainting)+++, insomnia, and a mercurial stomatitis+++(=lip inflammation)+++ which had been kept up for months by way of medical treatment and which rendered it nearly impossible to take nourishment in any form. “Twoey&amp;quot; was vivacious and cheerful, full of quaint and witty talk, never lost consciousness, and could take abundant nourishment, which she declared she must do for the sake of “Number One.&amp;quot;+++(5)+++ Her talk was most quaint and fascinating, but without a trace of the acquired knowledge of the primary personality. She gave frequent evidence of supranormal intelligence regarding events transpiring in the neighbourhood. It was at this time that the case came under my observation, and has remained so for the past ten years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn from platonists</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/articles/MT/learn_from_platonists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/articles/MT/learn_from_platonists/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1576296031746039809.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Warning long thread that&amp;rsquo;ll be part of future note:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is rather important that H who are inclined toward a proper polytheistic philosophy study the yavana tradition closely.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first reason is simple: having a related phylum at some distance from our own provides a comparative perspective that might clarify uncertain points because they might be augmented in it, or they help sharpen an ancestral signal that might not be otherwise discernable.+++(4)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>punarjanma</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/articles/MT/punarjanman/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/articles/MT/punarjanman/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;non-centrality-to-religion&#34;&gt;Non-centrality to religion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The second point where I call for circumspection is the insistence on the beliefs of punarjaman and/or mokSha as central belief elements of the H religion. They are important for uttaramImAMsA but that is not a universal scaffold for other H systems. I don&amp;rsquo;t discount the possibility that punarjaman was one of the greatest discoveries of the ancients that needs us to completely alter the framework of modern knowledge. However, I remain insufficiently convinced by the evidence favoring that position.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>siddhiH</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/articles/MT/siddhiH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/articles/MT/siddhiH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;group&#34;&gt;Group&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1735509258219762066&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While mantra-practicing yogin-s can attain several siddhi-s they are a rare minority. The attainment of siddhi of several mantra-s, especially of the shaiva &amp;amp; its derivative shAkta tradition are not easy for solitary sAdhaka despite having the predisposition &amp;amp; devoted practice. They usually need the &amp;ldquo;chakra&amp;rdquo; of sAdhaka-s for proper expression and may be seen only within that context. Many modern aspirants miss this aspect and hope they can attain these in isolation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
