<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 Mantra Yoga And Mantra as a Karmic Tool on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/1_Mantra_Yoga_And_Mantra_as_a_Karmic_Tool/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 Mantra Yoga And Mantra as a Karmic Tool on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/1_Mantra_Yoga_And_Mantra_as_a_Karmic_Tool/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Mantra and Primal Sound</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/1_Mantra_Yoga_And_Mantra_as_a_Karmic_Tool/01_Mantra_and_Primal_Sound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/1_Mantra_Yoga_And_Mantra_as_a_Karmic_Tool/01_Mantra_and_Primal_Sound/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-universal-tradition-of-sacred-sound&#34;&gt;The Universal Tradition of Sacred Sound&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All over the world we find traditions of special words of power, magical phrases or secret codes that can unlock the great mysteries of life otherwise unapproachable to the human mind. Such traditions occur in religion, occult sciences, mysticism, shamanism, and almost every known spiritual path. Poetry, literature and philosophy worldwide similarly recognize the power of the word, sound or prime concept to influence and move us at a very deep level. While accessing the cosmic powers may not be as simple as repeating a phrase like ‘open sesame’, there are key sounds and words that can dramatically reveal new vistas of insight and energy within us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Mantra and Classical Yoga</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/1_Mantra_Yoga_And_Mantra_as_a_Karmic_Tool/02_Mantra_and_Classical_Yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/1_Mantra_Yoga_And_Mantra_as_a_Karmic_Tool/02_Mantra_and_Classical_Yoga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Classical Yoga is one of the world’s most important approaches to Self-realization, to understanding our true nature beyond time and space, birth and death, suffering and limitation. Mantra in Sanskrit means the tool ‘tra’ of the mind ‘manas’. It is the primary tool of Yoga for calming the mind, which is necessary to allow us access to the higher Self. While classical Yoga through the Yoga Sutras of Patanjali does not make mantra specifically into one of Yoga’s eight limbs, it does regard mantra as a key practice relative to all aspects of Yoga.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Managing Your Karma with Mantra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/1_Mantra_Yoga_And_Mantra_as_a_Karmic_Tool/03_Managing_Your_Karma_with_Mantra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/1_Mantra_Yoga_And_Mantra_as_a_Karmic_Tool/03_Managing_Your_Karma_with_Mantra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Though mantra is central to all the branches of Yoga, the importance of mantra is not limited to Yoga and spiritual practices. There are special mantras to improve all human activities and our connections with the whole of life. In fact, mantra can help us do whatever we are doing better, with more awareness, more in tune with the greater universe of consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mantra is relevant for everyone for creating the greater harmony and well-being that we are all seeking. There are many different types of mantras and different ways to apply them depending upon our aims and intentions. There are mantras that each person can benefit from in his or her own way at any stage or circumstance of life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Energizing Mantras with Power and with Grace</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/1_Mantra_Yoga_And_Mantra_as_a_Karmic_Tool/04_Energizing_Mantras_with_Power_and_with_Grace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/1_Mantra_Yoga_And_Mantra_as_a_Karmic_Tool/04_Energizing_Mantras_with_Power_and_with_Grace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mantras require the proper energization for them to work in the best possible manner. How to awaken and empower the mantra is one of the most important considerations in the usage of any mantra. In the following chapter, we will explore the main methods and approaches for doing this. One must bring life to the mantra, which is to make the mantra not only part of your personal life but of the universal life around you. Energization of mantra in turn requires some guidance and connection with the greater tradition of Mantra Yoga.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 Mantra, the Divine Word and Cosmic Manifestation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/1_Mantra_Yoga_And_Mantra_as_a_Karmic_Tool/05_Mantra_the_Divine_Word_and_Cosmic_Manifestation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/1_Mantra_Yoga_And_Mantra_as_a_Karmic_Tool/05_Mantra_the_Divine_Word_and_Cosmic_Manifestation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many profound philosophies of mantra and the Divine Word in the different spiritual traditions of the world. Western philosophy and theology has aimed at the Logos or Divine Word, as perhaps its prime inspiration, since the time of the ancient Greeks. The great yogic philosophies of India have been rooted in mantra, of which the ancient Vedic philosophy is probably the oldest and most comprehensive. The Vedas teach how the entire universe in all its vastness arises from a single sound, just as the Big Bang theory of modern physics teaches how the entire universe arises from a single timeless and spaceless point. Yoga explains how our own psyche mirrors cosmic sound in the structure of our subtle body and its chakra centers, which are mantric formations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
