<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Intro on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/sangrahaH/shAnti-raxita-tattva-sangrahaH/gangAnAthaH/00_intro/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Intro on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/sangrahaH/shAnti-raxita-tattva-sangrahaH/gangAnAthaH/00_intro/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>0001 Introduction by Śāntarakṣita</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/sangrahaH/shAnti-raxita-tattva-sangrahaH/gangAnAthaH/00_intro/0001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/sangrahaH/shAnti-raxita-tattva-sangrahaH/gangAnAthaH/00_intro/0001/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: Śāntarakṣita is the author of the Tattvasaṃgraha.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This Tattvasaṃgraha, ‘Compendium of True Doctrines is being composed after bowing to that Omniscient Person, the greatest of expounders, who, with a view to bringing about the welfare of the world,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—propounded the Doctrine of the ‘Wheel of Intervolved Causation’,(&lt;em&gt;see notes below&lt;/em&gt;)—independently of any self-sufficient revelation,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;supreme mercy having entered into His very soul through long innumerable cycles.—(5-6)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;—This ‘Wheel of Causation’ is free from all notions of the functioning of any such cause as ‘Primordial Matter’,—‘God—both of these (Primordial Matter and God), —Soul, —and such other entities (postulated by Philosophers);—&lt;br&gt;&#xA;it is mobile;—&lt;br&gt;&#xA;it is the basis of all such notions as ‘Karma’ (Actions, good and bad), the fruits of acts, the connection between these two.—(1)—It is devoid of all such concepts as ‘Quality’, ‘Substance’, ‘Movement’, ‘Universal’, ‘Inherence’, and so on;—it is amenable to ‘words’ and ‘cognitions’ only in an assumed (superimposed) form.—(2).—It is definitely cognised by means of two clearly defined Means of Cognition; it is not mixed up with the nature of anything else, even in the slightest degree.—(3).—It admits of no translocation; it is without beginning and without end; it is like a reflected image and other such things; it is absolutely free from the whole lot of fantasies; it has not been apprehended by others.—(4).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>0002 Introduction by Kamalaśīla (verses 1-6)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/sangrahaH/shAnti-raxita-tattva-sangrahaH/gangAnAthaH/00_intro/0002/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/sangrahaH/shAnti-raxita-tattva-sangrahaH/gangAnAthaH/00_intro/0002/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note&lt;/em&gt;: Kamalaśīla is the author of the Pañjikā (commentary) on the Tattvasaṃgraha, also known as the Tattvasaṃgrahapañjikā.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After reverentially bowing to that World-Teacher, the best of the Knowers of Truth,—who, through mercy, made the World happy by alleviating the sufferings of Birth, Disease, Decay and the rest,—through the nectar of Truths obtained by the churning of the ocean of knowable things,—the clear ‘Commentary’ on the Compendium of True Doctrines is hereby commenced.—(1)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>0003 Introduction to second volume</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/sangrahaH/shAnti-raxita-tattva-sangrahaH/gangAnAthaH/00_intro/0003/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/sangrahaH/shAnti-raxita-tattva-sangrahaH/gangAnAthaH/00_intro/0003/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Much need not be said here in regard to the personal history of the two authors—regarding their (&lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt;) date, (&lt;em&gt;b&lt;/em&gt;) residence, (c) contact and relation with other writers; as all this has been dealt with in great detail in the excellent Foreword attached to Vol. I of the Sanskrit Text. From this we learn that our Authors—who were Master and Pupil—(&lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt;) lived between 705 and 764 A.D.,—(&lt;em&gt;b&lt;/em&gt;) they were residents of &lt;em&gt;Magadha&lt;/em&gt; in North India, from where they went over to Thibet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
