<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/confucianism/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/confucianism/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Aizawa on ritual</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/confucianism/articles/aizawa_on_ritual/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/confucianism/articles/aizawa_on_ritual/</guid>
      <description>&lt;details&gt;&lt;summary&gt;विस्तारः (द्रष्टुं नोद्यम्)&lt;/summary&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The phrase for this is saisei itchi (祭政一致) meaning the unity of ritual &amp;amp; government&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/details&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mito scholars&amp;rsquo; assertion that in antiquity the import of the fundamental principles of human relations had been conveyed to the populace through nonverbal means dovetailed with another dimension of their outlook: a belief in the efficacy of ritual that they inherited from Sorai together with suspicion of Song metaphysics and introspection. As the leading late Mito thinker Aizawa Seishisai (1782-1863) put it in an observation that clearly built on Sorai&amp;rsquo;s ideas, the people could not be made to understand, but they could be made to follow. To do so, however, a &amp;ldquo;tool&amp;rdquo; (gu) was necessary, and the only thing that could function effectively as such a tool was li+++(=ritual)+++. If li were used to &amp;ldquo;carry&amp;rdquo; the people, there would be no need to rely on strident and ultimately ineffective sermonizing. The people would instinctively &amp;ldquo;keep within the current&amp;rdquo; of what was correct.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Tao-bauddha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/confucianism/articles/anti-Tao-bauddha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/confucianism/articles/anti-Tao-bauddha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Confucians like to attack Daoism by claiming the religion Daoism founded by Zhang Daoling has little to do with the philosophy of Daoism founded by Li Er (Laozi). Religious Daoism claims that Li Er came back as a deity to appoint Zhang Daoling as Heavenly Master and his&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Btw Daoists themselves study Confucian texts and proclaim themselves to be Confucians, it&amp;rsquo;s the actual orthodox Confucians who attack Daoism and view it with disdain. Pretty much no one can criticize Confucianism - Buddhists and Daoists did not attack or criticize Confucius because his school is ingrained in Chinese culture while orthodox Confucians can freely insult, attack and criticize the other two.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sorai on ritual</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/confucianism/articles/sorai-on-ritual/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/confucianism/articles/sorai-on-ritual/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deviation from the ideas of li advocated by Song thinkers such as Zhu Xi may be found not only in Tokugawa discourse about family li but also in notions of the basis for the efficacy of ritual. It is most apparent in the writings of Ogyū Sorai, whose systematic recasting of the premises of Confucianism produced a sea change in its conceptual dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sorai directly challenged the assumption that through the enactment of li the individual realized an innate capacity for alignment with a natural moral order.+++(4)+++ In his view the very notion of an innate order encompassing both the human realm and Heaven was a misinterpretation that had resulted from ambiguities in the writings of successors of Confucius such as Zisi 7 and Mencius. The Way, Sorai held, was not something &amp;ldquo;natural.&amp;rdquo; It was nothing other than the totality of li and other institutions created by the ancient kings with the aim of bringing order to human society. Like those entities it thus was itself a human construction and necessarily external to the individual.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tokugawa-relationship-degrees</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/confucianism/articles/tokugawa-relationship-degrees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/confucianism/articles/tokugawa-relationship-degrees/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tokugawa Confucian approaches to the central object of ritual attention in Confucian ancestral rites, the spirit tablet (shinshu E, Chinese shenzhu), show other repercussions of a lack of attunement to degrees of relationship. According to Jiali, the spirit tablet was to be inscribed with the name of the deceased at the time of interment of the coffin. Installed in the family offering hall (shidō, Chinese citang), it served as the repository for the soul of the deceased and for the next several generations was the object of individual sacrifices by the deceased&amp;rsquo;s descendants. With each change in generation the tablet was reinscribed (to indicate, e.g., that what had been the tablet of a father was now that of a grandfather) and moved to a new place in the ancestral hall appropriate to its changed relationship with the sacrificer. Eventually, after &amp;ldquo;kinship was exhausted,&amp;rdquo; the tablet was removed from the offering hall to the grave site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
