<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;07 Yoga and Meditation on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/07_Yoga_and_Meditation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;07 Yoga and Meditation on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/07_Yoga_and_Meditation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>30 A Tantric Meditation on Emptiness</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/07_Yoga_and_Meditation/30_A_Tantric_Meditation_on_Emptiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/07_Yoga_and_Meditation/30_A_Tantric_Meditation_on_Emptiness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Donald S. Lopez, Jr.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From the origins of Tantric Buddhism in India, origins that remain in many ways  mysterious, questions have been raised about the relation of Tantra to the pre existing traditions of Buddhist thought and practice. These questions have been  faced by scholars and practitioners throughout the Buddhist world over the course  of centuries, and continue to intrigue modern scholars of Buddhism. One way of  posing the questions has been: Does Tantra represent a complete and autonomous  system that replaces and surpasses all that has come before, or is Tantra a sup plement to be appended to the traditional path?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 Japanese Tantra, the Tachikawa-ryu, and Ryobu Shinto</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/07_Yoga_and_Meditation/31_Japanese_Tantra_the_Tachikawa-ryu_and_Ryobu_Shinto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/07_Yoga_and_Meditation/31_Japanese_Tantra_the_Tachikawa-ryu_and_Ryobu_Shinto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bernard Faure&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scholars have often tried to define Buddhism through its theory of causality. The  Buddhist conception of karmic retribution, although derived from Brahmanic  thought, is usually presented as the most significant advance, not only over Brah manism but also over such other religious trends as Daoism and Confucianism,  which emphasized a system of cosmological connections based on &amp;ldquo;correlative  thinking.&amp;rdquo; In this respect, it is significant that Tantric Buddhism also emphasized  cosmological connections rather than linear causality, and seems to have returned  to the Vedic conception of man as a microcosm. This macro-microcosmic con ception of the universe as emanating from a first principle is a major departure  from early Buddhism which, never overly concerned with cosmogony, instead  focused on ontogeny; that is, on the series of causes forming the so-called twelve linked chain - from ignorance to birth and death - leading to the emergence of  the individual.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32 Assorted Topics of the Great Completeness by Dodrupchen III</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/07_Yoga_and_Meditation/32_Assorted_Topics_of_the_Great_Completeness_by_Dodrupchen_III/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/07_Yoga_and_Meditation/32_Assorted_Topics_of_the_Great_Completeness_by_Dodrupchen_III/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anne Carolyn Klein&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oral commentary by Khetsun Sangpo Rinpoche&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Great Completeness tradition is considered the highest of the hierarchically  arranged ninefold path described by the most ancient order of Tibetan Buddhism,  known as Nyingma. Great Completeness, or Dzogchen (rDzogs chen) entails,  above all, discovery of one&amp;rsquo;s actual, and utterly natural, condition. This condition  is also known as the base, and the process of coming to recognize it is the path.  Through such recognition the fruit, one&amp;rsquo;s own buddhahood, becomes manifest.  All three - base, path, and fruit - are in important ways identical, not causally  related or sequential. This text describes base, path, and fruit in terms of three  delightful and spontaneous qualities: smoothness, splendor, and freshness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>33 On the Seal of Sambhu: A Poem</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/07_Yoga_and_Meditation/33_On_the_Seal_of_Sambhu_A_Poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/07_Yoga_and_Meditation/33_On_the_Seal_of_Sambhu_A_Poem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;by Abhinavagupta&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Paul E. Muller-Ortega&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Anubhava-nivedana-stotra&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;Song of Praise Intended to Communicate  the Direct Experience of the Absolute&amp;rdquo; is a poetic composition in Sanskrit attrib uted to the eleventh-century Kashmiri Tantric master, Abhinavagupta. It is one  of but a handful of short poetic works or hymns of praise (stotras) attributed to  this important Tantric philosopher and theologian. Probably written toward the  end of his life as a kind of elegant summary of the author&amp;rsquo;s vision of Saiva mys ticism, the poem is an evocation of the experience of the ultimate consciousness&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 Jain Tantra: Divinatory and Meditative Practices in the Twelfth-Century Yogasastra of Hemacandra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/07_Yoga_and_Meditation/35_Jain_Tantra_Divinatory_and_Meditative_Practices_in_the_Twelfth-Century_Yogasastra_of_Hemacandra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/07_Yoga_and_Meditation/35_Jain_Tantra_Divinatory_and_Meditative_Practices_in_the_Twelfth-Century_Yogasastra_of_Hemacandra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Olle Qvarnstrom&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study of Jain medieval Sanskrit texts reveals a Tantric influence on the two  main traditions of Jainism - Digambara and Svetambara - both in the sense of  ideas and practices and in the sense of a literary class. This influence was restricted  neither geographically nor confessionally, and manifested itself within different  literary genres and contexts. Its impression is also visible in iconography and art.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The questions of the precise extent to which Tantra penetrated into Jainism,  the historical development of Jain Tantra, and its indebtedness to Hindu and  Buddhist Tantra are at the present stage of research not entirely clear, even though  their outlines have been sketched by scholars such as John Cort and Paul Dundas.  Many Tantric texts are still only available in manuscript form. Few have been  critically edited. For various reasons Jain Tantra has not caught the attention of  Indologists. This has in its turn made it difficult to integrate Jain Tantra into a  broader religious, cultural, and historical framework, as well as to define its dis tinctive character.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>36 Cheating Death</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/07_Yoga_and_Meditation/36_Cheating_Death/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/07_Yoga_and_Meditation/36_Cheating_Death/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michael Walter&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Death and dying are significant topics for all religions, including Buddhism. When  Tantra was the dominant form of Buddhism in both northern India and Tibet,  Buddhists displayed a voracious curiosity about this topic. Ritual and meditational  materials show a variety of methods for dealing with the process of decline and  death.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometime before the year 1000, Tantric teachings that dealt with preparation  for death, cremation, and so forth, had been organized into cycles. One group is  a set of teachings by Atisa, an eleventh-century Buddhist master from Bengal, on  the goddess Tara, called the &amp;ldquo;Thirteen Spells.&amp;rdquo; These teachings provide instruction  in recognizing and preparing for death, as well as in perpetuating the practice of  merit making, a process that allows a Buddhist to accrue merit for spiritual im&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
