<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On darshanas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/2006-12-28_on-darshanas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/2006-12-28_on-darshanas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/12/28/on-darshanas/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing many fellow traditional Hindus have found frustrating about me&#xA;is my lack knowledge and lack of affinity for the advaita stream of&#xA;vedanta, and more fundamentally me being a svatantra. My blasphemous&#xA;views regarding vedas and their apauruSheyatva are also hardly&#xA;appreciated in their midst. I am not shaken by their views because I am&#xA;pretty firm in my convictions on these matters arising from ongoing&#xA;study of the originals, and yAj~navalya always stands out as beacon.&#xA;These are indeed matters of worthy of deep historical study by any Hindu&#xA;and it is advisable that they take nothing for granted. The key to their&#xA;study is comparative philosophy – a term first suggested by&#xA;Brijendranath Seal, a modern va~Nga scholar of early Hindu thought.&#xA;Just like comparative linguistics is central to the understanding of&#xA;Sanskrit, the language of Hindu thought, comparative philosophy is&#xA;central to understanding the evolution of Hindu thought. It should be&#xA;amply clear that the fundamental aspects of Hindu thought cannot be&#xA;understood without comparative linguistics and philosophy, a point so&#xA;blithely neglected by many traditional Hindus. Of course like most other&#xA;sketches presented here the below ramblings are not completely worked&#xA;out pieces of research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The iconography of diverse goddesses</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/2006-10-06_the-iconography-of-diverse-goddesses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/2006-10-06_the-iconography-of-diverse-goddesses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/10/06/the-iconography-of-diverse-goddesses/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Wodeyar of Mysore, kR^iShNa rAja, prepared a compendium of Hindu&#xA;iconography from diverse classical Hindu sources. This collation called&#xA;the shrI-tattva-nidhI (STN) has become a useful standard for upAsaka-s&#xA;in amongst educated Hindus, especially from Southern India. Sadly, the&#xA;full text is not easily accessible these days. It is useful to examine&#xA;the succinct descriptions of iconography that he provides in his text.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The STN is divided into 9 chapters:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Tantric” upaniShad-s and their role in Hindu thought</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/2006-07-29_tantric-upanishad-s-and-their-role-in-hindu-thought/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/2006-07-29_tantric-upanishad-s-and-their-role-in-hindu-thought/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/07/29/tantric-upanishad-s-and-their-role-in-hindu-thought/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The point of origin of the later sectarian upaniShads is unclear. It&#xA;appears that the early shaiva-s and vaiShNava-s had begun the composing&#xA;upaniShadic material in the latest phase of the vedic era. The oldest&#xA;amongst these is the shaiva-leaning upaniShad- shvetAshvatara, which&#xA;incorporates several verses from the shatarudriya of the&#xA;kR^iShNa-yajurveda. The atharva-shiras and the nArAyaNa-valli seem to&#xA;the next set of upaniShads composed by the shaivas and vaiShNavas&#xA;respectively. The bahvR^icha upaniShad with a shrIkula orientation is of&#xA;unclear provenance, eventhough its character suggests that it is&#xA;definitely much later than the former upaniShads. Beyond these there are&#xA;a series of “tantric” upaniShad-s that appear even later and their sole&#xA;purpose appears to be expound particular tantric mantra-s.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Examples of these include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>shrI vidyAraNaya yati and his shrIvidyArNava</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/2006-03-26_shri-vidyaranaya-yati-and-his-shrividyarnava/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/2006-03-26_shri-vidyaranaya-yati-and-his-shrividyarnava/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/03/26/shri-vidyaranaya-yati-and-his-shrividyarnava/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The shrIvidyArNava is an excellent tAntric manual that was used as&#xA;textbook for mantra shAstra instruction amongst certain brahminical&#xA;schools. It contains 2 halves called pUrva and uttara ardha-s of 18&#xA;chapters called shvAsas each. It runs into 1459 devanagari print pages&#xA;to give an idea of its size. It is a digest for a wide range of material&#xA;from ancient tantras that appear to be lost. One of these is the&#xA;kukkuTeshvara tantra, whose prayogas are still remembered by several&#xA;practioners even if only in fragments. The other archaic tantras cited&#xA;by it include : 1) kulArNava 2) vAmakeshvara 3) yoginI hR^idya 4)&#xA;tantra-rAja 5) pheTkAriNi 6) the yAmalas 7) bR^ihadnIlA 8)&#xA;siddha-sarasvatI 9) pi~Ngala mata 10) pA~nchrAtra saMhitAs 11)&#xA;kulaprakAsha 12) dakshiNAmurti saMhitA 13) bhairava tantras 14)&#xA;kAlimata. Interestingly it also cites digests of vaiShNava tantric&#xA;material outside of the classical pA~ncharAtra. These include 1)&#xA;shrikrama nArAyaNIya and 2) bR^ihat nArAyaNIya. It also cites secondary&#xA;tantric encyclopedia such as the shAradA-tilakaM. In its general form&#xA;the shrividyArNava is a relatively late digest coming at the end of a&#xA;long line of such texts including prapa~nchasAra, shAradA tilakaM,&#xA;mantramahodadhi, bR^ihat-tantrasAra, mantrArNava and tantrasArasaMgraha.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Agama-mImAMsA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/Agama-mImAMsA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/Agama-mImAMsA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some traditions developed their own unified theory similar to mImAMsA: e.g. parshurAma-kalpasUtra-s for the shrIkula tradition. abhinavagupta&amp;rsquo;s tantrAloka can be seen as another such synthesis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, the main issue is the basic focal &amp;amp;/ sectarian nature of most tAntrika traditions. Hence, 1 could complain that these works are narrow &amp;amp; not overarching like mImAMsA addresses the vaidika ritual. In that sense we align with the the message of thread.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, as a smArta, while I&amp;rsquo;m a (low level) practitioner of the tAntrika religion, like many of my ilk over the centuries we have an inclination for an overarching structure with mImAMsA akin to that done in the older vaidika religion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Babaisms and apports</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/bAbaisms_and_apports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/bAbaisms_and_apports/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1468067668376883202&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1468067668376883202&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A recent post on the TL brought to mind a curious phenomenon that seems to be one of the factors that draw people into certain bābāisms: the production of apports. This caught my attention early on because I noticed that several votaries claimed to have received bābāistic apports. I have heard of three unrelated bābājī-s (one of them more of a low-profile vaiṣṇava &amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;magician&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo;) producing apports.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shortly thereafter I first saw one such apport, I saw demo by a vaṅgīya magician Sarkar on TV where he produced an apport explicitly as a magic trick. I pointed this to the votary and he gradually de-bābāized.+++(5)+++ I subsequently had the occasion to watch Sarkar live on stage producing various apports as part of his magic show. For at least one public bābājī the introduction of video cameras allowed the capture of the whole palming routine for sneaking in apports and then producing them quite like Sarkar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hindu literalism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/hindu-literalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/hindu-literalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good points. Agree with the proposal that most H are not equipped. Anecdotally speaking I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the same &amp;ndash; a certain H fragility &amp;ndash; a newly half-educate H who might &amp;rsquo;ve picked up a tome or 2 of Dick Dawkins &amp;amp; suddenly see himself as possessing a deep insight which obviates the the need for religion. Regurgitating Dick or someone like that he would bellow on to those who might listen or not how meaningless &amp;amp; useless religion is. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen similar transformations with H who encounter Marx &amp;amp; his cohorts, Ambedkar, the canon of nayonmAda or even a physics or a biology textbook. Then those newbies would lecture about how &amp;ldquo;irrational&amp;rdquo; religion is &amp;ndash; a polycephalous or therocephalous god is deemed an impossibility of a specimen for teratological+++(←abnormalities of physiological development)+++ investigation. The size of ghaTotkacha is given an analysis in terms of speed of neuronal conductance, etc. This indeed can lead to a denudation of religion &amp;amp; consequent exposure to self-wrought or enemy-engineered social devolution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>siddha vs paNDita</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/siddha_vs_paNDita/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/siddha_vs_paNDita/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;importance-of-vidvan-s&#34;&gt;Importance of vidvAn-s&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I have earlier clarified to @goghritaM there might be sAdhaka-s who primarily develop as yogin-s on the siddha track with acquisition of mantra-siddhi-s and those who primarily develop as vidvAn-s with little mantra-siddhi-s. As abhinavagupta laid out the latter is more important for the system as they preserve tradition. Hence, even though the first might look immensely charismatic to the lay devotee it is important that the system focus on development of the latter, and ensure that the siddha-s don&amp;rsquo;t stray out of the bounds of the system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>आगम-शिक्षणम्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/Agama-shixaNam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/MT/Agama-shixaNam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Those receiving mantrashAstra education should acquire special stava-s beyond those meant for lay devotees. These stava-s are essentially core to the personal practice of the deshika along with his yoga. These are very important for the development of the deshika as a mantra-vAdin. E.g. for saiddhAntika-Shaiva I would say the pa~nchAvarNa stava and vyapohanastava are a must. gUDha-dhyana on the deities unfolding in them is of highest importance to the practice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
