<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/vodUn/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/vodUn/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ancestral vs Divine origins</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/vodUn/articles/ancestral-vs-divine-origins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/vodUn/articles/ancestral-vs-divine-origins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;VODUN: ANCESTRAL ORIGINS VS OUR DIVINE ORIGINS&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Mami Wata Priest-  &lt;a href=&#34;https://m.facebook.com/mamiwatadan/posts/vodun-ancestral-origins-vs-our-divine-originswhen-i-peruse-the-faces-of-so-many-/1045331968831874/&#34;&gt;FB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I peruse the faces of so many Arabs, or Middle Easterners in general, I see my grandfather&amp;rsquo;s face, my father&amp;rsquo;s face and so many faces of my relatives. But I am reminded that my grandfather&amp;rsquo;s head spirit was the great Ganesh&amp;hellip; to which I inherited upon his death; my father&amp;rsquo;s, Lord Dattatreya (called Densu in Africa which means &amp;ldquo;father of the river&amp;rdquo;) from which I inherited my Dattatreya.+++(5)+++ And, as told by the spirits themselves, their particular dwelling place is that of the sacred Red Sea. As I can never feel worthy enough I am always in awe of the majesty of this great divine one. Yet, even as I first walked inside my ancestral village, in the Republic of Benin, I saw many of the same similarities amongst those of my oldest ancestors. And herein lies the dilemma for those Pan Africanist who perpetuate the myth that all the spirits, hailing from the continent of Africa, are black because the African American is black&amp;hellip;it is a farce!+++(5)+++&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Convent children</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/vodUn/articles/convent-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/vodUn/articles/convent-children/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vodun children in Togo must dedicate their lives to the convent&lt;br&gt;&#xA;May 21, 2018&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By Raluca Besliu&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A little girl looks into a vodun convent in Togo.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;A young vodun initiate stands in front of the Anfoin convent, surrounded by images of vodun deities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The walls of the vodun convent in Anfoin, a small village in the West African country of Togo, were painted with images of vodun and Hindu divinities. The 80-year-old mamissi, the convent’s head priestess, waited in a chamber covered in photos of her predecessors and depicting various vodun gods, whose cult she carries. Hers is one of many vodun convents spread across Togo, Ghana and Benin, where the West African traditional religion is amply practiced.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ghAna vodun spirituality</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/vodUn/articles/ghAna-vodun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/vodUn/articles/ghAna-vodun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Look At Today&amp;rsquo;s Voodoo Spirituality In Ghana&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rajaa Banda&lt;br&gt;&#xA;31 August 2017&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In a continent rife with ever-growing populations of Christians and Muslims, practicing traditional religions remains a quietly practiced but rarely discussed part of many Ghanaians’ lives. One such religion, Vodun, links Ghana to the wider African diaspora and still hold on to some of the same traditions and practices used generations ago.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ghana—and Africa as a whole—is heavily associated with Christianity in various forms. From the traditional movements such as Methodist or Episcopalian to the more popular evangelical mega churches led by pastors without affiliations to or roots in traditional theology or divinity. All of these are products of colonial expansion and it is sometimes difficult to find and know what is still present that connects Ghanaians to their roots. Voodoo spirituality, known in Ghana as Vodun, is one of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
