<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;2 The Mantra Purusha and Shakti Mantras on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/2_The_Mantra_Purusha_and_Shakti_Mantras/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;2 The Mantra Purusha and Shakti Mantras on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/2_The_Mantra_Purusha_and_Shakti_Mantras/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>06 Mantra and Sanskrit, the Language of the Gods</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/2_The_Mantra_Purusha_and_Shakti_Mantras/06_Mantra_and_Sanskrit_the_Language_of_the_Gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/2_The_Mantra_Purusha_and_Shakti_Mantras/06_Mantra_and_Sanskrit_the_Language_of_the_Gods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Sanskrit is called the ‘universal language’ or the ‘language of the Gods’, it is no mere exaggeration.1 Sanskrit reflects the primal sounds through which the entire universe is created, by which it is sustained, and into which it is eventually dissolved. These primal sounds of the universe are embodied in the Sanskrit letters.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sanskrit is not just another human language invented for purposes of social convenience, but a cosmic language. The letters of the Sanskrit alphabet allow the human mind to interface with the primal energies of cosmic intelligence and receive its deeper insights. Sanskrit, as it were, allows us to think with the Gods as one of the Gods ourselves! Through a right understanding of the Sanskrit alphabet, we can unite our individual Self with the universal Self, and regain our inner voice in the world of eternity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 The Vowels: the Prime Vibrations of Consciousness</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/2_The_Mantra_Purusha_and_Shakti_Mantras/07_The_Vowels_the_Prime_Vibrations_of_Consciousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/2_The_Mantra_Purusha_and_Shakti_Mantras/07_The_Vowels_the_Prime_Vibrations_of_Consciousness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is not enough to use the sounds of words as a tool; we must understand the nature of the tool that we are using. Only then can we shape our speech in a creative and insightful manner. In the following chapters, we will examine each letter of the Sanskrit alphabet from the standpoint of mantra, starting with the vowels, looking for the connections between the nature of the sound, how it is pronounced, and its deeper meaning and effect upon us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Semivowels and Sibilants: Powers of the Elements and the Pranas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/2_The_Mantra_Purusha_and_Shakti_Mantras/08_Semivowels_and_Sibilants_Powers_of_the_Elements_and_the_Pranas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/2_The_Mantra_Purusha_and_Shakti_Mantras/08_Semivowels_and_Sibilants_Powers_of_the_Elements_and_the_Pranas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The semivowels and sibilants are extremely important sounds in Yoga and Ayurveda. They connect to the primal forces of prana and the five elements, which in turn relate to the sensory qualities (tanmatras) sense organs, motor organs, and tissues of the body. In pranayama practices and in Kundalini Yoga, the sounds of the semi-vowels and sibilants are central. They help awaken our inner prana and dissolve the elements back into their seed powers allowing us to return to pure unity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 The Twenty Five Consonants</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/2_The_Mantra_Purusha_and_Shakti_Mantras/09_The_Twenty_Five_Consonants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/2_The_Mantra_Purusha_and_Shakti_Mantras/09_The_Twenty_Five_Consonants/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-powers-of-manifestation&#34;&gt;The Powers of Manifestation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Consonants are the main powers through which sound is diversified and a variety of words, statements and expressions of ideas becomes possible. The twenty five consonants have their particular energetics as described in Sanskrit texts. However, there is less agreement on their overall correspondences than there is with the vowels.1 Consonants, owing to their diversity, allow for a broad range of meaning, which is also modified according to the vowels and other consonants they are conjoined with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Shakti Bija Mantras</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/2_The_Mantra_Purusha_and_Shakti_Mantras/10_Shakti_Bija_Mantras/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/2_The_Mantra_Purusha_and_Shakti_Mantras/10_Shakti_Bija_Mantras/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Besides the mantric power of letters of the Sanskrit alphabet, there is another series of powerful bija or single-syllable mantras, which consist of several vowels or consonants. These come under the term ‘Shakti mantras’, as they are commonly used in the worship of Shakti, projecting various Shaktis or types of cosmic energies. &lt;em&gt;Oṁ&lt;/em&gt; is usually the foremost of these Shakti bija mantras. With it there are said to be eight total such primary bija mantras, with &lt;em&gt;Aiṁ&lt;/em&gt;,* Hrīṁ, Klīṁ, Krīṁ, Śrīṁ, Trīṁ, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Strīṁ*, as mentioned in the Mantra Yoga Samhita.1 They are several more such mantras that are commonly found in bija mantras, particularly to the Goddess. We have examined most of these below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Mantra Purusha: The Body of Sound</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/2_The_Mantra_Purusha_and_Shakti_Mantras/11_Mantra_Purusha_The_Body_of_Sound/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/2_The_Mantra_Purusha_and_Shakti_Mantras/11_Mantra_Purusha_The_Body_of_Sound/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Besides our gross, form-based physical body, we have another subtle energy body made up of sound. Our higher Self or inner being, the Purusha of yogic thought, is connected to the physical body through this body of sound. Mantra Yoga contains a very important teaching through which we can harmonize this body of sound to insure the right flow of energy into the physical body. Each of the fifty letters of the Sanskrit alphabet corresponds to a certain portion of the physical body called the Mantra Purusha, the Cosmic Being or Person (Purusha) made of mantra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 How to Use the Mantra Purusha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/2_The_Mantra_Purusha_and_Shakti_Mantras/12_How_to_Use_the_Mantra_Purusha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/2_The_Mantra_Purusha_and_Shakti_Mantras/12_How_to_Use_the_Mantra_Purusha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Mantra Purusha has many important applications relative to meditation, Yoga therapy, and Ayurvedic medicine. Like the human body overall, it can serve as a blueprint for the forces of the greater universe. This chapter will explore a number of the most important usages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;reciting-the-alphabet-through-the-mantra-purusha&#34;&gt;Reciting the Alphabet through the Mantra Purusha&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The simplest way to use the Mantra Purusha is to recite the entire Sanskrit alphabet starting with the letter-A at the top of the head, directing our prana and attention to each mantra location along the way. This serves as a complete mantric workout of the entire body and its pranic field. You can touch the respective bodily locations as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
