<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Kaufman on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/Neitzesche/Will_to_Power/1_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/Kaufman/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Kaufman on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/Neitzesche/Will_to_Power/1_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/Kaufman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>0</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/Neitzesche/Will_to_Power/1_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/Kaufman/0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/Neitzesche/Will_to_Power/1_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/Kaufman/0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;Preface&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Nov. 1887-March 1888)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of what is great one must either be silent or speak with greatness. With greatness&amp;ndash;that means cynically and with innocence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I relate is the history of the next two centuries. I describe what is coming, what can no longer come differently: the advent of nihilism. This history can be related even now; for necessity itself is at work here. This future speaks even now in a hundred signs, this destiny announces itself everywhere; for this music of the future all ears are cocked even now. For some time now, our whole European culture has been moving as toward a catastrophe, with a tortured tension that is growing from decade to decade: restlessly, violently, headlong, like a river that wants to reach the end, that no longer reflects, that is afraid to reflect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 NIHILISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/Neitzesche/Will_to_Power/1_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/Kaufman/1_NIHILISM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/Neitzesche/Will_to_Power/1_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/Kaufman/1_NIHILISM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2 (Spring-Fall 1887)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What does nihilism mean? That the highest values devaluate themselves. The aim is lacking; &amp;ldquo;why?&amp;rdquo; finds no answer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;3 (Spring-Fall 1887)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Radical nihilism is the conviction of an absolute untenability of existence when it comes to the highest values one recognizes; plus the realization that we lack the least right to posit a beyond or an in-itself of things that might be &amp;ldquo;divine&amp;rdquo; or morality incarnate.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This realization is a consequence of the cultivation of &amp;ldquo;truthfulness&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash;thus itself a consequence of the faith in morality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 HISTORY OF EUROPEAN NIHILISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/Neitzesche/Will_to_Power/1_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/Kaufman/2_HISTORY_OF_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/Neitzesche/Will_to_Power/1_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/Kaufman/2_HISTORY_OF_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;57 (1884)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My friends, it was hard for us when we were young: we suffered youth itself like a serious sickness. That is due to the time into which we have been thrown&amp;ndash;a time of extensive inner decay and disintegration, a time that with all its weaknesses, and even with its best strength, opposes the spirit of youth. Disintegration characterizes this time, and thus uncertainty: nothing stands firmly on its feet or on a hard faith in itself; one lives for tomorrow, as the day after tomorrow is dubious. Everything on our way is slippery and dangerous, and the ice that still supports us has become thin: all of us feel the warm, uncanny breath of the thawing wind; where we still walk, soon no one will be able to walk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
