<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Canonization-differences</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/canonization-differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/canonization-differences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/arya_amsha/status/1713176657803071719&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A thread on the historical progression of Hinduism and Hellenism. Quoting for higher visibility.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hindus and Greeks started of very similar. Both had shared origins, shared epics, similar religious pantheons, myths and systems of morality. Both were living in places surrounded by once great civilizations. Both had a similar environment, surrounded by other polytheistic cultures, it was an abundance of Gods and Goddesses, sacrifices, deified heroes, and remnants of a Bronze Age culture mingling with an urban one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Socrates prayer</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/socrates-prayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/socrates-prayer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Socrates: Is it not well to pray to the deities here before we go?&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Phaedrus: Of course.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Socrates: O beloved Pan and all ye other Gods of this place, grant to me that I be made beautiful in my soul within, and that all external possessions be in harmony with my inner man. May I consider the wise man rich; and may I have such wealth as only the self-restrained man can bear or endure. Do we need anything more, Phaedrus? For me that prayer is enough.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Phaedrus: Let me also share in this prayer; for friends have all things in common.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tertullian - child sacrifice</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/tertullian_child-sacrifice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/tertullian_child-sacrifice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tertullian on child sacrifice&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Autor(en):Rives, James B.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tertullian on Child Sacrifice&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By James B. Rives, Columbia University, New York&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That the Carthaginians offered their children in ritual sacrifice was noto-rious in antiquity and has in more recent times been amply confirmed by archaeological evidence1. Although much remains obscure about this practice, it was clearly an important part of the worship of the two chief Punic deities, Ba&amp;rsquo;al and Tanit. These deities continued to be widely worshipped in Roman times, under the Latin names of Saturnus and Caelestis, although child sacrifice seems to have disappeared as a central rite in their cult. This disappearance is not surprising, given the professed Roman hostility to human sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vapors of Delphi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/vapors_of_delphi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/vapors_of_delphi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: TW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apollo’s sanctuary at Delphi is the stuff of legends For over a thousand years, the famous oracle foretold the futures and fortunes of the city-states and heroes of ancient Greece. This thread explores whether she was stoned on geological vapors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Set in a mountainous landscape, with a view down to the gulf of Corinth, the site at Delphi is breathtakingly beautiful. Ancient myths describe it as the center of the world, the place where Zeus’s two eagles met, each released at the opposite end of the earth. I simply cannot get this point across enough. I’m not usually a romantic person when it comes to archaeology. It’s my job, after all. But, the feeling at this site is … it just is It gets in your bones and fills your spirit. The architects who designed the sanctuary certainly knew how to play up this feeling. You enter at the bottom and wind your way up. Each terrace has a more epic view to what lay below. Near the top, the theater has the best seats in the house.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voces</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/voces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/articles/voces/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: Grok&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;voces&amp;rdquo; in the context of the X post you shared refers to &amp;ldquo;voces magicae&amp;rdquo;, a concept from Classical Antiquity that is well-documented in historical and magical traditions of Ancient Greece, Egypt, and Rome. Let me break it down for you based on the post and the additional context provided.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What Are Voces Magicae?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Voces magicae (singular: vox magica, meaning &amp;ldquo;magical words&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;magical names&amp;rdquo;) are special, often pronounceable but incomprehensible, magical formulas used in spells, charms, curses, and amulets during Classical Antiquity (roughly spanning from the 8th century BCE to the 5th century CE). These words were believed to hold mystical power and were frequently inscribed on objects like gemstones, tablets, or papyri to invoke supernatural forces, deities, or spirits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
