<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;SHAKTI AND SHAKTA on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;SHAKTI AND SHAKTA on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 INDIAN RELIGION AS BHARATA DHARMA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/01_INDIAN_RELIGION_AS_BHARATA_DHARMA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/01_INDIAN_RELIGION_AS_BHARATA_DHARMA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER ONE. INDIAN RELIGION AS BHARATA DHARMA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A FRIEND of mine who read the first edition of this book suggested that I should add to it an opening Chapter, stating the most general and fundamental principles of the subject as a guide to the understanding of what follows, together with an outline of the latter in which the relation of the several parts should be shown. I have not at present the time, nor in the present book the space, to give effect to my friend’s wishes in the way I would have desired, but will not altogether neglect them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 SHAKTI: THE WORLD AS POWER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/02_SHAKTI_THE_WORLD_AS_POWER/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/02_SHAKTI_THE_WORLD_AS_POWER/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWO. SHAKTI: THE WORLD AS POWER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is no word of wider content in any language than this Sanskrit term meaning‘Power’. For Shakti in the highest causal sense is God as Mother, and in another sense it is the universe which issues from Her Womb. And what is there which is neither one nor the other? Therefore, theYoginihridaya Tantra thus salutes Her who conceives, bears, produces and thereafter nourishes all worlds:“Obeisance be to Her who is pure Being-Consciousness-Bliss, as Power, who exists in the form of Time and Space and all that is therein, and who is the radiant Illuminatrix in all beings.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 WHAT ARE THE TANTRAS AND THEIR SIGNIFICANCE?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/03_WHAT_ARE_THE_TANTRAS_AND_THEIR_SIGNIFICANCE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/03_WHAT_ARE_THE_TANTRAS_AND_THEIR_SIGNIFICANCE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER THREE. WHAT ARE THE TANTRAS AND THEIR SIGNIFICANCE?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A VERY common expression in English writings is“The Tantra”; but its use is often due to a misconception and leads to others. For what does Tantra mean? The word denotes injunction (Vidhi), regulation (Niyama), Shastra generally or treatise.Thus,Shamkara calls the Samkhya a Tantra. A secular writing may be called Tantra. For the followingnote,I am indebted to Professor SurendranathdasGupta.“The word‘Tantra’has been derived in the Kashika-Vritti (7-2-9) from the root‘Tan’‘to spread’by the Aunadika rule Sarvadhatubhyah tran, with the addition of the suffix‘tran’. Vacaspati, Anandagiri, and Govindananda, however, derive the word from the root‘Tatri’of‘Tantri’in the sense of Vyutpadana, origination or knowledge. In Ganapatha, however,‘Tantri’has the same meaning as‘Tan’‘to spread’and it is probable that the former root is a modification of the latter. The meaning Vyutpadana is also probably derived by narrowing the general sense of Vistara which is the meaning of the root‘Tan’.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 TANTRA SHASTRA AND VEDA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/04_TANTRA_SHASTRA_AND_VEDA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/04_TANTRA_SHASTRA_AND_VEDA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER FOUR. TANTRA SHASTRA AND VEDA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In writing this Chapter I have in mind the dispute which some have raised upon the question whether the Agamas, or some of them, are Vaidik or non-Vaidik.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do not here deal with the nature and schools of Tantra or Agama nor with their historical origin. Something has been said on these points in the Introductions to the English translations of Pandit Shiva Chandra Vidyarnava’s Tantra-tattva. I have also dealt with this subject in the two Chapters,“What are the Tantras and their significance?”and“Shakti and Shakta”. I wish to avoid repetitions, except so far as is absolutely necessary for the elucidation of the particular subject in hand. On the disputed question whether the Agamas are Vaidik or non-Vaidik I desire to point out that an answer cannot be given unless we keep apart two distinct matters, viz., (1) what was the origin of the Agamas and (2) what they are now. I am not here, however, dealing with the first or historical question, but with the second so far as the Shakta Agama is concerned. Let us assume, for the sake of argument, that (to take a specific example) worship of Kali and other Devis by the Shaktas indicates the existence of non-Aryan elements in their Agama. The question of real importance here, as always, is not as to what were the facts in remote past ages, but what they are now. The answer then is - let it be as you willbe regardingthe origin of the Shakta Agama; but at present Shakta worship is an integral part of the Hinduism and as such admits the authority of Veda, accepting, as later explained, every other belief held by the general body of the Hindu people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 THE TANTRAS AND RELIGION OF THE SHAKTAS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/05_THE_TANTRAS_AND_RELIGION_OF_THE_SHAKTAS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/05_THE_TANTRAS_AND_RELIGION_OF_THE_SHAKTAS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER FIVE. THE TANTRAS AND RELIGION OF THE SHAKTAS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(What follows this bracket is a translation, done in literal fashion, from the German, of an article by the learned Sanskritist, Professor Winternitz, entitled“Die Tantras und die Religion der Saktas”published in the Berlin monthly, the Ostasiatische Zeitschrift, 1916, Heft. 3. The article does not show a complete comprehension of its subject-matter, nor was this to be expected. In European fashion Sadhaka is translated“Magician”and Sadhana is thought of as“magical evocation”and Mahayogini as“Great Magician”. This is the more unfortunate, as the Professor evidently does not like“magic”. It is true that in Indrajalavidya there is Sadhana to achieve its purposes, but what is of course meant is Sadhana in its religious sense. We hear again of“idolatry”though idolatry is not (in the sense in which those who make the charge use the word) to be found in any part of the world. Mantra is still“gibberish,”“trash”and so on. After all, many of these matters are as much a question of temperament as argument. The mind which takes these views is like that of the Protestant who called the Catholic Mass“Hocus Pocus”. It is superstitious trash to him but a holy reality to the believer. Such criticism involves the fallacy of judging others from one’s own subjective standpoint. Moreover, not one man in thousands is capable of grasping the inner significance of this doctrine and for this reason it is kept secret nor does any writing reveal it to those without understanding. The learned Professor has also evidently no liking for “Occultism” and “India-faddists”(Indiensschwarmern). But the former exists whether we like its facts or not. Nevertheless, in reading this article one feels oneself in the presence of a learned mind which wills to be fair and is not to be stampeded from investigation on hearing the frightful word“Tantra”. Several appreciations are just. Particularly noteworthy is the recognition that the Tantra Shastras or Agamas are not merely some pathological excrescence on“Hinduism”but simply one of its several presentations. Nor are they simply Scriptures of the Shaktas. Their metaphysics and ethics are those of the common Brahmanism of which all the sects are offshoots, whatever be the special peculiarities in presentment of doctrine or in its application. Before this Professor Albert Grunwedel had said (in hisDer Weg Nach Sambhala, Munchen 1915):“The Tantras are nothing but the continuation of the Veda”(Die Tantras, sind eben die fortsetzung des Veda). He calls also the Tantras the“model-room”(Akt-saal) of Indian Art (the Akt-saal is a room in an Academy of Art in which casts are kept as models for the students).“These Scriptures,”he adds,“furnish the aesthetics and in fact we find that in the later books (of the Kalacakra) the whole figurative mythology (of that system) has been built upon this scheme. Whence this evolution of forms arises is indeed another question which will bring many a surprise to the friends of‘National Indian Art’(sic!). Talking is easier. The Jains too have such things.”I may add that the fact that some Jains carry out someso-called“Tantrik rites”is not generally known. Vaishnavas and Bauddhas also have these rites. Notions and practices generally charged to Shaktas only are held and carried out by other sects. It is to be remembered also that there are many schools of Agama. Some of them state that other Agamas were promulgated“for the delusion of men”. It is needless to add that, here as elsewhere, to the adherent of a particular Agama his particular scripture is good, and it is the scripture of his opponent which is“for delusion”. Orthodoxy is“my doxy”in India also amongst some sects. Shakta liberalism (being Advaita Vedanta) finds a place for all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 SHAKTI AND SHAKTA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/06_SHAKTI_AND_SHAKTA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/06_SHAKTI_AND_SHAKTA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER SIX. SHAKTI AND SHAKTA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Shakti who is in Herself pure blissful Consciousness (Cidrupini) is also the Mother of Nature and is Nature itself born of the creative play of Her thought. The Shakta faith, or worship of Shakti, is I believe, in some of its essential features one of the oldest and most wide-spread religions in the world. Though very ancient, it is yet, in its essentials, and in the developed form in which we know it to-day, harmonious with some of the teachings of modern philosophy and science; not that this is necessarily a test of its truth. It may be here noted that in the West, and in particular in America and England, a large number of books are now being published on“New Thought,”“Will Power,”“Vitalism,”“Creative Thought,”“Right Thought,”“Self-Unfoldment,”“Secret of Achievement,”“Mental Therapeutics”and the like, the principles of which are essentially those of some forms of Shakti Sadhana both higher and lower. There are books of disguised magic as how to control (Vashikarana) by making them buy what they do not want, how to secure“affection”and so forth which, not-withstanding some hypocrisies, are in certain respects on the same level as the Tantrik Shavara as a low class of books on magic are called. Shavara or Candala are amongst the lowest of men. The ancient and at the same time distinguishing character of the faith is instanced by temple worship (the old Vaidik worship was generally in the home or in the open by the river), the cult of images, of Linga and Yoni (neither of which, it is said, were part of the original Vaidik Practice), the worship of Devis and of the Magna Mater (the great Vaidik Devata was the male Indra) and other matters of both doctrine and practice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 IS SHAKTI FORCE?</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/07_IS_SHAKTI_FORCE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/07_IS_SHAKTI_FORCE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER SEVEN. IS SHAKTI FORCE?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are some persons who have thought, and still think, that Shakti means force and that the worship of Shakti is the worship of force.Thus,Keshub Chunder Sen (New Dispensation, p. 108), wrote:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Four centuries ago the Shaktas gave way before the Bhaktas. Chaitanya’s army proved invincible, and carried all Bengal captive. Even to-day his gospel of love rules as a living force, though his followers have considerably declined both in faith and in morals. Just the reverse of this we find in England and other European countries. There the Shaktas are driving the Bhaktas out of the field. Look at the Huxleys, the Tyndalls and the Spencers of the day. What are they but Shaktas, worshippers of Shakti or Force?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 CINACARA \(VASHISHTHA AND BUDDHA\)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/08_CINACARA_VASHISHTHA_AND_BUDDHA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/08_CINACARA_VASHISHTHA_AND_BUDDHA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER EIGHT. CINACARA (VASHISHTHA AND BUDDHA)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It has been the subject of debate whether the Tantrik Pañcatattva ritual with wine and so forth is a product of Buddhism, and whether it is opposed to Vaidika Dharma. Some have supposed that these rites originally came from yellow Asia, penetrated into India where they received its impress, and again made their way to the north to encounter earlier original forms. I have elsewhere put forward some facts which suggest that these rites may be a continuance, though in another form, of ancient Vaidik usage in which Soma, Meat, Fish and Purodasa formed a part. Though there are some Maithuna rites in the Vedas it is possible that the Bengal Shakta ritual in this respect has its origin in Cinacara. Possibly the whole ritual comes therefrom. I have spoken of Bengal because we should distinguish it from other forms of Shakta worship. The matter is so obscure at present that any definite affirmation as to historical origins lacks justification. Most important however in the alleged Buddhist connection is the story of Vashishtha to be found in the Tantras. He is said to have gone to Mahacina (Tibet), which, according to popular belief, is half way to Heaven. Mahadeva is said to be visible at the bottom of the Manasarova Lake near Kailasa. Some of the Texts bearing on it have been collected in the Appendix to the edition of the Tara Tantra which has been published by the Varendra Anusandhana Samiti. The Tara Tantra opens (l. 2) with the following question of Devi Tara or Mahanila-Sarasvati:“Thou didst speak of the two Kula-bhairavas, Buddha and Vashishtha. Tell me by what Mantra they became Siddha’. The same Tantra (IV. 10) defines a Bhairava as follows:“He who purifies these five (i.e., Pañcatattva) and after offering the same (to the Devata) partakes thereof is a Bhairava.”Buddha then is said to be a Kula-bhairava. It is to be noted that Buddhist Tantriks who practice this ritual are accounted Kaulas. Shiva replied,“Janardana (Vishnu) is the excellent Deva in the form of Buddha (Buddharupi).”It is said in theSamayacara Tantra that Tara and Kalika, in their different forms, as also Matangi, Bhairavi, Chhinnamasta, and Dhumavati belong to the northern Amnaya. The sixth Chapter of the Sammohana Tantra mentions a number of Scriptures of the Bauddha class, together with others of the Shakta, Shaiva, Vaishnava, Saura and Ganapatya classes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 THE TANTRA SHASTRAS IN CHINA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/09_THE_TANTRA_SHASTRAS_IN_CHINA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/09_THE_TANTRA_SHASTRAS_IN_CHINA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER NINE. THE TANTRA SHASTRAS IN CHINA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Adopting for the purpose of this essay, and without discussion as to their accuracy, the general views of Orientalists on chronology and the development of the Buddhistic schools, the history of the Buddhistic Tantra is shortly as follows. The Mahayana (which commenced no one knows exactly when) was represented in the first and second centuries by the great names of Ashvaghosha and Nagarjuna. Its great scripture is the Prajñaparamita. Its dominance under the protection of Kanishka marks the first steps towards metaphysical, theistic, and ritualistic religion, a recurring tendency amongst men to which I have previously referred. In the second half of the first century A.D., Buddhism, apparently in its Mahayana form, spread to China, and thence to Korea, then to Japan in sixth century A.D. and to Tibet in the seventh. Some time between the 4th and 5th centuries AD Asanga, a Buddhist monk of Gandhara, is said to have promulgated the Buddhist Yogacara which, as its name imports, was an adaptation of the Indian Patañjali’s Yoga Darshana. Dr. Waddell says that“this Yoga parasite (most Europeans dislike what they understand of Yoga) containing within itself the germs of Tantrism”soon developed“monster out-growths”which“cankered”“the little life of purely Buddhistic stock”in the Mahayana, which is itself characterized as merely“sophistic nihilism”. Whatever that may mean, it certainly has the air of reducing the Mahayana to nothingness. We are then told that at the end of the sixth century“Tantrism or Sivaic mysticism (a vague word) with its worship of female energies (Shakti) and Fiendesses began to tinge both Hinduism and Buddhism, the latter of which“became still more debased with silly contemptible mummery of unmeaning jargon, gibberish, charmed sentences (Dharani) and magic circles (Mandala)”in the form of the“Vehicle”called Mantrayana alleged to have been founded by Nagarjuna who received it from the Dhyani Buddha Vairocana through the Bodhisattva Vajrasattva at the“Iron tower”in Southern India. Continuing he says“that on the evolution in the tenth century of the demoniacal Buddhas of the Kalacakra (system) the Mantrayana developed into the Vajrayana“the most depraved form of Buddhist doctrine”wherein the“Devotee”endeavors with the aid of the“Demoniacal Buddhas”and of“Fiendesses”(Dakini)“to obtain various Siddhis”. The missionary author, the Rev. Graham Sandberg, who is so little favorable to Buddhism that he can discover (p. 260) in it“no scheme of metaphysics or morality which can be dignified with the title of an ethical system,”when however speaking of this“most depraved form”in a short Chapter on the Tantras and Tantrik rites“Tibet and the Tibetans,”218) says that this new vehicle (Ngag-kyi Thegpa) did not profess to supersede the time-honored Vajrayana (Dorje-Thegpa) but it claimed“by its expanded mythological scheme and its fascinating and even sublime mystic conceptions to crystallize the old Tantrik methods into a regular science as complicated as it was resourceful.”We are all naturally pleasedat finding resemblances in other doctrines to teachings of our own, and so the reverend author, after pointing out that a leading feature of the Kalacakra (Dus-Kyi-khorlo) was the evolution of the idea of a Supreme Personal Being, says that“many fine and distinctively theistic characteristics of the Deity, His disposition, purity, fatherliness, benevolence and isolated power are set out in the Kalacakra treatises.”But he is, as we might expect, of the opinion that this was only an effort towards the real thing, probably influenced by the fact of Christian and Mohamedan teaching. We commonly find that a Semitic source is alleged for what cannot be denied to be good in Hinduism, or its child Buddhism. One wonders however how the“demoniacal Buddhas”and“Fiendesses”work themselves into this be-praised effort to teach Christian ideas. At the risk of straying from my subject, I may point out that in Buddhism the Devatas are given both peaceful (Zhi) and wrathful (Khro) aspects. The latter denotes the terrible (what in India is called Bhairava) aspects of the Divinity, but does not change Him or her into a Demon, at least in Buddhist or Indian belief. Even to the Christian, God has both a terrible and a benign aspect. It is true that some of the representations of the former aspect in Northern Buddhism are, to most Westerns, demoniac in form, but that is the way the Tibetan mind works in endeavoring to picture the matter for itself, as the Hindus do with their Devis, Kali, Chinnamasta and Candi. Another and artistically conceived idea of Bhairava is pictured in a beautiful Indian Kangra painting in my possession in which a smoldering restrained wrath, as it were a lowering dark storm-cloud, envelopes the otherwise restrained face and immobile posture of the Devata. As regards the esoteric worship of Dakinis I have said a word in the Foreword to the seventh volume of my Tantrik Texts. Without having recourse to abuse, we can better state the general conclusion by saying that the Tantrik cult introduced a theistical form of organized worship with prayers, litanies, hymns, music, flowers, incense, recitation of Mantra(Japa), Kavacas or protectors in the form of Dharanis, offerings, help of the dead: in short, with all practical aids to religion for the individual together with a rich and pompous public ritual for the whole body of the faithful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 A TIBETAN TANTRA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/10_A_TIBETAN_TANTRA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/10_A_TIBETAN_TANTRA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TEN. A TIBETAN TANTRA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[This Chapter is an admirably understanding review (reprinted from The Theosophist of July 1919) by Mr. Johan Van Manen, the Tibetan scholar. It was written on the seventh volume of Tantrik Texts which contains the first Tibetan Tantra to be published. The Tantra which was selected for the series was the Shricakra-Sambhara, because the Editor happened to have manuscripts of this and other works of the same school.]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 SHAKTI IN TAOISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/11_SHAKTI_IN_TAOISM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/11_SHAKTI_IN_TAOISM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER ELEVEN. SHAKTI IN TAOISM&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The belief in Shakti or the Divine Power as distinguished from the Divine Essence (Svarupa), the former being generally imagined for purposes of worship as being in female form, is very ancient. The concept of Shakti in Chinese Taoism is not merely a proof of this (for the Shakti notion is much older) but is an indication of the ancient Indian character of the doctrine. There are some who erroneously think, the concept had its origin in“Sivaic mysticism,”having its origin somewhere in the sixth century of our era. Lao-tze or the“old master”was twentyyears’senior to Confucius and his life was said to have been passed between 570-490 B.C. A date commonly accepted by European Orientalists as that of the death of Buddha (Indian and Tibetan opinions being regarded, as“extravagant”) would bring his life into the sixth century s.c., one of the most wonderful in the world’s history. Lao-tze is said to have written the Tao-tei-king, the fundamental text of Taoism. This title means Treatise on Tao and Tei. Tao which Lao-tze calls“The great”is in its Sanskrit equivalent Brahman and Tei is Its power or activity or Shakti. As Father P. L. Wieger, S. J., to whose work (Histoire des Croyances Religieuses et des Opinions Philosophiques en Chine, p. 143 et seg. 1917) I am here indebted, points out, Lao-tze did not invent Taoism no more than Confucius (557-419 B.C.) invented Confucianism. It is characteristic of these and other Ancient Eastern Masters that they do not claim to be more than“transmitters”of a wisdom older than themselves. Lao-tze was not the first to teach Taoism. He had precursors who, however, were not authors. He was the writer of the first book on Taoism which served as the basis for the further development of the doctrine. On this account its paternity is attributed to him. There was reference to this doctrine it is said in the official archives (p. 743). The pre-Taoists were the analysts and astrologers of the Tcheou. Lao-tze who formulated the system was one of them (ib. 69). The third Ministry containing these archives registered all which came from foreign parts, as Taoism did. For as Father Wieger says, Taoism is in its main lines a Chinese adaptation of the contemporary doctrine of the Upanishads (“or le Taoisme est dans ses grandes lignes une adaptation Chinoise de la doctrine Indienne contemporaine des Upanisads”). The actual fact of importation cannot in default of documents be proved but as the learned author says, the fact that the doctrine was not Chinese, that it was then current in India, and its sudden spread in China, creates in favor of the argument for foreign importation almost a certain conclusion. The similarity of the two doctrines is obvious to any one acquainted with that of the Upanishads and the doctrine of Shakti. The dualism of the manifesting Unity (Tao) denoted by Yin-Yang appears for the first time in a text of Confucius, a contemporary of Lao-tze, who may have informed him of it. All Chinese Monism descends from Lao-tze. The patriarchal texts were developed by the great Fathers of Taoism Lie-tzeu and Tchong-tzeu (see“Les Péres du systéme Taoiste”by the sameauthor) whom the reverend father calls the only real thinkers that China has produced. Both were practically prior to the contact of Greece and India on the Indus under Alexander. The first development of Taoism was in the South. It passed later to the North where it had a great influence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 ALLEGED CONFLICT OF SHASTRAS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/12_ALLEGED_CONFLICT_OF_SHASTRAS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/12_ALLEGED_CONFLICT_OF_SHASTRAS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWELVE. ALLEGED CONFLICT OF SHASTRAS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A NOT uncommon modern criticism upon the Indian Shastras is that they mutually conflict. This is due to a lack of knowledge of the doctrine of Adhikara and Bhumika, particularly amongst Western critics, whose general outlook and mode of thought is ordinarily deeply divergent from that which has prevailed in India. The idea that the whole world should follow one path is regarded by the Hindus as absurd, being contrary to Nature and its laws. A man must follow that path for which he is fit, that is, for which he is Adhikari. Adhikara or competency literally means“spreading over”that is“taking possession of”. What is to be known (Jñatavya), done (Kartavya), acquired (Praptavya) is determined not once and generally for all, but in each case by the fitness and capacity therefor of the individual. Each man can know, do, and obtain not everything, nor indeed one common thing, but that only of which he is capable (Adhikari). What the Jiva can think, do, or obtain, is his competency or Adhikara, a profound and practical doctrine on which all Indian teaching and Sadhana is based. As men are different and therefore the Adhikara is different, so there are different forms of teaching and practice for each Adhikara. Such teaching may be Srauta or Ashrauta. Dealing here with the first, it is said of all Vidyas the Lord is Ishana, and that these differing forms are meant for differing competencies, though all have one and the same object and aim. This has been well and concisely worked out by Bhaskararaya, the Commentator on Tantrik and Aupanishadic Texts in his Bhashya upon the Nityashodashikarnava, which is, according to him, a portion of the great Vamakeshvara Tantra. The second portion of the Nityasohdashkarnava is also known as the Yoginihridaya. These valuable Tantrik Texts have been published as the 56th Volume of the Poona Anandashrama Series which includes also (Vol. 69) the Jñanarnava Tantra. The importance of the Vamakeshvara is shown by the fact that Bhaskararaya claims for it the position of the independent 65th Tantra which is mentioned in the 31st verse of the Anandalahari. Others say that the Svatantra there spoken of, is the Jñanarnava Tantra, and others again are of the opinion that the Tantraraja is the great independent Tantra of which the Anandalahari (ascribed to Shrimadacaryabhagavatpada, that is, Shamkaracarya) speaks. Bhaskararaya who lived in the first half of the eighteenth century gives in his Commentary the following exposition:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 SARVANANDANATHA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/13_SARVANANDANATHA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/13_SARVANANDANATHA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER THIRTEEN. SARVANANDANATHA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Sarvollasa, a copy of which came into my possession some three years ago, is a rare MS. It is a Samgraha by the Sarvavidyasiddha Sarvanandanatha who, though celebrated amongst the Bengal followers of the Agama, is I should think, almost unknown to the general public. There is a life in Sanskrit of Sarvanandanatha entitled Sarvanandataramgini by his son Shivanatha in which an account of the attainment of his Siddhi is given and I am indebted in respect of this article to a short unpublished memoir by Sj. Dinesha Candra Bhattacaryya, formerly Research Scholar, who as a native of Tipperah has had the desire to see Sarvanandanatha’s place in the History of the so-called“Tantricism”in Bengal duly recognized.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 CIT-SHAKTI \(THE CONSCIOUSNESS ASPECT OF THE UNIVERSE\)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/14_CIT-SHAKTI_THE_CONSCIOUSNESS_ASPECT_OF_THE_UNIVERSE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/14_CIT-SHAKTI_THE_CONSCIOUSNESS_ASPECT_OF_THE_UNIVERSE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER FOURTEEN. CIT-SHAKTI (THE CONSCIOUSNESS ASPECT OF THE UNIVERSE)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cit-Shakti is Cit, as Shakti, that is as Power, or that aspect of Cit in which it is, through its associated Maya-Shakti, operative to create the universe. It is a commonly accepted doctrine that the ultimate Reality is Samvid, Caitanya or Cit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But what is Cit? There is no word in the English language which adequately describes it. It is not mind: for mind is a limited instrument through which Cit is manifested. It is that which is behind the mind and by which the mind itself is thought, that is created. The Brahman is mindless (Amanah). I f we exclude mind we also exclude all forms of mental process, conception, perception, thought, reason, will, memory, particular sensation and the like. We are then left with three available words, namely, Consciousness, Feeling, Experience. To the first term there are several objections. For if we use an English word, we must understand it according to its generally received meaning.Generally,by“Consciousness”is meant self-consciousness, or at least something particular, having direction and form, which is concrete and conditioned; an evolved product marking the higher stages of Evolution. According to some, it is a mere function of experience, an epiphenomenon, a mere accident of mental process. In thissense,it belongs only to thehighly-developedorganism and involves a subject attending to an object of’which, as of itself, it is conscious. We are thus said to have most consciousness when we are awake (Jagrat avastha) and have full experience of all objects presented to us; less so when dreaming (Svapna avastha) and deep anesthesia in true dreamless sleep (Sushupti). I may here observe that recent researches show that this last state is not so common as is generally supposed. That is complete dreamlessness is rare; there being generally some trace of dream. In the laststate,it is commonly said that consciousness has disappeared, and so of course it has, if we first define consciousness in terms of the waking state and of knowledge of objects. According to Indian notions there is a form of conscious experience in the deepest sleep expressed in the well-known phrase“Happily I slept, I knew nothing”. The sleeper recollects on waking that his state has been one of happiness. And he cannot recollect unless there has been a previous experience (Anubhava) which is the subject-matter of memory. In ordinaryparlance,we do not regard some low animal forms, plants or mineral as“conscious”. It is true that now in the West there is (due to the spread of ideas long current in India) growing up a wider use of the term“consciousness”in connection not only with animal but vegetable and mineral life, but it cannot be said the term“consciousness”has yet generally acquired this wide signification. If then we use (as for convenience we do) the term“Consciousness”for Cit, we must give it a content different from that which is attributed to the term in ordinary English parlance.Nextly, it is to be remembered that what in either view we understand by consciousness is something manifested, and therefore limited, and derived from our finite experience. The Brahman as Cit is the infinite substratum of that. Cit in itself (Svarupa) is not particular nor conditioned and concrete. Particularity is that aspect in which it manifests as, and through, Maya-Shakti. Cit manifests as Jñana-Shakti which, when used otherwise than as a loose synonym for Cit, means knowledge of objects. Cit-Svarupa is neither knowledge of objects nor self-consciousness in the phenomenal sense. Waking, dreaming and dreamless slumber are all phenomenal states in which experience varies; such variance being due not to Cit but to the operation or cessation of particular operation of the vehicles of mind (Antahkarana) and sense (Indriya). But Cit never disappears nor varies in either of the three states, but remains one and the same through all. Though Cit-Svarupa is not a knowledge of objects in the phenomenal sense, it is not, according to Shaiva-Shakta views (I refer always to Advaita Shaiva-darshana), a mere abstract knowing (Jñana) wholly devoid of content. It contains within itself the Vimarsha-Shakti which is the cause of phenomenal objects, then existing in the form of Cit (Cidrupini). The Self then knows the Self. Still less can we speak of mere‘awareness”as the equivalent of Cit. A worm or meaner form of animal may be said to be vaguely aware. In fact,mere“awareness”(as we understand that term) is a state of Cit in which it is seemingly overwhelmed by obscuring Maya-Shakti in the form of Tamoguna. Unless therefore we give to“awareness,”as also to consciousness, a content, other than that with which our experience furnishes us, both terms are unsuitable. In some respects,Cit can be more closely described by Feeling, which seems to have been the most ancient meaning of the term Cit. Feeling is more primary, in that it is only after we have been first affected by something that we become conscious of it. Feeling has thus been said to be the raw material of thought, the essential element in the Self, what we call personality being a particular form of feeling. Thus,in Samkhya, the Gunas are said to be in the nature of happiness (Sukha), sorrow (Dukha) and illusion (Moha) as they are experienced by the Purusha-Consciousness. And in Vedanta, Cit and Ananda or Bliss or Love are one. For Consciousness,then is not consciousness of being (Sat) but Being-Consciousness (Sat-Cit); nor a Being which is conscious of Bliss (Ananda) but Being-Consciousness-Bliss (Sacchidananda). Further,“feeling”has this advantage that it is associated with all forms of organic existence even according to popular usage, and may scientifically be aptly applied to inorganic matter. Thus whilst most consider it to be an unusual and strained use of language, to speak of the consciousness of a plant or stone, we can and do speak of the feeling or sentiency of a plant. Further the response which inorganic matter makes to stimuli is evidence of the existence therein of that vital germ of life and sentiency (and therefore Cit) which expands into the sentiency of plants, and the feelings and emotions of animals and men. It is possible for any form of unintelligent being to feel, however obscurely. And it must do so, if its ultimate basis is Cit and Ananda, however veiled by Maya-Shakti these may be. The response which inorganic matter makes to stimuli is the manifestation of Citthrough the Sattvaguna of Maya-Shakti, or Shakti in its form as Prakriti-Shakti. The manifestation is slight and apparently mechanical because of the extreme predominance of the Tamoguna in the same Prakriti-Shakti. Because of the limited and extremely regulated character of the movement which seems to exclude all volitional process as known to us, it is currently assumed that we have merely to deal with what is an unconscious mechanical energy. Because vitality is so circumscribed and seemingly identified with the apparent mechanical process, we are apt to assume mere unconscious mechanism. But as a fact this latter is but the form assumed by the conscious Vital Power which is in and works in all matter whatever it be. To the eye, however, unassisted by scientific instruments, which extend our capacity for experience, establishing artificial organs for the gaining thereof, the matter appears Jada (or unconscious); and both in common English and Indian parlance we call that alone living or Jiva which, as organized matter, is endowed with body and senses. Philosophically, however, as well as scientifically, all is Jivatma which is not Paramatma: everything in fact with form, whether the form exists as the simple molecule of matter, or as the combination of these simple forms into cells and greater organisms. The response of metallic matter is a form of sentiency &amp;ndash; its germinal form &amp;ndash; a manifestation of Cit intensely obscured by the Tamoguna of Prakriti-Shakti.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 MAYA-SHAKTI \(THE PSYCHO-PHYSICAL ASPECT OF THE UNIVERSE\)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/15_MAYA-SHAKTI_THE_PSYCHO-PHYSICAL_ASPECT_OF_THE_UNIVERSE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/15_MAYA-SHAKTI_THE_PSYCHO-PHYSICAL_ASPECT_OF_THE_UNIVERSE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER FIFTEEN. MAYA-SHAKTI (THE PSYCHO-PHYSICAL ASPECT OF THE UNIVERSE)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Spirit, Mind and Matter are ultimately one, the two latter being the twin aspects of the Fundamental Substance or Brahman and Its Power or Shakti. Spirit is the substance of mind-matter, the Reality (in the sense of the lasting changelessness) out of which, by Its Power, all Appearance is fashioned not by the individual mind and senses but by the cosmic mind and senses of which they are but a part. What It creates It perceives. In the last chapter I dealt with the Spirit or Consciousness (Cit) aspect: in this I consider the mind-matter aspect in which Consciousness veils itself in apparent unconsciousness. These twin principles are called Purusha, Brahman, Shiva on the one hand and Prakriti, Maya, and Maya-Shakti on the other by the Samkhya Mayavada Vedanta and Shaktivada of the Shakta Agama respectively. The latter Shastra, however, alone treats them as aspects of the one Substance in the manner here described and thus most aptly in this respect accommodates itself to the doctrine of Western scientific monism. So, Professor Haeckel points out in conformity with Shakta Advaitavada that Spirit and Matter are not two distinct entities but two forms or aspects of one single Entity or fundamental Substance. According to him, the One Entity with dual aspect is the sole Reality which presents itself to view as the infinitely varied and wondrous picture of the universe. Whatever be the case transcendentally in what the Buddhist Tantra aptly calls“The Void”(Shunyata. In Tibetan sTongpa-nyid) which is not“nothing”as some have supposed, but That which is like nothing known to us; the ultimate formless (Arupa) Reality as contrasted with appearance (sNang-va-dang) or form (Rupa) of which the Prajñaparamita-hridaya-garbha says only“neti neti”can be affirmed, in this universe immaterial Spirit is just as unthinkable as spiritless matter. The two are inseparately combined in every atom which, itself and its forces, possess the elements of vitality, growth and intelligence in all their developments. In the four Atmas which are contemplated in the Citkunda in the Muladhara Cakra, Atma pranarupi represents the vital aspect, Jñanatma the Intelligence aspect, and Antaratma is that spark of the Paramatma which inheres in all bodies, and which when spread (Vyapta) appears as the Bhuta or five forms of sensible matter which go to the making of the gross body. These are all aspects of the one Paramatma (Jñanarnava Tantra, Ch. XXI, Vv. 1-9).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 MATTER AND CONSCIOUSNESS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/16_MATTER_AND_CONSCIOUSNESS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/16_MATTER_AND_CONSCIOUSNESS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER SIXTEEN. MATTER AND CONSCIOUSNESS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The subject of my lecture today is Consciousness or Cit, and Matter or Unconsciousness, that is, Acit; the unchanging formlessness and the changing forms. According to Shakta Advaitavada, man is Consciousness-Unconsciousness or Cit-Acit; being Cit-Shakti as regards his Antaratma, and the particularized Maya-Shakti as to his material vehicles of mind and body. The reason that I have selected this subject, amongst the many others on which I might have addressed you, is that these two ideas are the key concepts of Indian Philosophy and religion. If they are fully understood both as to their definition and relations, then, all is understood so far as intellect can make such matters intelligible to us; if they are not understood then nothing is properly understood. Nor are they always understood even by those who profess to know and write on Indian Philosophy. Thus, the work on Vedanta, of an English Orientalist, now in its second edition, describes Cit as the condition of a stone or other inert substance. A more absurd error it is hard to imagine. Those who talk in this way have not learnt the elements of their subject. It is true that you will find in the Shastra, the state of the Yogi described as being like a log (Kashthavat). But this does not mean that his Consciousness is that of a piece of wood; but that he no more perceives the external world than a log of wood does. He does not do so because he has the Samadhi consciousness that is Illumination and true Being itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 SHAKTI AND MAYA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/17_SHAKTI_AND_MAYA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/17_SHAKTI_AND_MAYA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER SEVENTEEN. SHAKTI AND MAYA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the Eighth Chapter of the unpublished Sammohana Tantra, it is said that Shamkara manifested on earth in the form of Shamkaracarya, in order to root out Buddhism from India. It compares his disciples and himself to the five Mahapreta (who form the couch on which the Mother of the Worlds rests), and identifies his maths with the Amnayas, namely, the Govardhana in Puri with Purvamnaya (the Sampradaya being Bhogavara), and so on with the rest. Whatever be the claims of Shamkara as destroyer of the great Buddhistic heresy, which owing to its subtlety was the most dangerous antagonist which the Vedanta has ever had, or his claims as expounder of Upanishad from the standpoint of Siddhi, his Mayavada finds no place in the Tantras of the Agamas, for the doctrine and practice is given from the standpoint of Sadhana. This is not to say that the doctrine is explicitly denied. It is not considered. It is true that in actual fact we often give accommodation to differing theories for which logic can find no living room, but it is obvious that in so far as man is a worshipper he must accept the world-standpoint, if he would not, like Kalidasa, cut from beneath himself the branch of the tree on which he sits. Next, it would be a mistake to overlook the possibility of the so-called“Tantrik”tradition having been fed by ways of thought and practice which were not, in the strict sense of the term, part of the Vaidic cult, or in the line of its descent. The worship of the Great Mother, the Magna Mater of the Near East, the Adya Shakti of the Shakta Tantras, is in its essentials (as I have elsewhere pointed out) one of the oldest and most widespread religions of the world, and one which in India was possibly, in its origins, independent of the Brahmanic religion as presented to us in the Vaidik Samhitas and Brahmanas. If this be so, it was later on undoubtedly mingled with the Vedanta tradition, so that the Shakta faith of to-day is a particular presentation of the general Vedantik teaching. This is historical speculation from an outside standpoint. As the Sarvollasa of Sarvanandanatha points out, and as is well-known to all adherents of the Shakta Agamas, Veda in its general sense includes these and other Shastras in what is called the great Shatakoti Samhita. Whatever be the origins of doctrine (and this should not be altogether overlooked in any proper appreciation of it), I am here concerned with its philosophical aspect, as shown to us to-day in the teachings and practice of the Shaktas who are followers of the Agama. This teaching occupies in some sense a middle place between the dualism of Samkhya, and Shamkara’s ultra-monistic interpretation of Vedanta to which, unless otherwise stated, I refer. Both the Shaiva and Shakta schools accept the threefold aspect of the Supreme known as Prakasha, Vimarsha and Prakasha-Vimarsha called in Tantrik worship,“The Three Feet”(Caranatritaya). Both adopt the Thirty-six Tattvas, Shiva, Shakti, Sadashiva, Ishvara and Shuddhavidya, preceding the Purusha-Prakriti Tattvas with which the Samkhya commences. For whereas these are the ultimate Tattvas in that Philosophy, the Shaiva and Shakta schools claim to showhow Purusha and Prakriti are themselves derived from higher Tattvas. These latter Tattvas are also dealt with from the Shabda side as Shakti, Nada, Bindu and as Kalas which are the Kriya of the various grades of Tattvas which are aspects of Shakti. The Shakta Tantras, such as the Saubhagyaratnakara and other works, speak of ninety-four of such Kalas appropriate to Sadashiva, Ishvara, Rudra, Vishnu, and Brahma,“Sun,”“Moon,’and“Fire,”(indicated in the form of the Ram Bija with Candrabindu transposed) of which fifty-one are Matrika Kalas, being the subtle aspects of the gross letters of Sanskrit alphabet. This last is the Mimamsaka doctrine of Shabda adapted to the doctrine of Shakti. Common also to both Shakta and Shaiva Sampradayas is the doctrine of the Shadadhva. (See my Garland of Letters).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 SHAKTA ADVAITAVADA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/18_SHAKTA_ADVAITAVADA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/18_SHAKTA_ADVAITAVADA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER EIGHTEEN. SHAKTA ADVAITAVADA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have often been asked-In what consists the difference between Vedanta and‘Tantra’. This question is the product of substantial error, for it assumes that Tantra Shastra is not based on Vedanta. I hope that, after many years of work, I have now made it clear that the Tantra Shastra or Agama (whatever be its ultimate origin as to which little is known by anybody) is now, and has been for centuries past, one of the recognized Scriptures of Hinduism, and every form of Hinduism is based on Veda and Vedanta. Another erroneous question, though less so, is-In what consists the difference between Advaita Vedanta and‘Tantra’Shastra. But here again, the question presupposes a misunderstanding of both Vedanta and Agama. There are, as should be well known, several schools of Advaita Vedanta, such as Mayavada (with which too commonly the Advaita Vedanta is identified), such as the schools of the Northern Shaivagama, and Shuddhadvaita of Vallabhacarya. In the same way, there are different schools of doctrine and worship in what are called the‘Tantras’, and a grievous mistake is committed when the Tantra is made to mean the Shakta Tantra only, such as is prevalent in Bengal and which, according to some, is either the product of, or has been influenced by Buddhism. Some English-speaking Bengalis of a past day, too ready to say,“Aye aye,”to the judgments of foreign critics, on their religion as on everything else, and in a hurry to dissociate themselves from their country’s“superstitions,”were the source of the notion which has had such currency amongst Europeans that,“Tantra”necessarily meant drinking wine and so forth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 CREATION AS EXPLAINED IN THE NON-DUALIST TANTRAS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/19_CREATION_AS_EXPLAINED_IN_THE_NON-DUALIST_TANTRAS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/19_CREATION_AS_EXPLAINED_IN_THE_NON-DUALIST_TANTRAS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER NINETEEN. CREATION AS EXPLAINED IN THE NON-DUALIST TANTRAS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Psychological analysis of our worldly experience ordinarily gives us both the feeling of persistence and change. This personal experience expresses a cosmic truth. An examination of any doctrine of creation similarly reveals two fundamental concepts, those of Being and Becoming, Changelessness and Change, the One and the Many. In Sanskrit, they are called the Kutastha and Bhava or Bhavana. The first is the Spirit or Purusha or Brahman and Atman which is unlimited Being (Sat), Consciousness (Cit) and Bliss (Ananda). According to Indian notions the Atman as suchis and never becomes. Its Power (Shakti) manifests as Nature, which is the subject of change. We may understand Nature in a two-fold sense: first, as the root principle or noumenal cause of the phenomenal world, that is, as the Principle of Becoming and secondly, as such World. Nature in the former sense is Mulaprakriti, which means that which exists as the root (Mula) substance of things before (Pra), creation (Kriti), and which, in association with Cit, either truly or apparently creates, maintains and destroys the Universe. This Mulaprakriti the Sharada Tilaka calls Mulabhuta Avyakta, and the Vedanta (of Shamkara to which alone I refer) Maya.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 THE INDIAN MAGNA MATER</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/20_THE_INDIAN_MAGNA_MATER/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/20_THE_INDIAN_MAGNA_MATER/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY. THE INDIAN MAGNA MATER&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introductory&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On the last occasion that I had the honor to address you, I dealt with the subject of the psychology of Hindu religious ritual from the particular standpoint of the religious community called Shaktas, or Worshippers of the Supreme Mother. To-day I speak of the Supreme Mother Herself as conceived and worshipped by them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The worship of the Great Mother as the Grand Multiplier is one of the oldest in the world. As I have elsewhere said, when we throw our minds back upon the history of this worship, we discern even in the most remote and fading past the Figure, most ancient, of the mighty Mother of Nature. I suspect that in the beginning the Goddess everywhere antedated, or at least was predominant over, the God. It has been affirmed (Glotz: Ægean Civilization, 243) that in all countries from the Euphrates to the Adriatic, the Chief Divinity was at first in woman form. Looking to the east of the Euphrates we see the Dusk Divinity of India, the Adya-Shakti and Maha-Shakti, or Supreme Power of many names-as Jagadamba, Mother of the World, which is the Play of Her who is named Lalita, Maya, Mahatripurasundari and Maha-kundalini, as Maha-Vaishnavi, the Sapphire Devi who supports the World, as Mahakali who dissolves it, as Guhyamahabhairavi, and all the rest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 HINDU RITUAL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/21_HINDU_RITUAL/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/21_HINDU_RITUAL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-ONE. HINDU RITUAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is well said that Ritual is the Art of Religion. As practiced by the Hindus, it is not rightly judged, because the religious and philosophical doctrines of which it is a practical expression and method are either unknown or misunderstood. If we add to incapacity, a temperament hostile to all Ritualism, the resultant criticism is “mummery,” “idolatry,” “gibberish,” and so forth. It is true that Ritual is meaningless to those who do not know its meaning; just as a telegram sent in cipher is without sense to those who are ignorant of the code according to which it is written. It may, however, be admitted that in so far as, and to the extent that Ritual is carried out without understanding on the part of the worshipper, such criticisms may, to that extent, be justified. Despite shallow views, Ritual is a necessity for men as whole. Those who profess to reject it in religion are yet found to adhere to it, in some form or other, in social and political life. The necessity of Ritual is shown by well-known historical reactions. Degeneracy leads to “Protestant” abolitions. The jejune worship of the “reformer” lacks appeal and power and Ritual comes into its own again. This oscillation is well marked in Europe in the history of Catholicism and Protestantism. It is displayed again in the East in Buddhism, which, starting as a revolt from an excessive Vaidik Ritual, adopted in the end the elaborate rites to be found in the Hindu and Buddhist Tantras. The Brahmanic position is the middle and stable way, acknowledging the value of both the “Protestant” and “Catholic” attitude. Its view is that all men need Ritual, but in varying degree and various kinds, until they are Siddha, that is, until they have achieved the end which Ritual is designed to secure. When the end is gained there is no longer need for the means to it. Further, the need becomes less and less as approach is made to that end. The Ritual must be suitable to the spiritual attainments and disposition of the worshipper. For the simple and ignorant the Ritual is of a Sthula or gross kind. The word Sthula in Sanskrit does not necessarily imply any moral censure. It is here used as the opposite of Sukshma or subtle. Again, count is taken of human emotion and of its varieties. The dispositions or temperaments, or Bhava, of worshippers vary. One worshipper may place himself before the Lord in the relation of a servant towards his Master, another in the relation of a friend, and yet another in the relation of a lover. In the same way, Yoga, in the sense of a system of self-control and self-fulfillment, varies. For those who are predominantly intellectual there is the Yoga of Knowledge (Jñana); for those in whom emotion is strong there is the Yoga of Devotion (Bhakti); for such as belong to neither of these classes there is the great Yoga of Action (Karma). The end to which each medially or directly works is the same. There is, in fact, no religion more Catholic than Hinduism. For this reason, those who dislike and fear it, speak of its “rapacious maw”. It has in fact, an enormous faculty of assimilation; for there is in it that which will satisfy all views and temperaments. In the West, we are too apt to quarrel with views and practices which we dislike. We will not, in such case, accept them, but that is not necessarily a reason why those who like them should not do so. Thus, to some, all Ritual is repellent, or some kinds of devotion, such as the use of erotic imagery. Let each take or reject what is suitable or unsuitable to him. Controversy is futile. Fitness or Adhikara is a fundamental principle of Hinduism. Some may be fit for one doctrine and practice, and others not. The wisdom of the universal man with a world-mind converts many an absolute judgment into a relative one. For the judgment, “This is bad,” he will substitute, “This is not good for me”. In this way, he will both save own health and temper, and that of the other.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 VEDANTA AND TANTRA SHASTRA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/22_VEDANTA_AND_TANTRA_SHASTRA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/22_VEDANTA_AND_TANTRA_SHASTRA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-TWO. VEDANTA AND TANTRA SHASTRA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When your representative asked me to speak this evening, he suggested to me as my subject, that Shastra which is a practical application of the Vedantic teaching. Mere talk about Vedanta is nothing but a high form of amusement. If more than this is to be achieved, definite Sadhana is necessary. In the grand opening chapter of the Kularnava Tantra it is said: “In this world are countless masses of beings suffering all manner of pain. Old age is waiting like a tigress. Life ebbs away as it were water from out of a broken pot. Disease kills like enemies. Prosperity is but a dream; youth is like a flower. Life is seen and is gone like lightning. The body is but a bubble of water. How then can one know this and yet remain content? The Jivatma passes through lakhs of existence, yet only as man can he obtain the truth. It is with great difficulty that one is born as man.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 THE PSYCHOLOGY OF HINDU RELIGIOUS RITUAL</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/23_THE_PSYCHOLOGY_OF_HINDU_RELIGIOUS_RITUAL/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/23_THE_PSYCHOLOGY_OF_HINDU_RELIGIOUS_RITUAL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-THREE. THE PSYCHOLOGY OF HINDU RELIGIOUS RITUAL&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The word “religious” in the title of this lecture has been inserted in order to exclude magical ritual, with which I do not deal, though I have a word or two to say on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As regards the word “Hindu,” it must be remembered that there is considerable variety of doctrine and ritual, for there are a number of communities of Indian worshippers. Though, perhaps, too much stress is generally laid on these differences, and sufficient notice is not taken of fundamental points of agreement, yet there are differences, and if we are to be exact, we must not forget that fact. It is not, of course, possible, during the hour or so at my disposal, to treat of all these differences. I have, therefore, selected the ritual of one of these communities called Shaktas. These worshippers are so called because they worship the great Mother-Power or Mahashakti. Their doctrine and practice is of importance, because, (as an Italian author has recently observed), of its accentuation of Will and Power. He describes it as “a magnificent ensemble of metaphysic, magic and devotion raised on grandiose foundations”. And so, whether it be acceptable or not, I think it is. The title, therefore, is, in this matter, not exact. Some of what is here said is of common application and some is peculiar to the Shaktas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 SHAKTI AS MANTRA \(MANTRAMAYI SHAKTI\)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/24_SHAKTI_AS_MANTRA_MANTRAMAYI_SHAKTI/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/24_SHAKTI_AS_MANTRA_MANTRAMAYI_SHAKTI/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-FOUR. SHAKTI AS MANTRA (MANTRAMAYI SHAKTI)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is in every way both a most important, as well as a most difficult, subject in the Tantra Shastra; so, difficult that it is not understood, and on this account, has been ridiculed. Mantra, in the words of a distinguished Indian, has been called “meaningless jabber”. When we find Indians thus talking of their Shastra, it is not surprising that Europeans should take it to be of no account. They naturally, though erroneously, suppose that the Indian always understands his own beliefs, and if he says they are absurd it is taken that they are so. Even, however, amongst Indians, who have lost themselves through an English Education, the Science of Mantra is largely unknown. There are not many students of the Mimamsa now-a-days. The English-educated have in this, as in other matters, generally taken the cue from their Western Gurus, and passed upon Mantravidya a borrowed condemnation. There are those among them (particularly in this part of India), those who have in the past thought little of their old culture, and have been only too willing to sell their old lamps for new ones. Because they are new they will not always be found to give better light. Let us hope this will change, as indeed it will. Before the Indian condemns his cultural inheritance let him at least first study and understand it. It is true that Mantra is meaningless &amp;ndash; to those who do not know its meaning; but to those who do, it is not “Jabber”; though of course like everything else it may become, and indeed has become, the subject of ignorance and superstitious use. A telegram written in code in a merchant’s office will seem the merest gibberish to those who do not know that code. Those who do may spell thereout a transaction bringing lakhs of “real” Rupees for those who have sent it. Mantravidya, whether it be true or not, is a profoundly conceived science, and, as interpreted by the Shakta Agama, is a practical application of Vedantic doctrine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 VARNAMALA \(THE GARLAND OF LETTERS\)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/25_VARNAMALA_THE_GARLAND_OF_LETTERS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/25_VARNAMALA_THE_GARLAND_OF_LETTERS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-FIVE. VARNAMALA (THE GARLAND OF LETTERS)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The world has never altogether been without the Wisdom, nor its Teachers. The degree and manner in which it has been imparted have, however, necessarily varied according to the capacities of men to receive it. Soalso,have the symbols by which it has been conveyed. These symbols further have varying significance according to the spiritual advancement of the worshipper. This question of degree and variety of presentation have led to the superficial view that the difference in beliefs negatives existence of any commonly established Truth. But if the matter be regarded more deeply, it will be seen that whilst there is one essential Wisdom, its revelation has been more or less complete according to symbols evolved by, and, therefore, fitting to, particular racial temperaments and characters. Symbols are naturally misunderstood by those to whom the beliefs they typify are unfamiliar, and who differ in temperament from those who have evolved them. To the ordinary Western mind the symbols of Hindusim are often repulsive and absurd. It must not, however, be forgotten that some of the Symbols of Western Faiths have the same effect on the Hindu. From the picture of the“Slain Lamb,”and other symbols in terms of blood and death, he naturally shrinks in disgust. The same effect on the other hand, is not seldom produced in the Western at the sight of the terrible forms in which India has embodied Her vision of the undoubted Terrors which exist in and around us. All is not smiling in this world. Even amongst persons of the same race and indeed of the same faith we may observe such differences. Before the Catholic Cultus of the“Sacred Heart”had overcome the opposition which it at first encountered, and for a considerable time after, its imagery was regarded with aversion by some who spoke of it in terms which would be to-day counted as shocking irreverence. These differences are likely to exist so long as men vary in mental attitude and temperament, and until they reach the stage in which, having discovered the essential truths, they become indifferent to the mode in which they are presented. We must also in such matters distinguish between what a symbol may have meant and what it now means. Until quite recent times, the English peasant folk and others danced around the flower-wreathed Maypole. That the pole originally (like other similar forms) represented the great Linga admits of as little doubt as that these folk, who in recent ages danced around it, were ignorant of that fact. The Bishop’s mitre is said to be the head of a fish worn by ancient near-eastern hierophants. But what of that? It has other associations now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 SHAKTA SADHANA \(THE ORDINARY RITUAL\)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/26_SHAKTA_SADHANA_THE_ORDINARY_RITUAL/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/26_SHAKTA_SADHANA_THE_ORDINARY_RITUAL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-SIX. SHAKTA SADHANA (THE ORDINARY RITUAL)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sadhana is that, which produces Siddhi or the result sought, be it material or spiritual advancement. It is the means or practice by which the desired end may be attained and consists in the training and exercise of the body and psychic faculties, upon the gradual perfection of which Siddhi follows. The nature or degree of spiritual Siddhi depends upon the progress made towards the realization of the Atma whose veiling vesture the body is. The means employed are numerous and elaborate, such as worship (Puja) exterior or mental, Shastric learning, austerities (Tapas), Japa or recitation of Mantra, Hymns, meditation, and so forth. The Sadhana is necessarily of a nature and character appropriate to the end sought.Thus,Sadhana for spiritual knowledge (Brahmajñana) which consists of external control (Dama) over the ten senses (Indriya), internal control (Sama) over the mind (Buddhi, Ahamkara, Manas), discrimination between the transitory and eternal, renunciation of both the world and heaven (Svarga), differs from the lower Sadhana of the ordinary householder, and both are obviously of a kind different from that prescribed and followed by the practitioners of malevolent magic (Abhicara). Sadhakas again vary in their physical, mental and moral qualities and are thus divided into four classes, Mridu, Madhya, Adhimatraka, and the highest Adhimatrama who is qualified (Adhikari) for all forms of Yoga. In a similar way, the Shakta Kaulas are divided into the Prakrita or common Kaula following Viracara with the Pancatattvas described in the following Chapter; the middling (Madhyama) Kaula who (may be) follows the same or other Sadhana but who is of a higher type, and the highest Kaula (Kaulikottama) who, having surpassed all ritualism, meditates upon the Universal Self. These are more particularly described in the next Chapter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 THE PAÑCATATTVA \(THE SECRET RITUAL\)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/27_THE_PACATATTVA_THE_SECRET_RITUAL/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/27_THE_PACATATTVA_THE_SECRET_RITUAL/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-SEVEN. THE PAÑCATATTVA (THE SECRET RITUAL)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The notoriety of the Shakta Pañcatattva ritual with wine and women has thrown into the shade not only the practical topics with which I have dealt, but every other, including the valuable philosophical presentment of Vedanta contained in the Shakta Tantra. Notwithstanding, and indeed because, of the off-hand and (in certain respects) ignorant condemnation which this ritual has received, the interests of both scholarship and fairness (which by the way should be identical) require, that we should first ascertain the facts, think clearly and fearlessly, and then determine without prejudice. From both the Shastrik and historical point of view the subject is of such importance that it is not possible for me to here deal with it otherwise than in a very general way. It is necessary, however, in a paper on Upasana, to at least touch upon the matter because as against everything one says about the Tantras, there is raised the express or implied query“That may be all very well. But what about the infamous Pañcamakara?”Anything said in favor of the Shastra is thus discounted in advance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 MATAM RUTRA \(THE RIGHT AND WRONG INTERPRETATION\)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/28_MATAM_RUTRA_THE_RIGHT_AND_WRONG_INTERPRETATION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/28_MATAM_RUTRA_THE_RIGHT_AND_WRONG_INTERPRETATION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-EIGHT. MATAM RUTRA (THE RIGHT AND WRONG INTERPRETATION)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In connection with the doctrine and Sadhana just described it is apposite to cite the following legend from Tibet, which shows how, according to its Sadhakas, it may be either rightly or wrongly interpreted, and how, in the latter case, it leads to terrible evils and their punishment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Guru Padma-sambhava, the so-called founder of“Lamaism,”had five women disciples who compiled several accounts of the teachings of their Master and hid them in various places for the benefit of future believers. One of these disciples,Khandro Yeshe Tsogyal,was a Tibetan lady who is said to have possessed such a wonderful power of memory that if she was told a thing only once she remembered it for ever. She gathered what she had heard from her Guru into a book called the Padma Thangyig Serteng or Golden Rosary of the history of her Guru who was entitled the Lotus-born (Padmasambhava). The book was hidden away and was subsequently, under inspiration, revealed some five hundred yearsago,by a Terton.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 KUNDALINI SHAKTA \(YOGA\)</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/29_KUNDALINI_SHAKTA_YOGA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/29_KUNDALINI_SHAKTA_YOGA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER TWENTY-NINE. KUNDALINI SHAKTA (YOGA)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The word“Yoga”comes from the root “yuj” which means“to join”and, in its spiritual sense, it is that process by which the human spirit is brought into near and conscious communion with, or is merged in, the Divine Spirit, according as the nature of the human spirit is held to be separate from (Dvaita, Vishishtadvaita) or one with (Advaita) the Divine Spirit. As, according to Shakta doctrine, with which alone we are concerned, the latter proposition is affirmed, Yoga is that process by which the identity of the two (Jivatma and Paramatma), which identity ever in fact exists, is realized by the Yogi or practitioner of Yoga. It is so realized because the Spirit has then pierced through the veil of Maya which as mind and matter obscures this knowledge from itself. The means by which this is achieved is the Yoga process which liberates from Maya.So,the Gheranda Samhita, a Hathayoga treatise of the Tantrik school, says (Chap. 5):“There is no bond equal in strength to Maya, and no power greater to destroy that bond than Yoga.”From an Advaita or Monistic standpoint, Yoga in the sense of a final union is inapplicable, for union implies a dualism of the Divine and Human spirit. In such a case, it denotes the process rather than the result. When the two are regarded as distinct, Yoga may apply to both. A person who practices Yoga is called a“Yogi.”According to Indian notions all are not competent (Adhikari) to attempt Yoga; only a very few are. One must, in this or in other lives, have first gone through Karma or ritual, and Upasana or devotional worship and obtained the fruit thereof, namely, a pure mind (Citta-shuddhi). This Sanskrit term does not merely mean a mind free from sexual impurity, as an English reader might suppose. The attainment of this and other good qualities is the A B C of Sadhana. A person may have a pure mind in this sense and yet be wholly incapable of Yoga. Citta-shuddhi consists not merely in moral purity of every kind, but in knowledge, detachment, capacity for pure intellectual functioning, attention, meditation and so forth. When, by Karma and Upasana, the mind is brought to this point and when, in the case of Vedantik Yoga, there is dispassion and detachment from the world and its desires, then the Yoga path is open for the realization of Tattva-jñana, that is ultimate Truth. Very few persons indeed are competent for Yoga in its higher forms. The majority should seek their advancement along the path of ritual and devotion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 CONCLUSIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/30_CONCLUSIONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/avalon-arthur_woodroffe/shakti_and_shAkta/30_CONCLUSIONS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CHAPTER THIRTY. CONCLUSIONS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brahmanism or Hinduism, as in its later development the former has been called, is not merely a religion. It is a Socio-Economic System, the foundation of which is the Law of Caste and Stages of life. That System has its culture of which several forms of Religion, resting on a certain common basis, are but a part. Dealing, however, with Brahmanism in its religious aspect, we may say that it, together with Jainism and Buddhism, are the three chief religions of India, as opposed to those of the Semitic origin. All three religious systems share in common certain fundamental concepts which are denoted by the Sanskrit termsKarma, SamsaraandMoksha.These concepts constitute a common denominator of Indian belief as next stated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
