<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/yogaH/meta/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/yogaH/meta/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>DattAtreyan yatis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/yogaH/meta/MT/dattAtreyan-yatis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/yogaH/meta/MT/dattAtreyan-yatis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/2008429274168971603&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;separation-from-mantra-sadhakas&#34;&gt;Separation from mantra-sAdhakas&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At some point in the medieval period, the dattAtreyan ascetics separated out of the matrix of the shaiva, vaiShNava and bauddha mantra-sAdhaka-s. They began propounding a new program of yoga, which held rAjayoga to be the highest form of practice. This is made explicit in the dattAtreya’s yoga taught to another atri, sAMkR^iti.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;teachings&#34;&gt;Teachings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It has two sub-teachings: the aShTA&lt;del&gt;Ngayoga attributed to yAj&lt;/del&gt;navalkya and the haThayoga of kapila. The teaching of dattAtreya has come down to us in multiple texts, primarily the dattAtreya-saMhitA or yogashAstra, and the yogatattvopaniShad:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mantra-mArga origins</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/yogaH/meta/MT/mantra-mArga-origins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/yogaH/meta/MT/mantra-mArga-origins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/2008777977388028146&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;mayurasana&#34;&gt;mayUrAsana&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The mayUrAsana, where you hoist yourself on your posteriorly directed palms, was most likely invented by the vaikhAnasa-s. The urethral yoga-s of vajroli (bauddha vajrayANa) and amaroli (amaraugha-shAsana: shaiva successors of mIna) were probably derived from an ancestral version of this in the shaiva tradition.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;khechari&#34;&gt;khecharI&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;khecharI-mudra and at least two of the tri-bandha-s &amp;ndash; jAlandhara and oDDiyAna &amp;ndash; were canonized in the kaula tradition, most likely starting with the pUrvAmnAya (trika). Of course, khecharI has deep roots going back to the maitrAyaNIya shruti of the yajurveda itself, and a version of it close to the upaniShad was likely practiced by the tathAgata. But its integration into the mantramArga happens in the pUrvAmnAya as indicated by the khecharI-mudra tantra. It was subsequently also acquired by the pA~ncharAtrika vaiShNava-s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
