<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/meta/myth/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/meta/myth/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>musingsofhh</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/meta/myth/articles/2012-09-23_german-christian-in-dialogue-with-balinese-on-rama/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/meta/myth/articles/2012-09-23_german-christian-in-dialogue-with-balinese-on-rama/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://musingsofhh.wordpress.com/2012/09/23/german-christian-in-dialogue-with-balinese-on-ramayanas-historicity/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://musingsofhh.wordpress.com/2012/09/23/german-christian-in-dialogue-with-balinese-on-ramayanas-historicity/&#34;&gt;German Christian in Dialogue with Balinese on Ramayana’s Historicity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;September 23, 2012&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is not a post by Hauma Hamiddha but something I found interesting nonetheless, so sharing it:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the contemporary era we can see a great deal of continuity between modern conceptions of religion and the Christian understanding of &lt;em&gt;religio&lt;/em&gt;. Both tend to place a great deal of emphasis upon a faithful (&lt;em&gt;sic&lt;/em&gt;) adherence to doctrine as indicative of religious allegiance, upon sacred texts as of central importance to religious communities and to questions of truth and falsity as of paramount importance to the religious adherent or ‘believer’. The Christian interest in the truth and falsity of religion is distinctive in this aspect and the emphasis it places upon the importance of the historicity of the gospel story and the falsity of pagan mythologies. This is in sharp contrast to the pagan Roman approach, which does not project a dichotomy between myth and history onto the category of &lt;em&gt;religio&lt;/em&gt;. It would seem that this characteristically Christian approach to religion is also a source of perplexity for those who remain culturally uninfluenced by it. German writer Bichsel relates the following conversation between himself and a young Balinese Hindu.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
