<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;04 Traditions in Transition and Conflict on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/04_Traditions_in_Transition_and_Conflict/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;04 Traditions in Transition and Conflict on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/04_Traditions_in_Transition_and_Conflict/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>13 The Jain Monk Jinapati Suri Gets the Better of a Nath Yogi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/04_Traditions_in_Transition_and_Conflict/13_The_Jain_Monk_Jinapati_Suri_Gets_the_Better_of_a_Nath_Yogi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/04_Traditions_in_Transition_and_Conflict/13_The_Jain_Monk_Jinapati_Suri_Gets_the_Better_of_a_Nath_Yogi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Paul Dundas&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps more than any other Indian religious tradition, Jainism has placed a high  value on maintaining barriers of physical and moral restraint and self-discipline  in order to advance on the path to liberation. The entire regimen of the religion&amp;rsquo;s  adherents, at least as ideally conceived, has been oriented toward the ascetic  quieting of the mind, body, and speech. The aim is to reduce and ultimately  eliminate the flow of karmic matter, which brings about both the soul&amp;rsquo;s embod&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Longchenpa and the Possession of the Dakinis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/04_Traditions_in_Transition_and_Conflict/14_Longchenpa_and_the_Possession_of_the_Dakinis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/04_Traditions_in_Transition_and_Conflict/14_Longchenpa_and_the_Possession_of_the_Dakinis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;David Germano and Janet Gyatso&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lay communities of itinerant yogins and yoginis have been a vital dimension of  Tibetan Buddhist culture from at least the ninth century onward. These com munities were almost always irreducibly Tantric in character, in their ritual and  contemplative practices, their textual traditions, and the very structure of their  communal life. Although much of our information about early Tantric Buddhist  . communities in India and Tibet is fragmentary and heavily mythologized, detailed  biographical and historical narratives that emerged in in later centuries in Tibet  give a fuller portrayal of the nature of these communities, and afford us a glimpse  of actual male-female relationships. We have chosen to translate a depiction of  the fourteenth-century Tibetan saint Longchenpa&amp;rsquo;s (Klong chen pa, 1308-1363)  ritual empowerment of a group of Tibetan yogins and yoginis into esoteric Tantric  practices. The action portrayed here occurred in the spring of 1339. The work is  signed by Longchenpa himself in the colophon and is specifically referred to as  his composition in his own catalogue to The Seminal Quintessence of the Dakinis,  which is the larger cycle of his texts in which it is found. It refers to him through&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 The Anonymous Agama Prakasa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/04_Traditions_in_Transition_and_Conflict/15_The_Anonymous_Agama_Prakasa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/04_Traditions_in_Transition_and_Conflict/15_The_Anonymous_Agama_Prakasa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Anonymous Agama Prakasa: Preface to  a Nineteenth-Century Gujarati Polemic&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Robin Rinehart and Tony K. Stewart&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1874, a substantial Gujarati book was published in the city of Ahmedabad by  an anonymous author, with a lengthy English title: Exposition of the Nigamas or  that portion of Hindoo Shastras which the dukshinas or Right Hand sect follows as their  books of revelation, i.e. Vedas, Sootra, Smritis, Pooranas &amp;amp;c. For the use of reformers  in India by the author of the &amp;ldquo;Nibandha Sangraha.&amp;rdquo; The author prefaced the text,  which included extensive Sanskrit passages from more than seventy different  texts, like this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Conversation between Guru Hasan Kabiruddm and Jogi Kanipha</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/04_Traditions_in_Transition_and_Conflict/16_Conversation_between_Guru_Hasan_Kabiruddm_and_Jogi_Kanipha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/04_Traditions_in_Transition_and_Conflict/16_Conversation_between_Guru_Hasan_Kabiruddm_and_Jogi_Kanipha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Conversation between Guru Hasan Kabiruddm and  Jogi Kanipha: Tantra Revisited by the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Isma&amp;quot;ili Preachers&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dominique-Sila Khan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ismailism, a form of Shi&amp;rsquo;a Islam, entered the Indian subcontinent toward the end  of the eighth century C.E. In 1094 it underwent a major split, from which there  emerged two main branches. The Nizari sect, originally known as the &amp;ldquo;new mis sion,&amp;rdquo; was first based in Iran, but soon spread to Syria and Central Asia, as well  as into the subcontinent, perhaps as early as the twelfth century. As Daftary and  Corbin have shown, Isma&amp;rsquo;ilism can be broadly defined as a well-organized rev olutionary type of movement, undergirded by a complex esoteric philosophy.  Persecuted by the Sunni rulers of Delhi, who cast themselves as the representatives  of an &amp;ldquo;orthodox&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;normative&amp;rdquo; Islam, the Indian Isma&amp;rsquo;ilis, viewed as heretics,  generally resorted to the Shi&amp;rsquo;a custom of precautionary concealment of one&amp;rsquo;s true  faith (taqiyya). At the same time, they adopted a strategy that involved accepting  most of the beliefs and practices of the people they sought to convert while  gradually transforming the same to fit the requirements of their own doctines.  This method, however, should not be viewed solely as a tactic for conversion but  rather as an essential part of Isma&amp;rsquo;ili philosophy: not merely a later evolute of  Islam, their faith was also a &amp;ldquo;culmination of Hinduism.&amp;rdquo; Rather than rejecting the  established beliefs and practices of local populations, the Nizari missionaries ab sorbed and adapted them in order to create what Maclean has righly called &amp;ldquo;an  innovative synthesis,&amp;rdquo; in which Muslim and Hindu elements were harmoniously  combined.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
