<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Cult competition on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Cult competition on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Evolution</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/evolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/evolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kernosovskiy and related images show shrauta kuNDa-s, praNIta-like pAtra &amp;amp; sruva or darvi; along with ithyphallic deity with weapons. Proto-shrauta fire-ritual, deity cults (even atimArga) and idol worship existed in parallel from ancient times.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Invasion state (from &lt;a href=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/note/sapiens/branches/Aryan/satem/indo-iranian/indo-aryan/india/1_invasion/meta-invasion/articles/MT/identity-impact&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;):&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The front end of the wave was led by IA speakers with a hotraka &amp;ldquo;indra-para&amp;rdquo; religious core. At their rear were the ancestors of the Kalasha &amp;amp; probably Brokpa (&lt;del&gt;drokpa&lt;/del&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On the steppe, just behind the first wave was an IA group with a distinct religious approach &amp;ndash; Adhvaryava &amp;amp; viShNu-focal with some rudra-focal elements scattered in their midst.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A more rudra-focal group lay on the steppes in the borderland with the Ir.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prājāpatya tradition rose as well, leading to Aindra decline..&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Core saMhitA-s were compiled in the kuru-pAnchAla realm; followed by the brAhmaNa-s and then the sUtra-s. Ritual was standardized, with Adhvaryava domination - leading to the emergence of pAncharAtra from SYV and vaikhAnasa from KYV.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;vedAnga-s blossomed.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;shikShA, kalpa, ChandaH, vyAkaraNa, jyotiSha took off.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;On the mīmāṃsā front, the development of the Śaunakīya tradition was limited and formulaic after the Bṛhaddevatā and Nirukta. Instead, daivimīmāṃsā was overtaken by tendencies that had a more Kautsa structure even if not explicitly so.&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/tattvam/articles/MT/learn_from_platonists/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Unanchored&amp;rdquo; brahmavāda (i.e., philosophy of brahman that gets increasingly decoupled from the ancestral pantheon) arose.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;nAstika counter-religions emerged - jaina, bauddha ..&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Unanchored sāṃkhyā resulted in philosophical developments (otherwise very parallel to the yavana ones) that increasingly lost touch with the foundational layer of the religion.&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/tattvam/articles/MT/learn_from_platonists/&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;yoga and sectarian proto-Agamas developed on sAnkhya and some brahmavāda foundations. Temples.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;prameya-centric vaisheShika school emerged off sAnkhya foundations. pramANa-centric nyAya developed as well; strengthened by competition with the nAstika-s.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sectarian ritual traditions, being more welcoming of non-Arya-s, grew in popularity, overshadowing the shrauta orthodoxy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Off brahmavAda rooted in brahma-sUtras (in some cases with sectarian Agama-s and purANa-s), various vedAntic schools developed.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Agama-based systems overcame orthodox opposition (&amp;ldquo;Vedaviruddham&amp;rdquo;) - based on writings and practices of shrautin-s who also adhered to Agama-s.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;With severe decline in royal patronage, shrauta tradition declined further. (Mostly vedAntic) maTha-s stepped into the vacuum and lapped up remaining smArta-s.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;With repeated invasions, brAhmaNa-dominance of religion weakened to the point where baba-isms, increasingly detached from old and new shAstra-s, bloomed - some of counter-religious nature.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Post European invasion and the scientific revolution, some hindu-s reexamined the history of their religion and its sister branches (including platonism).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>पर-मत-खण्डनम्</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/para-mata-khaNDanam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/para-mata-khaNDanam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenges-and-debates&#34;&gt;Challenges and debates&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A tradition which values challenges and confidently challenges others, is superior to one which doesn&amp;rsquo;t, and hides behind red herrings such as &amp;ldquo;see we don&amp;rsquo;t publicize/ don&amp;rsquo;t debate, so we&amp;rsquo;re OG&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some traditions are naturally fraudulent and hollow - much to be reticent about.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eg. we have yogi-s bullshitting about abilities to cure AIDS, flying in the sky and so on;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;while folks such as that 19yo daNDa-krama reciter open themselves to objective testing and reality-checks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
