<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;03 Studies in Early Saivism on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/03_Studies_in_Early_Saivism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;03 Studies in Early Saivism on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/03_Studies_in_Early_Saivism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 Sources for Reconstructing Ancient Forms of Siva Worship ´</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/03_Studies_in_Early_Saivism/01_Sources_for_Reconstructing_Ancient_Forms_of_Siv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/03_Studies_in_Early_Saivism/01_Sources_for_Reconstructing_Ancient_Forms_of_Siv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Siva Caturmukha ´&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The myth of Tilottamā&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In chapter 203 of the Adiparvan ¯ of the Mahābhārata we are told that, in order to kill the Asuras Sunda and Upasunda, who could only be killed by each other, Viśvakarman, ordered by Brahmā, creates a woman of unparallelled beauty. The Grandfather tells her to go to the two demons and to seduce them in order that they may kill one and other in their rivalry over her. This beauty, named Tilottamā, promises to do so and takes her leave of the gods by making a circumambulatioṇAmong those gods is Bhagavat Maheśvara, who sits to the south (sciḷof Brahmā) with his face turned east, whereas the gods sit to the north (of him) and the r̥ṣis all around (see below Textual Sources No. 2 (TS 2) v. 21). Only Indra and Bhagavat Sthāṇu (i.e. Maheśvara) are able to preserve their composure, but the latter’s excessive desire to watch her (draṣṭu kāmasya cātyartham. ) leads to the coming forth of three more faces (mukha), one directed towards the south, which is possessed of curling lashes (añcita pakṣmāntam), one to the west and one to the north, the latter two not further qualified (TS 2 vv. 22–24). In this way Sthāṇu Mahādeva became four-faced (caturmukhah.). Indra, on the other hand, issues forth eyes on all sides up to a thousand (TS 2 vv. 25–26).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 At the Right Side of the Teacher</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/03_Studies_in_Early_Saivism/02_At_the_Right_Side_of_the_Teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/03_Studies_in_Early_Saivism/02_At_the_Right_Side_of_the_Teacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imagination, Imagery, and Image in Vedic and Saiva Initiation ´&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then shall the King say unto them on his right hand,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Come, ye blessed of my Father, inherit the kingdom&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;prepared for you from the foundation of the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Matthew 25: 34 (cf. Ecclesiastes 10: 2)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The transformation of the Vedic religion into new systems of belief and prac tice, early Hinduism for short, is a process of cultural change that, despite two centuries of research, has only partly been understood. The replacement of the sacrificial fire by images of wood and stone is among the most obvious innovations. As has been convincingly argued by Phyllis Granoff (2006), this in novation was only reluctantly accepted in some circles of brahmanic orthodoxy. On the other hand, there can be little doubt that Vedic imagination informed the concept of God and His image (mūrti) in the newly emerging religions. It found expression in the Sanskrit texts of early Hinduism. The confrontation of this textual evidence with the material images of the archaeologist is often perplexing, however.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Thanesar, the Pāśupata Order and the Skandapurāṇa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/03_Studies_in_Early_Saivism/03_Thanesar_the_pAshupata_Order_and_the_skandapurA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/03_Studies_in_Early_Saivism/03_Thanesar_the_pAshupata_Order_and_the_skandapurA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Studies in the Skandapurāṇa IX&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The tradition of the four pupils of Lagud ¯ .i&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By the middle of the sixth century the city of Kanauj seems to have emerged as the capital of the rising dynasty of the Maukharis under its king Īśānavarman. 1 This town, in the Sanskrit tradition named Kānyakubja/ Kanyakubja, is known from the Skandapurāṇa, and from this text only, as the seat of one of the Pāśupata lineages.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 The Gospel of Kauṇḍinya</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/03_Studies_in_Early_Saivism/04_The_Gospel_of_kauNDinya/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/03_Studies_in_Early_Saivism/04_The_Gospel_of_kauNDinya/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Descent of God in Gujarat and the Practice of Imitating God&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kauṇḍinya’s Panc˜ arthabh ¯ as¯.ya&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kuśika and the divine revelation&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we speak of the gospel of Kauṇḍinya, we call forth an association with texts which describe the birth, life, and deeds of a saviour, texts which are meant to bring good news, an evangelium, into the world. This evocation is deliberate. As a tribute to Jan Bremmer’s life-long engagement, scholarly and otherwise, with gospels and kindred texts that have just failed to reach that status, I would like to show, that a text called ‘The Five Topics’, Pañcārtha, which has the form of a commentary (bhāṣya) on the Sūtras of the Pāśupata school (the Pāśupatasūtras (PS)), resembles a gospel in many respects. Not only by the dramatic facts which it professes to report, but also by its apodictic style, and its pretence to communicate a divine revelation, presenting a unique path (sādhana), which alone is able to promise and deliver hope and salvation to the faithful. Its author, Kauṇḍinya, who may have lived in the 4th century ad, puts himself in the lineage of preceptors that descends directly from the divine teacher’s first disciple, Kuśika. 1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 The Quest for the Pāśupata Weapon</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/03_Studies_in_Early_Saivism/05_The_Quest_for_the_pAshupata_Weapon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/03_Studies_in_Early_Saivism/05_The_Quest_for_the_pAshupata_Weapon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Gateway of the Mahādeva Temple at&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Madhyamikā (Nagarī)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hans Bakker &amp;amp; Peter Bisschop&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The village of Nagarī is situated in the Chittorgarh District (Rajasthan), 11 km north of the famous fort. The present archaeological site lies to the south of the village on the right bank of the River Berach. The original citadel along the river extended further northwards and included the space presently occupied by the village (Plate 129).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
