<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/meta/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/meta/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Consenting bride abduction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/meta/articles/consenting-bride-abduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/meta/articles/consenting-bride-abduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/Sagnamadr/status/1885155567238602980&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Very interesting lecture &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtube.com/watch?v=wWS9CixLBgs&#34;&gt;Stephanie Jamison - draupadi troy&lt;/a&gt;, arguing that from IE literature, there was a legal, ritualized form of bride abduction in IE cultures, in which a messenger is send and consent is granted; an example being the Skírnismál.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An example of a myth surrounding unlawful bride abduction would be a folk tale from Lower Saxony.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In it, a man disapproved of his daughter’s fiancé, and arranged to have her abducted from her wedding by a warrior he approved of. But, as he arrived, she prayed to Thor, who threatened her father by striking a tree next to him with lightning. Unlike the Skírnismál, no messenger was sent and no consent was given, making this an unlawful bride abduction, and Thor protected His devotee.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pater patrias - imperial cult</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/meta/articles/pater-patrias_imperial-cult/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/meta/articles/pater-patrias_imperial-cult/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/GraniRau/status/1343783199445569538&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;divine-emperor&#34;&gt;Divine Emperor&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Coin commemorating the consecratio of Antoninus Pius by Marcus Aurelius and Lucius Verus.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;DIVUS ANTONINUS, divine Antoninus. Consecration as a divus(divine) was not done with every emperor, and cult to deceased emperors was awarded by the Senate.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;DIVA FAUSTINA. CONSECRATIO. This coin is for Antoninus&amp;rsquo; wife Faustina. She died while he was reigning, and he pushed for her inclusion in the imperial cult.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The imperial cult is something that I think is important to understand for a pagan. The main point of contention for Romans was when and how an emperor was given these honors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
