<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;3 Special Methods of Mantra Yoga and Mantra Therapy on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/3_Special_Methods_of_Mantra_Yoga_and_Mantra_Therapy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;3 Special Methods of Mantra Yoga and Mantra Therapy on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/3_Special_Methods_of_Mantra_Yoga_and_Mantra_Therapy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>13 Mantra and Pranayama: The Yoga of the Sun and the Moon</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/3_Special_Methods_of_Mantra_Yoga_and_Mantra_Therapy/13_Mantra_and_Pranayama_The_Yoga_of_the_Sun_and_the_Moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/3_Special_Methods_of_Mantra_Yoga_and_Mantra_Therapy/13_Mantra_and_Pranayama_The_Yoga_of_the_Sun_and_the_Moon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pranayama and mantra naturally go together and work best in combination. Using a mantra along with pranayama unites the mind and prana, drawing our attention and awareness into the breathing process. It can turn pranayama into meditation, as well as bring energy, vitality and wakefulness into the repetition of the mantra. Uniting prana, our power of action, with the mind, our power of knowledge, integrates us back into the source of our being. Prana gives Shakti to the mantra and makes it alive and vibrating within our entire body.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 Tantra, Mantra, Chakras and Kundalini</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/3_Special_Methods_of_Mantra_Yoga_and_Mantra_Therapy/14_Tantra_Mantra_Chakras_and_Kundalini/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/3_Special_Methods_of_Mantra_Yoga_and_Mantra_Therapy/14_Tantra_Mantra_Chakras_and_Kundalini/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Traditional Tantric Yoga consists of the use of mantras, deities, rituals, and meditation for achieving all the goals of life, particularly the ultimate goal of liberation. Tantra recognizes that we live in a universe full of Divine powers that we can communicate with in order to improve our lives. While these forces are present for everyone, only those who know how to contact their energies can fully benefit by them. Tantra teaches us this art of cosmic communication through the language of mantra.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>15 Mantra Deity and the Chanting of Divine Names</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/3_Special_Methods_of_Mantra_Yoga_and_Mantra_Therapy/15_Mantra_Deity_and_the_Chanting_of_Divine_Names/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/3_Special_Methods_of_Mantra_Yoga_and_Mantra_Therapy/15_Mantra_Deity_and_the_Chanting_of_Divine_Names/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the primal sounds or bija mantras, probably the next most important are special &amp;ldquo;name mantras&amp;rdquo;. These consist of names, epithets, qualities or functions of the Divine in different forms, manifestations, or personalities. They are centered on one word, the name, which may have several syllables.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a tremendous power in the name, as we all know. In our ordinary communication, we use names in order to draw the attention of a person to us. If I know your name, for example, and call you by it you respond personally. If I address you by someone else&amp;rsquo;s name, you will not respond at all. The same is true of the Divine and higher consciousness. If we know the Divine names, we can commune more readily with the Divine being. Our minds revolve around various names. When we repeat such Divine Names, our minds and hearts become purified and we begin to see the Divine in others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>16 Ayurvedic Mantra Therapy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/3_Special_Methods_of_Mantra_Yoga_and_Mantra_Therapy/16_Ayurvedic_Mantra_Therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/3_Special_Methods_of_Mantra_Yoga_and_Mantra_Therapy/16_Ayurvedic_Mantra_Therapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mantra is one of the most important healing practices in Ayurvedic medicine. Mantra therapy is the main tool used in Ayurveda for healing the mind, but it can aid in physical healing as well. In fact, mantra has been called the most important healing therapy in Ayurveda as a whole. This is because mantra brings in both the cosmic powers and the soul of the patient into the healing process. Even if we are applying outer Ayurvedic treatment methods like diet, herbs, massage or Pancha Karma, mantra can be used to make these more effective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>17 Vedic Astrology Mantras</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/3_Special_Methods_of_Mantra_Yoga_and_Mantra_Therapy/17_Vedic_Astrology_Mantras/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/3_Special_Methods_of_Mantra_Yoga_and_Mantra_Therapy/17_Vedic_Astrology_Mantras/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vedic astrology is the main Vedic science connected to Mantra Yoga. There are two reasons for this. First, Vedic astrology provides us with the keys to choose mantras and correctly time their usage. Traditionally in India, mantras and even the names of children are chosen based upon astrological considerations. Second, mantras work on a subtle level that reflects the same forces as the planets and stars. While astrological positions are patterns of cosmic light, mantras are patterns of cosmic sound. Most mantras are astrological in nature or application, and all mantras can be looked at from an astrological angle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 Vastu and Directional Mantras</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/3_Special_Methods_of_Mantra_Yoga_and_Mantra_Therapy/18_Vastu_and_Directional_Mantras/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/3_Special_Methods_of_Mantra_Yoga_and_Mantra_Therapy/18_Vastu_and_Directional_Mantras/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mantra is not only connected to movement in time but also to location in space. The different directions of space convey various influences from nature, from other people, from technology, and from the greater universe that can be either helpful or harmful to us. We can use mantras to improve these &amp;ldquo;directional influences&amp;rdquo; in our lives that we otherwise have little protection against. There are universal directional influences, as well as those relative to the nature of the topography in which we live, and the orientation of our buildings, houses and rooms.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 Vedic and Vedantic Mantra Yoga</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/3_Special_Methods_of_Mantra_Yoga_and_Mantra_Therapy/19_Vedic_and_Vedantic_Mantra_Yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/3_Special_Methods_of_Mantra_Yoga_and_Mantra_Therapy/19_Vedic_and_Vedantic_Mantra_Yoga/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Vedas&lt;/em&gt; present the oldest form of the Sanskrit language, the language of mantra. As such, they present us with the oldest form of Mantra Yoga. Mantra Yoga is the oldest and most central of all the Yogas. Classical Yoga evolved out of the language of mantra, which is the language of the spiritually awakened mind that reveals the underlying unity of all existence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some scholars argue that there is no Yoga in the Vedas because the term Yoga is rare in Vedic texts and no Yoga asanas are described. However, they miss the obvious point: the Vedas represent a path of Mantra Yoga, including the use of Divine Names. Mantra, more so than asana, is an indicator of higher Yoga practices and Yoga in general.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
