<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;svastika on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/svastika/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;svastika on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/svastika/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hooked cross vs svastika</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/svastika/hooked-cross_vs_svastika/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/svastika/hooked-cross_vs_svastika/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ancient symbol that was hijacked by evil&lt;br&gt;&#xA;How an auspicious sacred sign was twisted to become the graphic embodiment of hate and intolerance. Kalpana Sunder explores the extraordinary history of a potent emblem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bbc.com/culture/article/20210816-the-ancient-symbol-that-was-hijacked-by-evil&#34;&gt;https://www.bbc.com/culture/article/20210816-the-ancient-symbol-that-was-hijacked-by-evil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The equilateral cross with legs bent at right angles – that looks like swirling arms or a pattern of L shapes – has been a holy symbol in Hinduism, Jainism and Buddhism for centuries. And, of course, the swastika (or the similar-looking hakenkreuz or hooked cross) is also a symbol of hate, embodying painful and traumatic memories of the Third Reich. The symbol of Nazism, it is associated with genocide and racial hatred after the atrocities of the Holocaust.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quartz article</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/svastika/quartz-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/svastika/quartz-article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How Nazis twisted the swastika, a symbol of the Buddha, into an emblem of hate&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this Thursday, Feb. 3, 2016 photo, visitors stand next to a religious ornament with the &amp;ldquo;manji&amp;rdquo; symbol, which comes from the ancient Sanskrit and is widely used for centuries to denote Buddhist temples on maps and elsewhere, at a temple in Tokyo. As Japan gears up to host the 2020 Tokyo Olympics and caters to a surging influx of foreign visitors, the country faces a cultural dilemma: Should it stop identifying Buddhist temples on maps with the traditional &amp;ldquo;manji&amp;rdquo; symbol that is often confused with a Nazi swastika? (AP Photo/Eugene Hoshiko)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>svastika history</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/svastika/svastika-history-bbc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/svastika/svastika-history-bbc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How the world loved the swastika - until Hitler stole it&lt;br&gt;&#xA;By Mukti Jain Campion&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Kiev&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Published&#xA;23 October 2014&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mukti Jain Campion is the producer and presenter of Reclaiming the Swastika on BBC Radio 4 at 11:00 on Friday 24 October - and on the BBC iPlayer for 30 days after broadcast.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Published&lt;br&gt;&#xA;14 March 2014&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the Western world the swastika is synonymous with fascism, but it goes back thousands of years and has been used as a symbol of good fortune in almost every culture in the world. As more evidence emerges of its long pre-Nazi history in Europe, can this ancient sign ever shake off its evil associations?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
