<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Boyce: Persian stronghold on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Boyce: Persian stronghold on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 THE VILLAGE OF THE TWO &#39;CATHEDRAL&#39; FIRES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/01_THE_VILLAGE_OF_THE_TWO_CATHEDRAL_FIRES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/01_THE_VILLAGE_OF_THE_TWO_CATHEDRAL_FIRES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;.-.-.&amp;mdash;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;YT-7-his,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;lsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Y1-&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;TITA&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is now generally agreed that the Arab conquest of Iran in the seventh century A.D. was not achieved by a few great battles, but took more than a generation to accomplish; and that, although Islam was established thereby as the state religion, it needed some three hundred years, or nine generations, for it to become the dominant faith throughout the land. During this time the Zoro astrians continued to look for leadership to their high priest, the Dastur dastūrān, hereditary successor to the prelate who in the days of the Sasanian Empire had been head of the established church. For two or three centuries after the conquest the Dastur dasturan continued to be a person of dignity and influence; but late in the ninth century the tide began to ebb swiftly for the Zoroastrians, with Islam now enjoying the full support of temporal power every where. It was then that the founding fathers of the Parsi community left their homeland to seek religious freedom in exile in India;&amp;rsquo; and thereafter those who held by their ancient faith in Iran were steadily ground down into the position of a small, deprived, and harassed minority, lacking all privileges or consideration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 THE WORSHIP OF OHRMAZD AND THE CREATIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/02_THE_WORSHIP_OF_OHRMAZD_AND_THE_CREATIONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/02_THE_WORSHIP_OF_OHRMAZD_AND_THE_CREATIONS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;سننننلننمتنعلنضنلننننننننننننننننننن&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ZOROASTER is the only founder of a great revealed religion who was a priest; and as such he clearly knew the value of observance, and therefore provided his followers with firm guidance for their devo tional lives. He himself, so the tradition says, was the author of the greatest of the Zoroastrian prayers, the Ahuna vairyo or Ahunvar, a brief utterance in honour of Ahura Mazda which is for the Zoro astrian what the Lord&amp;rsquo;s Prayer is for the Christian. It is the first prayer that is taught to a child. It is uttered at every act of worship, public or private, and because of its sanctity it can be used in all vicissitudes, and (if repeated a prescribed number of times) may at need replace all other devotions. Thus some of the older Sharifabadi women could not read and knew little Avestan by heart; and for certain religious exercises they made themselves rosaries on which they could tell the number of Ahunvars as they recited them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 SOME INDIVIDUAL RITES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/03_SOME_INDIVIDUAL_RITES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/03_SOME_INDIVIDUAL_RITES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOME INDIVIDUAL RITES OF PIETY AND CHARITY&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;IN one of the Rivayatst it is said that, if it were impossible, because of poverty, for anyone in a community to found a gahanbar, then all the faithful there should join together to celebrate what the writer calls a &amp;lsquo;gahāmbār-e toji&amp;rsquo;, to which each should contribute what he could. The literal meaning of tõjī is obscure, but the learned translator of the Rivayat sought to connect the word with one surviving in Persian as tõžī, used for a &amp;lsquo;schoolboys&amp;rsquo; picnic&amp;rsquo;, and with the verb tozīdan in the sense of &amp;rsquo;to gather, collect&amp;rsquo;. Communal celebrations of this kind among the Parsis were described by a European traveller in the eighteenth century; but in Iran by the twentieth century all celebrations during the six great seasonal festivals had come to be endowed, and the term &amp;lsquo;gahambar-e toji&amp;rsquo; was then applied there to what for the laity was a very similar observance, that is, an Afrinagan service, with distribution of lurk, or lurk and bread, dedicated either to Ohrmazd or to one of the lesser yazads, and performed at some other time of year as an individual act of piety and charity. Such an observance, which (unlike the seasonal gahambar ceremonies) could be carried out, if wished, after sunset, and in any &amp;lsquo;clean&amp;rsquo; place, might be performed only once, or become a regular institution. A gahambar-e toji was seldom endowed, however, and so a different verb was used in its respect: one &amp;lsquo;gave&amp;rsquo; a gahambar-e toji, whereas one &amp;lsquo;founded&amp;rsquo; a gahambar-e cakhra (in Dari gaambār-e čāra), that is, a true gaham bar which belonged to the cycle of the great six. Small ritual differences existed, moreover, in that the little rounds of bread for consecration belonged only to the major celebrations, while for the humbler gahambar-e toji large rounds were baked as for everyday use, these being easier to make and distribute, and by custom in Sharifabad a blood sacrifice was never made for a gahambar-e toji. The reasons for giving a gahambar-e toji were various. It might&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 SACRED FIRES AND EMPTY SHRINES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/04_SACRED_FIRES_AND_EMPTY_SHRINES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/04_SACRED_FIRES_AND_EMPTY_SHRINES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Down the centuries Zoroastrians have been called by those of other faiths &amp;lsquo;fire worshippers&amp;rsquo;, a name which thinking members of the community indignantly reject, saying that they worship only God. Fire, they declare, was appointed by Zoroaster simply as an object in whose presence men should pray, in order to fix their thoughts on righteousness—for fire, he taught, was the creation of Ardvahišt, the hypostasis of all that is right and just. To pray before fire is thus, they argue, no more than to pray before a crucifix or icon; and, living as they do among Moslems, they sometimes call fire a qibla, the thing, that is, which helps them to turn their thoughts towards God, as the qibla in a mosque helps the worshippers there to turn towards Mecca,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 THE LAWS AND RITES OF PURITY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/05_THE_LAWS_AND_RITES_OF_PURITY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/05_THE_LAWS_AND_RITES_OF_PURITY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WHETHER one is concerned with acts of worship, or holy places, or simply patterns of daily living, one is bound to become involved with one or other of the laws of purity, for these affect all areas of Zoroastrian life. The purity code of this ancient faith is a complex one, and some of its elements plainly go back to distant, pre Zoroastrian times. These elements were developed and refined upon in the light of the prophet&amp;rsquo;s dualistic teachings, and new ones were added. The resulting code was of immense importance to the ortho dox, for they held that there was a threefold path to God, through acts of worship, observance of the purity laws, and ethical behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 DEATH AND THE MYSTERIES OF THE DOG</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/06_DEATH_AND_THE_MYSTERIES_OF_THE_DOG/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/06_DEATH_AND_THE_MYSTERIES_OF_THE_DOG/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;WHEN death comes, Zoroastrians have two pressing duties: to dispose of the polluting corpse with care and celerity, according to strict rules, and to do everything possible to help the disembodied soul to reach heaven and be blessed. The first duty should be fulfilled within a day, the second should last at least thirty years&amp;ndash;a contrast which marks the difference in value between dead body and living soul, the one belonging to Ahriman, the other to Ohrmazd. Both sets of rites, of the one day and the many years, include immensely ancient elements representing different historic layers of belief. Some of the beliefs themselves were discarded millennia ago, but the observances have long outlasted them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 THE SPRING NEW YEAR</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/07_THE_SPRING_NEW_YEAR/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/07_THE_SPRING_NEW_YEAR/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE SPRING NEW YEAR AND THE HUNDREDTH-DAY FEAST&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ancient Iranian calendar, observed, it seems, by Zoroastrians till the downfall of the Parthians, had twelve months of thirty days each, and accordingly slipped back steadily against the natural year, being the shorter by over five days. It was kept in accord with it, however, by the frequent insertion about once every six years, of a thirteenth month. This calendar was reformed under the first Sasanian king by the addition on the model of the Egyptian calendar) of five days set at the end of the year. These five days were piously named by the reformers the Gāthā (Gāh) days after the five groups of Zoroaster&amp;rsquo;s hymns. The 365-day year was too close to the natural one to make the traditional intercalation of a month any longer a practical measure, since it now took 120 years to amass thirty days from the quarter-days disregarded annually.2 Accordingly, the new calendar was left to recede slowly against the solar year, and the Zoroastrian holy days, which with their symbolism are closely linked with the seasons, became gradually divorced from them. Two attempts were made to correct this state of affairs, one during the late Sasapian period and one again in about A.D. 1006; but both had only a temporary effect. By 1964 the religious New Year, No Ruz, had again receded so far that it was being celebrated in high summer, with 1 Farvardin coinciding with 31 July in the Gregorian calendar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 SOME RITES OF EXPIATION</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/08_SOME_RITES_OF_EXPIATION/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/08_SOME_RITES_OF_EXPIATION/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SOME RITES OF EXPIATION OR COMFORT FOR THE LIVING AND THE DEAD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The words of their ancient holy texts were a source of immense comfort and strength to the Zoroastrians, who believed unquestion ingly that these had all been directly revealed by God to their prophet. They had faith that by uttering verses from them they could procure divine aid and blessings, and it was usual to say a prayer before embarking on any enterprise, whether this was sowing the new season&amp;rsquo;s crops or setting off on a bus journey to Yazd. (The Ahunvar was most often recited.) Moreover, the power of the words, they held, could be increased by appropriate actions, and there were accordingly a number of individual rites which were regularly performed to obtain grace or help in this life, or to benefit the departed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 FESTIVALS OF ALL SOULS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/09_FESTIVALS_OF_ALL_SOULS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/09_FESTIVALS_OF_ALL_SOULS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE FESTIVALS OF ALL SOULS AND THE RELIGIOUS NEW YEAR&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;UNTIL the beginning of the Sasanian era the ancient festival of All Souls, Hamaspathmaedaya, was evidently celebrated on the last night of the twelfth month, directly after the day&amp;rsquo;s celebration of the sixth gahambar. The spirits of the dead were entertained as honoured guests in their old homes throughout the hours of dark ness, and were then bidden a formal, ritual farewell at the dawn of the new year. This pattern of observance, going back in all probability to at least Indo-Iranian times, was broken by the third-century reform, whereby five extra days were introduced after the twelfth month, Spendarmad, to create a 365-day calendar. Since the fravašis, welcomed back to earth on 30 Spendarmad, could not, according to ancient custom, depart before the dawn of 1 Farvardin, New Year&amp;rsquo;s day, this measure created deep bewilderment and dis tress; and its working was interpreted to mean that these invisible guests must now be ministered to for the five &amp;lsquo;Gatha&amp;rsquo; days as well. Moreover, in the first year of the reform the bulk of the population evidently ignored these newly introduced (or, as they called them, &amp;lsquo;stolen&amp;rsquo;) days, and made their own private calculations as usual, reckoning, that is, the first &amp;lsquo;Gatha&amp;rsquo; day as I Farvardin. The result was that by the end of that year they were already five days behind the new official calendar when the &amp;lsquo;Gatha&amp;rsquo; days were reached. Since, clearly, they were not allowed to celebrate No Ruz till the king permitted, they were forced to entertain the fravašis for a night and the ten days which then elapsed between their 30 Spendarmad and the official i Farvardin. Thereafter the worst of the confusion was over and a single calendar was observed, with everyone, perforce, recognizing the same day as i Farvardin, and acknowledging the existence, however suspect in origin, of the five new days; but plainly the reform, though it had thus, through the power of the throne, become fact, was neither widely understood nor willingly&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 INITIATIONS AND PILGRIMAGES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/10_INITIATIONS_AND_PILGRIMAGES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/10_INITIATIONS_AND_PILGRIMAGES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ACCORDING to the Avesta, initiation into the Zoroastrian community, with full responsibility for one&amp;rsquo;s own religious and moral life, should take place at fifteen years of age (which in ancient Iran was regarded as the time of maturity). Among the Parsis this had been reduced to seven or eight, much as the age of confirmation has been reduced in some Christian communities, but the Irani villagers usually initiated their children at between twelve and fifteen years. In the old illiterate days a boy would prepare for the rite by going to the family priest to be taught by word of mouth the essential prayers —the Ahunvar and Ašəm vohu, the košti-prayers and the Sroš Baj. By the 1960s, with schools in every village and so few priests, it was the school teachers who made sure that the boys learnt these prayers from the Khorda Avesta (of which copies, printed in Bombay or Tehran, were readily to be had); and since it was they who had the trouble, it was usually they too who performed the simple ceremony, and received gifts in recompense from the family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
