<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>phantom-justice</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/articles/MT/phantom-justice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/articles/MT/phantom-justice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1643809437746905089.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Andronovo-derived technology, ghosts &amp;amp;justice by phantoms in a didactic account of the Zhou age by old chIna philosopher Mozi.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We would posit that the successful overthrow of the Shang by the Zhou was due to late Andronovo military connections.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If an example is to be given that shows a ghost seen by many and heard by many, then the story of Du Bo is one. The King Xuan of Zhou killed his subject Du Bo unjustly. Du Bo said,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rational-belief-poles</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/articles/MT/rational-belief-poles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/chInaH/articles/MT/rational-belief-poles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Confucian &amp;ldquo;rationalist&amp;rdquo; is bumped off by a wraith &amp;ndash; a suggestive tale with a protective effect of a black cow. This gives us a glimpse of the chIna pendulum swinging between the &amp;ldquo;ultra-rational&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; believing poles even in the past, with Maoism as a recapitulation of the former.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zong Dai was the Inspector of the Commandery of Qingzhou. He abolished the excessive cults and wrote a fine treatise on the non-existence of ghosts, which no one could refute. One day a scholar wearing a grey headcloth and carrying a name card came to visit Dai. They discussed various issues and when they began to talk about the non-existence of ghosts, the scholar shook his robe and left, saying, “You have terminated our blood offering for twenty some years, but since you had a black cow and a bearded servant, we could not bother you. Now your servant has abandoned you and the cow is dead, today we are able to get the better of you.&amp;quot; As soon as he finished speaking, he disappeared. Dai died the next day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
