<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;06 Rites and Techniques on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;06 Rites and Techniques on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>22 Worship of the Ladies of the Dipper</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/22_Worship_of_the_Ladies_of_the_Dipper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/22_Worship_of_the_Ladies_of_the_Dipper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Charles D. Orzech and James H. Sanford&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Pole Star and the seven stars of the Great or Northern Dipper occupy a  prominent place in Chinese imperial and Daoist traditions, and have microcosmic  and macrocosmic associations on both the astronomical and the human scales. It  was widely believed that the stars and constellations of &amp;ldquo;heaven&amp;rdquo; (tian) had ana&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;logues in the &amp;ldquo;under-heaven&amp;rdquo; (tianxia) and within the human body, and that  events and conditions in one of these systems affected the analogous structures  in the other systems. Thus, heaven was the model for earth, and the heavenly  bureaucracy the model for the earthly empire. So too, the human body was con&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 The Great Wisdom Mother and the Good Tradition</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/23_The_Great_Wisdom_Mother_and_the_Good_Tradition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/23_The_Great_Wisdom_Mother_and_the_Good_Tradition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Giacomella Orofino&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The tradition of Bdud kyi good yul (literally, &amp;ldquo;the demon as the object that is to  be cut off) is a medieval Buddhist practice developed in Tibet in the eleventh  century. Becoming widespread soon after the so-called period of the &amp;ldquo;new trans lations&amp;rdquo; of the Indian Buddhist Tantras in Tibetan, it was developed directly in  Tibetan rather than imported from India and translated from Sanskrit. It is a  syncretic movement that marks the confluence of Indian Tantric Buddhist and  pre-Buddhist Tibetan elements that are clearly shamanic in nature, which together  gave rise to a religious phenomenon with an identity of its own. It is based on a  complex literature that incorporated texts on dance, chanting, ritual music, the  nature of mystic hallucinations and visions, geomancy, exorcism, curing plagues,  and funeral rites. The basic principle of the practice involves annihilating the ego  by severing or &amp;ldquo;cutting off demons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 Worship of Bell-Ears the Great Hero, a Jain Tantric Deity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/24_Worship_of_Bell-Ears_the_Great_Hero_a_Jain_Tantric_Deity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/24_Worship_of_Bell-Ears_the_Great_Hero_a_Jain_Tantric_Deity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;John E. Cort&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tantra in Jainism has two distinctive features: it is largely centered around the  use of verbal spells or mantra, and Jain Tantric practices are aimed at improving  one&amp;rsquo;s condition within the realm of rebirth rather than liberating one from rebirth.  Although Jain Tantric rites, such as that given in the second text below, also  involve the use of diagrams known as yantras, these play a subsidiary role com&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>25 Secret Yantras and Erotic Display for Hindu Temples</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/25_Secret_Yantras_and_Erotic_Display_for_Hindu_Temples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/25_Secret_Yantras_and_Erotic_Display_for_Hindu_Temples/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Michael D. Rabe&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Silpa Prakasa is the only surviving text on Hindu architecture that was written  from an explictly Tantric perspective. Its author, Ramacandra, was an architect  who belonged to a community of Kaula brahmans residing in the Mahanadi delta  of Orissa. Composed during the reign of an obscure local raja, the text&amp;rsquo;s date can  be approximated by the fact that its prescriptions are best exemplifed by one  particular temple. That is the Varahi temple at Chaurasi, located midway between  the great temple towns of Bhuvaneshvar and Puri, and assigned on stylistic  grounds to the early eleventh century.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 The Six Rites of Magic</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/26_The_Six_Rites_of_Magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/26_The_Six_Rites_of_Magic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gudrun Buhnemann&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;References to magical practices are found throughout ancient Indian literature,  especially the Atharva Veda. Rites of magic are a common topic in Tantric texts,  where we often encounter them in a group called the &amp;ldquo;six rites.&amp;rdquo; This group  represents a systematization of magical practices. Although elements of folk tra&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ditions are certainly present, the dependence on brahmanical rituals is clearly  evident.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mantramahodadhi (Great Ocean of Mantras), a Sanskrit text that prescribes  the mantras of different deities and ritual practices connected with them, was  composed by Mahidhara at Varanasi, in 1588. Mahidhara wrote the work with  the intention of gathering all significant information on the topic in a single book.  Because of the clarity of its presentation, the Mantramahodadhi - along with the  Nauka (The Boat), the author&amp;rsquo;s commentary written to enable practitioners to  cross the &amp;ldquo;Great Ocean of Mantras&amp;rdquo; - has enjoyed great popularity in all parts of  India up to the present day. Throughout the work, Mahidhara enumerates various  deities, the mantras of those deities, and the rites in which the mantras are em ployed and which may be performed, once the mantras have been mastered, for  the attainment of specific objectives. Among the rites are those usually classified  as &amp;ldquo;the six rites&amp;rdquo; (satkarmani).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 The Worship of Kali According to the Todala Tantra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/27_The_Worship_of_Kali_According_to_the_Todala_Tantra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/27_The_Worship_of_Kali_According_to_the_Todala_Tantra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sanjukta Gupta&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To many Hindu Bengalis, Kali is the most important divinity. Identified with the  great Goddess, Devi Bhagavati, she subsumes all other goddesses. She is held to  be equal in status to Durga and their annual festivals, which occur close to each  other, are celebrated with the greatest grandeur: feasts are held, gifts are ex&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;changed, and new clothes are worn in honor of the Goddess. Both Durga and  Kali, facets of the same supreme Goddess, are fierce and aggressive. The Goddess  is the embodiment of the divine power, potency, and dynamism. After the great  dissolution of the worlds she regenerates the creation and sustains it until the  time arrives when she must withdraw it into herself. She possesses both negative  and positive elements in her divine personality. She is the nurturing Mother of  created beings as well as the sovereign cosmic ruler who maintains cosmic law  and order through her invincible power and irresistible energy. She punishes the  evil and rewards the righteous. Above all, she protects all her creatures and is  especially kind and sweet to her loyal devotees, like an indulgent mother to her  devoted children.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 Ritual Manual for the Protective Fire Offering Devoted to Manjusri, Chuin Lineage</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/28_Ritual_Manual_for_the_Protective_Fire_Offering_Devoted_to_Manjusri_Chuin_Lineage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/28_Ritual_Manual_for_the_Protective_Fire_Offering_Devoted_to_Manjusri_Chuin_Lineage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Richard K. Payne&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every Tantric tradition has its own version of the homa, a votive ritual in which  offerings are made into a fire. In one form or another the homa is found from  Mongolia to Bali, from south India to Japan. The homa is also a link to the Vedic  ritual tradition and the broader Indo-European religious culture that includes  Iranian, Greek, and Roman ritual traditions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The homa ritual presented here is from the Shingon tradition of Japanese Bud dhism, specifically the Chuin lineage, which predominates in contemporary Ja pan. The Shingon tradition was established in the ninth century by Kukai, who  is also known by his posthumously awarded title &amp;ldquo;Kobo Daishi&amp;rdquo; and is sometimes  simply referred to as &amp;ldquo;the Daishi&amp;rdquo; meaning &amp;ldquo;the Great Teacher.&amp;rdquo; He traveled to  China (804 to 806) with the specific goal of initiation into the Buddhist Tantra,  and received authority for the dual lineage of the Mahavairocana and Tattvasam graha Sutras.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>29 The Purification of the Body</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/29_The_Purification_of_the_Body/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/06_Rites_and_Techniques/29_The_Purification_of_the_Body/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gavin Flood&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Tantric tradition&amp;rsquo;s most elaborated source for the purification of the body  and its ritual identification with the cosmos is the Jayakhya Samhita, one of the  three most important revealed texts of the Pancaratra, the tradition of Tantric  Vaisnavism, probably composed between the seventh and tenth centuries c.E.  The Pancaratra Samhitas are regarded by the tradition as revelation and are di&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;rectly parallel to the Saiva Tantras or Agamas, though these were not recognized  by the Pancaratrins. The status of the Sarhhitas within Vaisnavism as a whole is  ambiguous, though an early Sri Vaisnava teacher, Yamuna, defended their status  as revelation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
