<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/amerindian/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/amerindian/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Red jacket&#39;s defence of natural religion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/amerindian/articles/red_jacket_1805_defence_of_native-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/amerindian/articles/red_jacket_1805_defence_of_native-religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Senecas, members of the Iroquois Confederacy, fought on the side of the British in the American Revolution. Red Jacket, also known as Sagoyewatha, was a chief and orator born in eastern New York; he derived his English name from his habit of wearing many red coats provided to him by his British allies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After the hostilities, as the British ceded their territories to the Americans, the Senecas and many other Indian peoples faced enormous pressure on their homelands. Red Jacket was a critical mediator in relations between the new U.S. government and the Senecas; he led a delegation that met with George Washington in 1792, when he received a peace medal that appeared in subsequent portraits of the Indian leader.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seattle speech 1854</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/amerindian/articles/chief-seattle-1854/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/amerindian/articles/chief-seattle-1854/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yonder sky that has wept tears of compassion upon my people for centuries untold, and which to us appears changeless and eternal, may change. Today is fair. Tomorrow it may be overcast with clouds. My words are like the stars that never change. Whatever Seattle says, the great chief at Washington can rely upon with as much certainty as he can upon the return of the sun or the seasons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>yanomami view of white folk Gods</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/amerindian/articles/yanomami-view_of_white-folk-Gods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/amerindian/articles/yanomami-view_of_white-folk-Gods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threader.app/thread/1435316974028984327&#34;&gt;https://threader.app/thread/1435316974028984327&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some remarkable passages from Davi Kopenawa’s book The Falling Sky, discussing the Gods of the white people’s ancestors, whom white people have forgotten, but of whom Kopenawa and other Yanomami spiritworkers are aware.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Do not think that the napënapëri images we make dance are those of the white people who are nearby around us. Those white people of the present only want our death.” “Today’s white people know nothing about the xapiri who inhabit their land and they never even think about them. Yet they always existed, long before the white people themselves were created. The spirits are truly numerous there!” “Even though today’s white people of Europe have forgotten it, the xapiri who live on their land are the images of their ancestors who died long ago. These are the images of the first outsiders with ghost talk whom the shamans call napënapëri.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
