<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;GA on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;GA on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BhAratIyatA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/bhAratIyatA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/bhAratIyatA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/i/lists/934873690050740224&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tragicomical to see ahistorical “sanātana dharma was all over the world once” narrative backfire, with some of these Western “Hindus” claiming that Hindudharma does not have a special link with Bhārata.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a problem that we have pointed out before. It horrifies some of these Western Hindus, to the very core of their being, that a “lowly Bhāratīya” can be their Ācārya or Dīkșāguru. The resources of the religion (scriptures, lore, icons, etc) are for us to generate but the leadership position is for them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Folk accommodation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/folk-accommodation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/folk-accommodation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bhadrakali-priest-swap&#34;&gt;bhadrakAlI priest swap&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An Ādiśaiva Brāhmaņa who served at a temple at Simhapuri mentioned to us about a Bhadrakālī temple his patriline is associated with.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On most days, she would receive worship in the Saiddhāntika fashion, being seen as the consort of Vīrabhadra, whose Tattva placement is between Prakrti and Guņa tattvas. Her liturgy is Samskrta and the praxis is Āgamika, an “Ārya” evolute ultimately rooted in Vaidika and Sāńkhya thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hindu claim on Arya contributions</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/hindu-claim_on_Arya-contributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/hindu-claim_on_Arya-contributions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/GhorAngirasa/status/1970076550105366808&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are achievements by non Arya peoples all over that are great.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Agreed with the point on Non-Ārya contributions but most importantly, lest people be confused, Ārya contributions are exclusively for Hindus to claim, celebrate and boast. The historical origins &amp;amp; evolutionary lineage are highly overrated in the question of legacy. The Ārya contribution to Dharma is a pan-Hindu legacy for Hindus to enjoy and suffers no claims from those who are merely “fellow IEs”—an identity that means nothing to the Āryas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Karma &amp; non-sympathy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/karma-non-sympathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/karma-non-sympathy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/GhorAngirasa/status/1817423939267879176&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a Hindu who believes in karma, do you believe whatever is happening to people is due to their own past karma? Then why feel sympathy towards the poor?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Not for an individual to make karmic computations. It could also be his karma to be put into distress &amp;amp; then either successfully saved by you or fail to be saved by you (but you nevertheless attempted) or saved from the distress but only partially. Not for you to know.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Master morality</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/master-morality/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/master-morality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This “zest for life, indifference towards inferiors &amp;amp; master morality=bedic essence” thinking is very common among edgelords these days. Partially motivated by the projection of their resentment towards current social welfare excesses on the Devas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These circumstances explain the vitriol of some towards a post on Bhīșma’s discourse that critiques the enjoyment of forced labour/indentured servitude on the grounds of compassion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, actual Rgveda: 10.25.11b:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;nīcā santam ud anayaḥ parāvṛjam prāndhaṃ śroṇaṃ śravayan sāsy ukthyaḥ ||&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mercy by punishment</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/mercy-by-punishment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/mercy-by-punishment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/GhorAngirasa/status/1925109619128733978&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A point that will discomfit many: Deva/Devī X is father/mother of all; how can she cause harm to me for reciting certain mantras without initiation? How can he/she punish me for this, whether now or at some point in the future?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A naive question. Yes, Īśvara/Īśvarī is always gracing all sentients at all times. But why do you conflate their grace (i.e. what is Good from their POV) with what is good from your POV (protection of physical body and mind from harm and subtle body from pāpaphala).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rationale</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/rationale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/rationale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Those who do the greatest damage to traditional positions are those who give scientism-laced nonsense to rationalise the traditional position. If you don’t know how to defend traditional positions, it’s better to not say anything at all.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Truth is; some traditional positions have a straightforward rationale whereas others do not. It’s often the case that traditional positions on outsiders may not have a rationale spelt out or fleshed out because they are addressed to insiders and it’s taken for granted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ritual bhakti match</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/ritual-bhakti-match/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/ritual-bhakti-match/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/GhorAngirasa/status/1919354622768296023&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s important to read history of one’s religion and be fully aware of the diverse forms of our religion &amp;amp; what they achieved.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rise-of-popular-cults&#34;&gt;Rise of popular cults&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’m no fan of Kabīr &amp;amp; the like (it’s not my cup of tea and there are far more satisfying forms of religion for me, personally). However, one has to be honest and ask himself what leads to the proliferation of such forms of religion, which are more focused on “feel-good”, “vibes” &amp;amp; “social justice”? Changes like this do not happen in a vacuum. They are reactions to profoundly dissatisfying transformations of traditional religion, due to the erosion &amp;amp; corrosion of the caliber of the traditional custodians.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Similarities &amp; Opposites</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/similarities_opposites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/similarities_opposites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/GhorAngirasa/status/1839515413518193129&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The more you read your own scriptures as well as those of other religions as a Hindu, the more you will realize that 95% of the memes in other religions, which are purportedly objects of ridicule, contention or disgust, will have some parallels in the vast ocean that is Hindu Dharma. You just haven’t heard of them. It’s the remaining 5% which forms the most crucial line of demarcation &amp;amp; are completely non-negotiable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Veda tantra continuity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/veda-tantra-continuity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/veda-tantra-continuity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/GhorAngirasa/status/1925872890492154056&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fact is, it is the Āgamika-Tāntrika religion that saved the Vaidika-Paurāņika religion.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Firstly, it supplemented the latter in the form of material incorporated into the Purāņas.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the developed methods in Tantrāgama have been incorporated into vaidika praxis (nyāsa, mudras, etc).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thirdly, when the Aupanișada Vidyās and Upāsanas had mostly died off due to broken transmission, it is the Upāsanakrama of the Tantrāgama that was adopted by the Yatis of the different schools of Vedānta: Śrīvidyā by the Advaitīs, Pāñcarātra by the Vaișņavas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Way of life vs religion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/way-of-life_vs_religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/GA/way-of-life_vs_religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thread by @GhorAngirasa on Thread Reader App – Thread Reader App&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1236131126462148608.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;confusion&#34;&gt;Confusion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hinduism is not a religion; it is a “lifestyle thingy”—&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;why do Hindus keep repeating such meaningless &amp;amp; mediocre platitudes?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One observes a tendency to see “religion” as a negative term while “way of life” is something very exalted &amp;amp; noble.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ways-of-life&#34;&gt;Ways of life&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is nonsense. All religions are ways of living. Sullam is very much a complete way of life, having prescriptions going from the bathroom &amp;amp; bedroom to politics &amp;amp; taxation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
