<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;MT on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;MT on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Abaris</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/articles/MT/abaris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/articles/MT/abaris/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1574234674469081088&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Abaris son of Seuthes is a likely non-Zoroastrian, Iranic ritualist operating among the yavana-s. We could see him as an Iranic &amp;ldquo;pAshupata&amp;rdquo;-like figure. He is said to have composed several works titled the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Scythian oracles;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The marriage of river Hebrus;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Purificatory rites&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A prose theogony;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Apollo&amp;rsquo;s coming to the Hyperboreans.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;He is said to have been a contemporary of Pythagoras &amp;amp; the yavana-s record him as the author of numerous incantations, especially for medical use. He is said to have established a temple to a godddess at Sparta that the yavana-s identified with the awful Persephone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Armenian trimUrti</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/articles/MT/Armenian-trimUrti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/articles/MT/Armenian-trimUrti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In late antiquity many IE groups (India, Iran, Armenia, Germania, Rome to degree) converged to a triad (trimUrti) of &amp;ldquo;primary&amp;rdquo; deities. The Armenian one is given as Aramazd, Anahit, and Vahagn. It is not identical to the Iranic one despite the Iranic origin of the names. It seems the Iranic names were superimposed onto the original Armenian ones. Thus, it may indeed be correct to assume that behind vahagn was the original Armenia indra-class deity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kafIristAni-incantation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/articles/MT/kafIristAni-incantation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/articles/MT/kafIristAni-incantation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A “Kafiristani” incantation recorded via Morgenstierne:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;imro&lt;/em&gt;! delect machi mrhor o! o &lt;em&gt;bagiShT&lt;/em&gt; o!&lt;br&gt;&#xA;imro of the gods (delect ~ devaloka or godly realm) and of mortals the lord o! (c.f. devAnAm uta yo martyAnAM yajiShThaH); o the god baghiShT o!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The o in the incantation is likely a denasalized OM cognate.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The deity imro is the cognate of yamo rajan; The deity baghiShT seems to be a superlative formation from the same root as the I-Ir deity bhaga, who once enjoyed a popular Iranic cult. Comes in names like bhagadatta; baghdAd on both sides of the divide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>kalkin</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/articles/MT/kalkin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/articles/MT/kalkin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/blog_supplement/status/1710169100482162920&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The middle Iranian text AyAdgAr I zAmAspIg or zAmAsp nAmag presents an interesting Iranian apocalypse paralleling the coming of kalkin. Parallel to the H scenario, it presents events leading to the coming of the saoshyant when the Arabs, Turks &amp;amp; &amp;ldquo;Romans&amp;rdquo; will be overthrown.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It also posits a cosmic conflict between mithra and aeshma daeva paralleling that of ahura mazdha and angra mainyu. In the former battle a certain demon know as vadag-jav-kAr will join on the side of aeshma daeva. His name means maker of bad grain. It seems to be a late surviving Iranian memory of the dAnava kuyava slain by indra in the H tradition:&#xA;shuShNam pipruM kuyavaM vR^itram indra yadAvadhIr vi puraH shambarasya |&#xA;as you O indra, slew shuShNa, kuyava, vR^itra and rent the forts of shambara.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
