<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Shinto on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/shinto/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Shinto on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/shinto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>kAmi</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/shinto/kAmi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/shinto/kAmi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;general-intro&#34;&gt;General intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://refractory.unimelb.edu.au/2004/02/03/wonderment-and-awe-the-way-of-the-kami-lucy-wright/&#34;&gt;LW&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;relation to buddhism &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nippon.com/en/in-depth/a02902/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;kami-as-the-base-entities&#34;&gt;kAmi as the base entities&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yoshida Kanetomo&amp;rsquo;s formulation of Shinto in the 14-1500s has a touch of brilliance such that he can be called Japan&amp;rsquo;s Astika. He developed the idea that the buddha-s and the bodhisattva-s are not the original entities but they are merely manifestation of the kami who are the original divine entities. He also made the case that bauddha and Confucianism are merely second hand versions of Shinto with the kami as the primary pantheon being secondarily interpreted as nAstika buddha-s of chIna deities.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rites</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/shinto/rites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/shinto/rites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;adoring-deities-and-spiritis&#34;&gt;Adoring deities and spiritis&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;goma / homa&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;to vaishravaNa, in front of an image of marIchi, by kAgeTora/ Uesugi Kenshin a daimyo of the Sengoku (Heaven and Earth 天と地と) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n4AV_Gv_59k&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34;&gt;YT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QrriW9gFXsk&#34;&gt;YT_open&lt;/a&gt; (identification by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/yenkak/status/630249442613051392&#34;&gt;MT&lt;/a&gt;), also a devotee of vaishravaNa.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;shiNTo adaptation - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ooEKLqlT7ss&#34;&gt;YT&lt;/a&gt;. This was probably by Yoshida Kanetomo as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Offering hair - kAgeTora &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/n4AV_Gv_59k?list=WL&amp;amp;t=4526&#34;&gt;YT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Adoring the spirits of the dead&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;TakeDa &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/n4AV_Gv_59k?list=WL&amp;amp;t=3962&#34;&gt;YT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;battle&#34;&gt;Battle&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;raNa-dIxA&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;kAgeTora &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=n4AV_Gv_59k&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&amp;amp;list=WL&amp;amp;t=3776&#34;&gt;YT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;By Tea &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/zlnQO_rRRcI?list=WL&amp;amp;t=1367&#34;&gt;YT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chanting in battle - kAgeTora &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/n4AV_Gv_59k?list=WL&amp;amp;t=4854&#34;&gt;YT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;manufacturing-and-business&#34;&gt;Manufacturing and business&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rituals to keep up team spirit: Train cleaners &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rFXi1cM9vO0&#34;&gt;YT1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Factory drill in 1970-s - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PpiWx5_J6Dg&#34;&gt;YT&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In business coprorations - &lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgsafe.org/4e43f4a34d.jpg&#34;&gt;IMG&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Adoration of dead employees. &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/tG6tgTMzXGY?t=671&#34;&gt;YT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Rjrasva/status/854401802720169987&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sumo (very clear Shinto roots, all wrestlers including foreigners have to participate in shrine visits &amp;amp; rituals), agriculture (believed to be taught by kami to Japanese &amp;amp; hence ritually reenacted such as @ Sumiyoshi shrine), timekeeping (assoc with Omi jingu shrine, big clock companies like Casio &amp;amp; Seiko dedicated their clocks there), sword making (just watch any Samurai sword makers documentary, u will see the Shinto rituals to be performed), Traditional soy sauce &amp;amp; sake breweries both have rituals for the kami.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ōmiwa Shrine in Nara is one of Japan&amp;rsquo;s oldest extant Shinto shrines. It is a tutelary shrine of the Japanese alcohol producers. Most well-known alcohol producer families are in Nara and these families have a centuries-old tradition of producing alcohol.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Alcohol makers in general (including foreign drinks like whiskey) &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/t2239dShr6&#34;&gt;https://t.co/t2239dShr6&lt;/a&gt; Shinkansen &amp;amp; the rail companies building them also have kamidana in their offices. Many big Japanese corps r associated with specific shrines whether it be due to the given kami being known for its connection with the industry the company is involved in or because the founder of the corp was big devotee (e.g. Sazo Idemitsu the founder of Idemitsu was a worshiper at Munakata shrine &amp;amp; made big contributions to its renovation)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce making - &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zF8GfajCtgM&#34;&gt;The Kikkoman Creed&lt;/a&gt; tells the story of the rich heritage and family creed that shaped Kikkoman for over 300 years.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In the case of Toshiba, there is an Izumo Shrine in the main office&amp;hellip; The guardian deity of Tokyo Security Exchange in Nihonbashi, Tokyo, is enshrined in the Kabuto Shrine&amp;hellip; there is the Munakata Shrine of Idemitsu Enterprise, the Seiko Shrine of Shiseido, the Kotohira Shrine.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;The Mitsui Group is another example. While its guardian deity is enshrined in the Mitsui Shrine, its annual festival is carried out on a grand scale in the various offices of the company&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In a third pattern, the kami worshiped at the company shrines have a special relationship to the kind of work done&amp;hellip; But perhaps the most interesting example is the Toyota Motor Co. in Toyota city near Nagoya, which has had its own shrine-the Hoko shrine&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;agriculture&#34;&gt;Agriculture&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Even cherry blossom viewing has its roots in (by now u should be able to guess): hanami, or cherry blossom viewing, is said to have grown out of farmers’ seasonal offerings of food and sake to tanokami, the god of the rice paddy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot; Iwami Kagura - a regional traditional performing art at shrines thanking and praying for good harvest and health, which is actually the origin of the famous Kabuki performances&amp;quot;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;My name is Uriyasu Noejima. I am the 5th generation owner of Uejima Souroku-en. My tea company has been around for 180 years&amp;hellip; I always offer the first harvest of tea (Ichibancha) to our guardian god whose shrine is close to my house&amp;rdquo; - vimeo.com/351637940&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;science&#34;&gt;Science&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Space launches - &lt;a href=&#34;https://pmm.nasa.gov/image-gallery/jaxa-three-shrine-pilgrimage-ceremony&#34;&gt;NASA1&lt;/a&gt;, IMG. &amp;ldquo;on the occasion of its launching, three scientists pAirf a visit to Chichibu Shrine in Saitama Prefecture to pray for the success of the launch. From ancient times Chichibu Shrine has been known as Myoken-sama (the shrine in honor of the god of the stars&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shrines</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/shinto/shrines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/shinto/shrines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oft in the midst of nature&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Intro: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nippon.com/en/views/b05201/&#34;&gt;N16&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vids: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BfI8RVjSQmw&#34;&gt;YT1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RyVA7ywKTr8&#34;&gt;YT2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;shintai---body-of-kami-venerated-in-shrines&#34;&gt;shinTAi - body of kAmi, venerated in shrines&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;sacred objects hidden in honden&amp;rsquo;s core, never displayed. The outer space of the honden, where priests perform their duties, is called the gejin.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;typically mirrors, magatama (comma-shaped stones), or swords.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;sacred trees and forests - &amp;lsquo;himorobi&amp;rsquo; is used in reference to sacred forests or conspicuously large, old trees venerated as shinboku (sacred trees).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
