<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;1 Observation on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/bases/1_observation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;1 Observation on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/bases/1_observation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Omniscience / sarvajJNatA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/bases/1_observation/omniscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/bases/1_observation/omniscience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;pratyabhijjna-opinion&#34;&gt;pratyabhijJNA opinion&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BhAskarI (BhAskara&amp;rsquo;s commentary on AbhinavaguptAcArya&amp;rsquo;s vimarSinI) on yogi-s and their powers -&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;एतेन योगिनां सदा सर्वविषयं प्रतिविषयं च ज्ञानं वर्तत इति भ्रमोऽपि निरस्त एव ज्ञातव्यः, देहोपाधिं तावत्तदसम्भवात् । - - - दिदृक्षाविषयीकृतेषु बहुषु वस्तुषु यादृशी सूक्ष्मस्पर्शमात्ररूपा व्याप्तिर्भवति तादृश्येव योगिनः सर्वविषयत्वेनोक्ता, न तु त्वदभिमता, ययासौ योगी महातृष्णाग्रस्तस्य तव समस्तदेशकालगतान् भावान् कथयेद्येन त्वदभिमतसिद्धिः स्यात् ।&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This puts to naught your delusion that yogi-s can have the knowledge of all things of all times, always. As long as they are embodied, they can never have such knowledge. - - - About the things (of the past and future) you wish to see, the yogi-s have a subtle knowledge (knowledge that everything that seems separated from the Consciousness is what is projected by the latter outside itself), not the sort of knowledge that you would want. They cannot tell you about phenomena pertaining to all times and all places, so you can benefit by gaining such information and fulfill your insatiable desires&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>प्रत्यक्षम् Direct witness</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/bases/1_observation/pratyaxa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/bases/1_observation/pratyaxa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;प्रत्यक्ष is given high regard, even with regard to subjective experience. As is said:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;‘‘न हि दृष्टे ऽनुपपन्नं नाम’’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The pratyaxa of one person is always of questionable utility to another - Depends on the reliability and relatability of the experiencer vis-a-vis the other.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;biology&#34;&gt;Biology&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Lessons from biology are very important for superior understanding of a lot of issues in human society (ranging from mate selection, family dynamics, social structure, child rearing, memetic epidemics like Abe&amp;rsquo;s diseases, sexual orientation, police brutality, violence, carnivorism etc..). Indeed, in our past we see savants like viShNusharman and vyAsa teach us nIti with reference to animal behavior. One of the reasons why natural religions like ours are superior to counter religions like buddhism, Abe&amp;rsquo;s diseases and their successors like SJWism and communism stems from the fact that they are better adapted to our true &amp;ldquo;nature&amp;rdquo; (which is largely grounded in biology). The mAnasatarangiNIkAra is a rare savant who sees this clearly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
