<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Padoux - mantras on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Padoux - mantras on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>0</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To the memory of Harvey P. Alper who conceived and edited &lt;em&gt;Understanding Mantras&lt;/em&gt;, the only overview of the subject of mantras.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;brahma vai vāc.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Aitareya Brahmana&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;OṂ&lt;/em&gt;, that syllable truly is &lt;em&gt;Brahman&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That syllable indeed is the Supreme. …&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Knowing that syllable, indeed whatever one desires, is his.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Katha Upaniṣad&lt;/em&gt; 2.16)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The vast majority of those mantras are nonsense syllables such as Hring, Hung, Hum, Phat, sparks from the blazing furnace of aboriginal superstition whence the system arose, or from the equally superstitious stores laid up in the Atharvaveda.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/1_Introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/1_Introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The medium is the message.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Marshall McLuhan)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;donner un sens plus pur aux mots de la tribu.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(Stéphane Mallarmé)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why study Tantric mantras? One may well ask. Why Tantra? Why mantras? The answer is that Tantra, the Tantric phenomenon, is not, as was first believed, a limited and bizarre form of Hinduism (or Buddhism) but a fundamental aspect of the Indian religious world. It has pervaded the near totality of Hinduism (and of part of Mahayāna Buddhism) since, perhaps, the fifth or sixth centuries: religion, ritual, theology and metaphysics, iconography and temple building, even the structure of the state, in India and in part of Asia, would not have been the same without Tantra. The first ‘non-human’, purely verbal, theoretically eternal, self-proclaimed revelation of the Veda, the &lt;em&gt;śruti&lt;/em&gt; (‘what was heard’, the Vedic revelation being oral), which goes from the Veda to the Upaniṣads and so forth, and is followed by Veda-based texts (the &lt;em&gt;smr̥ti&lt;/em&gt;), has in some respect always had the pride of place: it forms the basic orthodox socio-religious teaching of Hindu society. Another, scriptural, revelation, that of the Tantras (texts deemed to have been revealed by deities), came later on and progressively pervaded most of the Hindu world. It did not so much reject the other revelation as depreciate it, considering it to be of merely social value and unable to offer the same access to liberation or other rewards as the esoteric Tantric teaching.1 And it progressively permeated and often transformed the orthodox Hindu world. One may say without exaggeration that since at least a thousand years Hinduism has been very largely Tantric or ‘tantricised’, not Vedic. The Tantric revelation cannot therefore be treated as secondary. Even though many of its texts, scriptures and exegetical works are arcane and obscure, the presence of the notions and practices it brought forth, together with its vision of the world, is to be felt everywhere in Hinduism – possibly also because most of these notions and practices have deep roots in the Indian soil.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 Mantroddhāra and mantravicāra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/2_mantroddhAra_and_mantravichAra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/2_mantroddhAra_and_mantravichAra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The extraction and examination of mantras&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The use of mantras being prescribed in different circumstances (in ritual, magic, yoga, or spiritual and meditative practices) are quoted, revealed or prescribed in different ways. In ritual, and especially in the course of the mandatory daily worship of a deity, but also in many other rites, such as &lt;em&gt;dīkṣā, pratiṣṭhā, pavitrārohana&lt;/em&gt; and so forth, their utterance at various moments of the ritual performance is prescribed by Tantras and other Tantric texts, or in compilations (&lt;em&gt;nibandhas&lt;/em&gt;) or manuals (&lt;em&gt;paddhati&lt;/em&gt;s) of ritual. The only condition for their use is that they are uttered exactly and as prescribed, by a socially and ritually authorised person. Such has been the case from Vedic times down to the present. It is, one may say, the normal, ordinary form in which the utterance of these constituent elements of all rites is prescribed, the form most often met with. It is, however, not the most characteristically Tantric and most interesting one. More interesting, and typically Tantric, is another way, first of quoting or revealing a mantra, then of examining and selecting it so as to be sure it is well adapted to its user and to the end pursued. This method is used whenever the mantra – which is the phonic, efficacious form of a deity and is therefore not to be revealed to inapt or uninitiated persons – is to be communicated to an adept or devotee. This form of revelation or secret (ritual or non-ritual) communication of a mantra is what is called &lt;em&gt;mantroddhāra&lt;/em&gt;, whereas the method for examining and adapting a mantra is called &lt;em&gt;mantravicāra&lt;/em&gt;, two practices some forms of which we shall see presently.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Japa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/3_Japa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/3_Japa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before studying &lt;em&gt;japa&lt;/em&gt;, one must first see how this term is to be translated. In other words, what does it mean for us? An answer – if an answer is possible – must take into account the descriptions and definitions of &lt;em&gt;japa&lt;/em&gt; given in Sanskrit texts as well as the nature of the ritual or religious uses of &lt;em&gt;japa&lt;/em&gt;. But the uses and the definitions of &lt;em&gt;japa&lt;/em&gt; have varied according to traditions, and, still more, have evolved in the course of centuries. A unique and generally valid translation of the term would be possible only if there were a unique and generally admitted conception and practice of &lt;em&gt;japa&lt;/em&gt;, which is not the case. The only solution to our problem is thus not to translate the word whilst trying to show the various conceptions and practices of &lt;em&gt;japa&lt;/em&gt; which have existed (and still exist now) in India.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Nyāsa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/4_nyAsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/4_nyAsa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The ritual placing of mantras&lt;em&gt;1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In practice, mantras are nearly always used in the context of ritual, indispensable, as we have seen, to their extraction or selection, to their transmission, or to their efficacy in action. We intend here to inquire into one ritual practice, that of &lt;em&gt;nyāsa&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The word &lt;em&gt;nyāsa&lt;/em&gt; is formed from the prefix &lt;em&gt;ni&lt;/em&gt; (‘below’, ‘under’) and the verbal root &lt;em&gt;AS&lt;/em&gt; (‘to throw’, ‘to project’) – from which the verb &lt;em&gt;NYAS, nyāsati&lt;/em&gt;, to throw, to project, is derived along with the masculine substantive &lt;em&gt;nyāsa&lt;/em&gt;, translated in Monier-Williams &lt;em&gt;Sanskrit–English Dictionary&lt;/em&gt; as ‘putting down or in, placing, fixing, inserting, applying … drawing, painting, writing down … depositing, intrusting, delivering … mental appropriation or assignment of various parts of the body to tutelary deities’ – a diversity of definitions one also finds in the St Petersburg Dictionary: ‘niedersetzen, hinsetzen, aufsetzen … das Auftragen mysticher Zeichen auf verschiedene Teile des Körpers’. P.V. Kane (&lt;em&gt;History of Dharmaśāstra&lt;/em&gt;, vol. V.2, p. 1120) writes: ‘&lt;em&gt;nyāsa&lt;/em&gt; … means mentally invoking a god or gods, mantras and holy texts to come to occupy certain parts of the body in order to render the body a pure and fit receptacle for worship and meditation’. He adds a little further on: ‘The &lt;em&gt;Kulārṇava&lt;/em&gt; explains it as follows: “&lt;em&gt;nyāsa&lt;/em&gt; is so called because therein riches that are acquired in a righteous way are deposited or placed with persons, whereby all-round protection is got”’ (&lt;em&gt;nyayoparjitavittanām aṅgeṣu viniveśanāt/sarvarakṣakarād devi nyāsa ityabhidhīyate&lt;/em&gt;) (KT 18.56, p. 352).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 A Hindu rosary ritual</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/5_A_Hindu_rosary_ritual/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/5_A_Hindu_rosary_ritual/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Jayākhyasaṃhitā&lt;/em&gt;, chapter 14)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The use of a rosary or string of beads (&lt;em&gt;akṣamālā, akṣasūtra&lt;/em&gt;) as a means for keeping count of a repeated incantation or prayer is very usual in Hinduism as well as in Buddhism. Most of the texts concerning the ritual recitation of a mantra, &lt;em&gt;japa&lt;/em&gt;, that is – be they purāṇas, tantras or manuals of ritual – include passages on how to use a rosary, and how to assemble or to dispose of it. As is to be expected, such instructions are specially numerous and detailed in Tantric works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>6 Mantradoṣa and mantrasaṃskāra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/6_Mantradosa_and_mantrasaMskAra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/6_Mantradosa_and_mantrasaMskAra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On the defects and the perfecting of mantras&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we have seen, Tantric mantras are the phonic form of deities – deities as mantras or mantras as deities. They are in this respect divine entities existing eternally as aspects of the supreme Word (&lt;em&gt;vāc&lt;/em&gt;), or at least existing on a pure, perfect level of speech, free of all imperfections. But they are also conceived as limited entities, either as ‘souls’ (&lt;em&gt;aṇu&lt;/em&gt;), of different degrees of perfection, or as spiritual powers existing on different levels of the cosmos. Finally, in ritual practice, they are empirically existing forms of phonic utterance: they are quoted in ritual manuals, ritually, often audibly, uttered and heard, sometimes even written, partaking thus of the imperfection of the created world.2 This explains why they can suffer from flaws or defects, &lt;em&gt;doṣas&lt;/em&gt;, of which they must be freed so as to recover their pristine perfection and be able to be perfectly effective (or harmless for their user). Hence the existence of such ritual practices as &lt;em&gt;mantraśuddhi&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;mantrasaṃskāra.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>7 Mantric practices and the nature of mantric utterance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/7_Mantric_practices_and_the_nature_of_mantric_utte/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/7_Mantric_practices_and_the_nature_of_mantric_utte/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most ancient Tantric texts, and some more recent ones too, contain a mixture of sometimes very elaborate theological and metaphysical notions with a mystical and soteriological aim, together with a variety of magical speculations and practices, these two categories of notions and actions forming two very largely overlapping areas rather than two separate ones. A coincidence that should not surprise us since rites are governed by rules, that is, by theoretical notions which give them their meaning. The Tantric initiate for whose benefit such texts were composed, the &lt;em&gt;sādhaka&lt;/em&gt;, was normally not a &lt;em&gt;mumukṣu&lt;/em&gt;, a seeker of liberation, but a &lt;em&gt;bubhukṣu&lt;/em&gt;, a religious virtuoso (to use Weber’s terminology) intent on obtaining supernatural powers or rewards and for whom &lt;em&gt;mokṣa&lt;/em&gt; was the Tantric liberation in life, &lt;em&gt;jīvanmukti&lt;/em&gt;, with its accompanying &lt;em&gt;siddhis.&lt;/em&gt; These texts thus never left aside entirely the quest for liberation, as appears for instance in the Trika system of &lt;em&gt;upāyas&lt;/em&gt; expounded mainly in Abhinavagupta’s &lt;em&gt;Tantrāloka&lt;/em&gt; (TĀ) on the basis of earlier Tantras such as the &lt;em&gt;Mālinivijayottara&lt;/em&gt; (MVT) and the &lt;em&gt;Siddhayogeśvarīmata&lt;/em&gt;. Considering the fundamental role of mantras both in the quest for liberation and in the acquisition and practice of powers, it is not surprising that in all these works mantras are described as effective in those two fields. The mantras used for these various purposes are sometimes different; but they may also be the same ones. I would like to consider briefly here a group of mantric practices used when magical effect are aimed at but which can also be used for other reasons – these two different sorts of purposes being admittedly not easy to distinguish.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8 Body and mantra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/8_Body_and_mantra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/8_Body_and_mantra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;mantras-in-the-human-body&#34;&gt;Mantras in the human body&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An interesting aspect of Tantric mantric practices and speculations concerns the (imaginary, of course) presence and circulation of mantras in the human body, or, more exactly, in the structure of channels (&lt;em&gt;nāḋī&lt;/em&gt;) and centres or nodal points (&lt;em&gt;granthi, cakra&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;padma&lt;/em&gt;) imagined in the haṭhayoga tradition as being present in the physical human body. This imaginary pattern is often called ‘subtle body’. But this is a misnomer since the subtle body properly so-called, &lt;em&gt;sūkṣmaśarīra&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;liṇgaśarīra&lt;/em&gt;, in Sanskrit, is made up of an ensemble of &lt;em&gt;tattvas&lt;/em&gt;, forming the element that transmigrates from body to body, and has by nature no form or aspect: it can be conceived, but not visualised; whereas the yogic structure is to be imagined, visualised, and it does not survive the death of the body. We shall therefore not call it subtle body, but rather yogic or imaginary body. In this structure, with which the Tantric adept lives and which he imagines (and sometimes visualises mentally) as being within his body, mantras are deemed to be present in the nodal points and to circulate in the &lt;em&gt;nāḋīs&lt;/em&gt; like a fluid, as a flow of power. To look briefly at this bodily presence of mantras may be of some interest from the point of view of the nature of mantras, but also as regards the way in which Tantric adepts perceive and experience their body. For the yogic body is not only ‘intraposed’ (to use T. Goudriaan’s felicitous expression) within the physical body, but also it oversteps it (the &lt;em&gt;dvādaśānta&lt;/em&gt; cakra is twelve fingerbreadths over the head). Furthermore, it includes cosmic visionary elements which transform it (or rather transform the way in which it is experienced), elements which also connect it, sometimes identify it, with aspects of the cosmos. The Tantrika’s experience of his body is thus of a very specific sort, being both human and cosmic or divine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>9 Mantra and mantraśāstra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/9_Mantra_and_mantrashAstra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/9_Mantra_and_mantrashAstra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The oral and the written&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mantra and &lt;em&gt;mantraśāstra**1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the theoretical approach as well as in the practice of mantras in Hinduism, the premium has always been (and still is) placed on the power of the oral word: Revelation, there, is not Scripture, but &lt;em&gt;śruti&lt;/em&gt;, ‘what has been heard’ (even though the first mantras were not heard, but ‘seen’ by the Vedic &lt;em&gt;r̥śis&lt;/em&gt;), a premium overemphasised in Tantra. Writing, however, is also sometimes used, and the literature on the subject, the so-called &lt;em&gt;mantraśāstra&lt;/em&gt;, the ‘teaching of the mantras’, is made up of a vast quantity of written texts. It thus appears that one writes on what is oral – which itself is sometimes transposed in writing. This written as well as oral ensemble is, of course, in Sanskrit. The oral literature we shall consider here is a part of the learned, lettered, not of the popular, domain, even though the learned (oral or written) sometimes ‘debases’ into the popular. The question of the relationship of the oral with the written – secondarily of the learned with the popular – insofar as it appears in the case of mantras, is what we shall try to see here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Authors and works cited</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/Authors_and_works_cited/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/Authors_and_works_cited/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BEFEO&lt;/em&gt; Bulletin de l’Ecole Française d’Extrême-Orient 125 n. 1, 128 n. 37, 130 n. 1, 141 n. 1, 156 n. 24, 158 n. 18 &lt;em&gt;JAs&lt;/em&gt; Journal Asiatique 143 n. 29, 146 n. 55, 151 n. 2 KSTS Kashmir Series of Texts and Studies 128 n. 39, 155 n. 2, 155 n. 6&lt;br&gt;&#xA;*&#xA;AgPur Agnipurāṇa 59, 75 AJ Ajtāgama 123 n. 9 Atharvaveda 56, 119 Abhinavagupta 3, 5, 8, 9, 14, 27, 42, 46–8, 55, 60, 61–2, 66, 73, 95, 100, 106, 113, 118, 138 n. 104 AhS Ahirbudhnyasaṃhitā Aitareyabrāhmaṇa 3, 111 Īśsp Īśānaśivagurudevapaddhati 18, 90, 97, 99 Amr̥;tānanda 37, 40, 45, 46, 60, 108, 136 n. 84, 156 n. 16 ĪPK Īśvarapratyabhijñākārikā 8, 9, 48 ĪPV Īśvarapratyabhijñāvimarśinī 150 n. 95 Utpaladeva 8, 48 Uddhārakoṣa of Dakṣiṇamūrti 5, 126 n. 7, 127 n. 29 R̥gveda 3, 12&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/Bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/Bibliography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Agnipurāṇa&lt;/em&gt; (1966) A prose English translation by M. Nāth Dutt Shastri, Varanasi, Chowkhamba Sanskrit Series Office.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alper, H.P. (ed.) (1986) &lt;em&gt;Understanding Mantras&lt;/em&gt;, Albany: State University of New York Press.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Atharva Veda Saṃhitā&lt;/em&gt; (1962) trans. by W.D. Whitney, Delhi: Motilal Banarsidass (reprint of the 1905 edition).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Avalon, A. (trad.) (1953) &lt;em&gt;Kāmakalāvilāsa&lt;/em&gt; by Punyānanda, Madras: Ganesh &amp;amp; Co.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brown, C.M. (1986) ‘&lt;em&gt;Purāṇa&lt;/em&gt; as scripture: from sound to image of the holy word in the Hindu tradition’, &lt;em&gt;History of Religion&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;26&lt;/em&gt; (1), pp. 68–86.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Index of Sanskrit terms</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/Index_of_Sanskrit_terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/Index_of_Sanskrit_terms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*aṃśa *21, 92, 101, 129 n. 48–9, 129 n. 52, 154 n. 6, 156 n. 24&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*akathahacakra *21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*akaḋamacakra *21&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*akṣamālā *10, 28, 33, 81, 88&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*akṣara *15, 65, 90, 93, 96, 101, 112, 116&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;akṣamālā&lt;/em&gt; Syn. *akṣasūtra *10, 28, 33, 81, 88&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*akṣasūtra *33&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*akṣasūtramantra *83&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*aṅga *16, 17, 30, 37, 60, 61, 65, 70–1, 72, 75, 76, 78, 83, 124 n. 28, 127 n. 26, 145 n. 50, 145 n. 53, 148 n. 73, 148 n. 75, 148 n. 78, 149 n. 86, 152 n. 7, 157 n. 7&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/Notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/padoux_mantras/Notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-introduction&#34;&gt;1 Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;1 Tantra is esoteric since its adepts, tāntrikas, are supposed to have been initiated. The sectarian initiation, &lt;em&gt;dīkṣā&lt;/em&gt;, being held as a first step towards liberation. All Tantric adepts or believers, however, are not initiated, But with or without initiation Tantric teaching is always described as secret. On the role of secrecy, see studies by Hugh Urban, notably &lt;em&gt;The Economics of Ecstasy. Tantra, Secrecy and Power in Colonial Bengal&lt;/em&gt; (New York: Oxford University Press, 2001).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
