<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bukka jaina vaiShNava truce</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/bukka-jaina-vaiShNava-truce_bhaNDAri-basadi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/bukka-jaina-vaiShNava-truce_bhaNDAri-basadi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;344 (136). At Bhandari-basti, on the first stone on the east side.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/epigraphiacarna02myso/page/n381/mode/2up?q=1290&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;स्वस्ति समस्त-प्रशस्ति-सहितम् ॥&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;पाषण्ड-सागर-महा-बडवामुखाग्नि-&lt;br&gt;&#xA;श्रीरङ्ग-राज-चरणाम्बुज-मूल-दास-&#xA;श्री-विष्णु-लोक-मणि-मण्टप-मार्ग्ग-दायी रामानुजो विजयते यति-राज-राज ॥&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;शक-वर्ष १२९०-नॆय कीलक-संवत्सरद भाद्रपद-शु १०&lt;br&gt;&#xA;बृ-स्वस्ति-श्रीमन्-महा-मण्डलेश्वरम् आरि-राय-विभाड&lt;br&gt;&#xA;भाषॆगॆ तप्पुव रायर गण्ड&lt;br&gt;&#xA;श्री-वीर-बुक्क-रायनु&lt;br&gt;&#xA;प्रिथ्वि-राज्यव माडुव कालदल्लि&lt;br&gt;&#xA;जैनरिगू भक्तरिगू संवादव् आदल्लि&lt;br&gt;&#xA;आनॆय-गॊण्डि हॊस-पट्टण पॆनुगुण्डॆ कल्लॆहड-पट्टणव् ऒळग् आद&lt;br&gt;&#xA;समस्त-नाड भव्य-जनङ्गळु आ बुक्क-रायङ्गॆ&lt;br&gt;&#xA;भक्तरु माडुव अन्यायङ्गळनू बिन्नहं माडल् आगि&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;कोविल्-तिरुमलॆ-पॆरुमाळ्&amp;ndash;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;कोविल्-तिरुनारायणपुर-मुख्यवाद सकलाचार्य्यरु&lt;br&gt;&#xA;सकळ-समयिगळु सकळ-सात्त्विकरु मोष्टिकरु तिरुपणि-तिरुविडि-तण्णी-&#xA;रवरु नाल्वत्त्-ऎण्टु-जनङ्गळु सावन्त-बोवक्कळु तिरिकुळ-जाम्बुव-कुलव्-ऒळगाद हदिनॆण्टु-नाड श्रीवैष्णवर कैय्यलु महारायनु वैष्णव-दर्शनक्कॆऊ&#xA;जैन-दर्शनक्कॆऊ भेधव् इल्लव् ऎन्दु रायनु वैष्णवर कैय्यलु जैनर कै-&#xA;विडिदु कॊट्टु यी-जैन-दर्शनक्कॆ पूर्व्व-मरियादॆयलु पञ्च-महा-वाद्यङ्गळु कळशवु सलुवुदु जैन-दर्शनक्कॆ भक्तर दॆसॆयिन्द हानि-व्रिद्धि आदरू वैस्-&#xA;ह्णव-हानि-व्रिद्धियागि पालिसुवरु यी-मर्य्यादॆयलु यल्ला-राज्यदॊळग् उळ्ळन्तह&#xA;पगॆ २ (१६०):&#xA;बस्तिगळिगॆ श्रीवैष्णवरु शासनव नट्टु पालिसुवरु चन्द्रार्क्क-स्थायिय्-आगि&#xA;वैष्णव-समयौ जैन-दर्शनव रक्षिसिकॊण्डु बहॆउ वैष्णवरु जैनरू&#xA;वॊन्दु भेदाव्äगि काणल् आगदु श्री-तिरुमलॆय तातय्यङ्गळु समस्त-राज्यद भ-&#xA;व्य-जनङ्गळ अनुमतदिन्द बॆळुगुळद-तीर्त्थदल्लि वैष्णव-अङ्ग-रक्षॆगोसुक समस्त-राज्यदॊळग् उळ्ळन्तह जैनर बागिळु-गट्टलॆयागि मनॆ-मनॆगॆ वर्षक्कॆ १&#xA;हण कॊट्टु आय्-ऎत्तिड हॊन्निङ्गॆ देवर अङ्ग-रक्षॆगॆय् इप्पत्त्-आळनू सण्टविट्टु मिक्-&#xA;क हॊन्निङ्गॆ जिर्ण्ण-जिनालयगळिगॆ सॊथॆयन् इकूडु यी-मरियादॆयलु चन्द्रार्क्कर्&#xA;उळ्ळन्नां तप्पलियदॆ वर्ष-वर्षक्कॆ कॊट्टु कीर्त्तियनू पुण्यवनू उपार्ज्जिसिकॊम्-&#xA;बुडु यी-माडिद कट्टळॆयनु आवन् ऒब्बनु मीरिदवनु राज-द्रोहि सङ्घ-संदायक्-&#xA;कॆ द्रोहि तपस्विय् आगलि ग्रामिणिय् आगलि यी-धम्र्म्मव कॆड्सिदर् आडडॆ गङ्गॆय तडि-&#xA;यल्लि कपिलॆयनू ब्राह्मणननू कॊन्द पापदल्लि होहरु ॥&#xA;श्लो ॥ स्व-दत्तं पर-दत्तं वा यो हरेति वसुन्धरां&#xA;षष्टि-वर्ष-सहस्राणि विष्टायां जायते क्रिमिः ॥&#xA;(सुब्सॆक़ुऎन्ल्य् अद्दॆद् अबॊवॆ.)&#xA;कल्लॆहड हर्वि-शॆट्टिय सु-पुत्र बुसुवि-शॆट्टि बुक्क-रायरिगॆ बिन्नहं-&#xA;माडि तिरुमलॆय तातय्यङ्गळ बिजयम्-गैसि तरण्डु जिर्ण्णोद्धारव माडिसिदरु&#xA;उभय-समयवू कूडि बुसुवि-शॆट्टियारिगॆ सङ्घ-नाय्क-पट्टव कट्टिदरु ॥&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trad-hindu-response-inadequacy</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/trad-hindu-response-inadequacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/trad-hindu-response-inadequacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1437818910238142466.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One sees that same cavalier attitude among some Ācāryas in respect of anti-Hindu threats in Academia. Recall a video where an Ācārya tries to joke:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Who is this Sheldon Bālak? I need to do Sandhyāvandana!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I didn’t think it was funny. I found it naive &amp;amp; unhelpful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Unhelpful assumptions:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Our adversaries’ religions are completely empty &amp;amp; stupid. No, they aren’t. It’s fine for an outburst. But not a serious response:&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;“All we need to do is to send our traditional Ācāryas to debate with academia.” Sorry to pour cold water but NO. They are not prepared; not in your wildest dreams.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Traditional scholarship is still plagued by blind denialism of academia &amp;amp; this most pernicious idea that all answers are already there in tradition. Not all but many of them are like this. Apparently, we don’t have to conceptualize new frameworks or arguments. One can see this stagnation in many of the heavily touted examples of “traditional intellectual response”. You “list” a rival’s positions, then state your traditional position (as if the world should just take it for granted), discuss staple examples from old Mīmāmsā texts in Skt for 45 minutes. Which of his substantive theses did you effectively demolish? Only Īśvara knows.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Which brings to my last point—Discourse in Skt is not going to solve problems. Thinking so means you are so caught up in the form &amp;amp; appearance that you have missed the substance.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Without making genuine effort to understand the other’s position &amp;amp; its nuances, without accepting the hard truth that traditional intellectual frameworks do need a significant upgrade today (as they did throughout history), traditional scholarship has very little future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
