<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Nikhil&#39;s vedism on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nikhil-vedism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Nikhil&#39;s vedism on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nikhil-vedism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ayn rand</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nikhil-vedism/ayn_rand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nikhil-vedism/ayn_rand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With regard to ontology, I accept many of her views especially related to Aristotelian logic (but not her rejection of Divinity), e.g. one objective reality independent of human sense-perceptions, the law of non-contradiction, the law of the excluded middle, the law of identity, the primacy of the concept, the motive power of the Idea, &amp;amp;c.  I have a profound distrust of people who question such basic principles as objective reality or the law of non-contradiction, because it shows that they are either unintelligent or reflexively contrarian.  I don&amp;rsquo;t believe anyone can really believe A∧¬A.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humility</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nikhil-vedism/humility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nikhil-vedism/humility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;would humility have been considered a virtue for the vedics&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It depends on what one means by &amp;ldquo;humility&amp;rdquo;.&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Humility&amp;rdquo; defined as a lack of arrogance, where arrogance means &amp;ldquo;overestimation of one&amp;rsquo;s ability&amp;rdquo;, would of course be a virtue in every society, since arrogance (so defined) is believing an untruth, one that can be quite dangerous not only to others but to the self.  There are several &amp;ldquo;pride comes before the fall&amp;rdquo; stories in the Véda, including in the primordial slaughter of Vr̥trá, described as &amp;ldquo;emasculate yet claiming manly vigor&amp;rdquo; (Griffith on R̥V 1.32.7).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nikhil on hindus</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nikhil-vedism/nikhil_on_hindus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nikhil-vedism/nikhil_on_hindus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sources: Vedism discord server.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;invitation&#34;&gt;Invitation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Never lose heart, Vedists.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The orthodox and modern Hindus, trapped in their false and impious ways, will always vastly outnumber us, just as even Dásyu-s have always far outnumbered the Ā́rya-s. There is nothing inherently wrong with that, nor surprising.…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Like ants obeying an adulterous queen, they are only capable of mindlessly citing their prædecessors and refuse to give thought to concepts like Beauty, Truth, or logical consistency. In fact, they view religion as a tool for social control rather than as actual Truth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Society</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nikhil-vedism/society/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nikhil-vedism/society/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;prostitution&#34;&gt;Prostitution&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prostitutes existed in Vedic times and were even employed in certain rituals.  So while (obviously) it should be discouraged and (far from Vedic society being &amp;ldquo;sex work–positive&amp;rdquo;) they were looked down upon as impure, there was a recognition that promiscuous women who sell their bodies are a fundamental part of any society (even the most supposedly degeneracy-free like Islamic ones), and the recognition of this rôle extended to the religious sphere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>varNa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nikhil-vedism/varNa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/nikhil-vedism/varNa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let us reject the framing of Vedism vs. orthodox Hinduism as a struggle between Rājanía and Brāhmaṇá religions, and remember instead that the Brahmá–Kṣatrá are Vedically united (TB 3.8.4.3, ĀiB 3.11.8) in ruling the Víş (KB 16.5.6, ŞB 11.2.7.16), with the Brahmán subordinate to the Kṣatrá in the realm of politics (TS 2.5.10.1, ĀiB 7.29.2) and yet, in the realm of ritual and of religious authority, the Kṣatrá subordinate to the Brahmán (PB 2.8.2, ĀiB 8.9.6).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
