<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On darshanas</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/2006-12-28_on-darshanas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/2006-12-28_on-darshanas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/12/28/on-darshanas/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing many fellow traditional Hindus have found frustrating about me is my lack knowledge and lack of affinity for the advaita stream of vedanta, and more fundamentally me being a svatantra. My blasphemous views regarding vedas and their apauruSheyatva are also hardly appreciated in their midst. I am not shaken by their views because I am pretty firm in my convictions on these matters arising from ongoing study of the originals, and yAj~navalya always stands out as beacon. These are indeed matters of worthy of deep historical study by any Hindu and it is advisable that they take nothing for granted. The key to their study is comparative philosophy – a term first suggested by Brijendranath Seal, a modern va~Nga scholar of early Hindu thought. Just like comparative linguistics is central to the understanding of Sanskrit, the language of Hindu thought, comparative philosophy is central to understanding the evolution of Hindu thought. It should be amply clear that the fundamental aspects of Hindu thought cannot be understood without comparative linguistics and philosophy, a point so blithely neglected by many traditional Hindus. Of course like most other sketches presented here the below ramblings are not completely worked out pieces of research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hindus on the hard problem</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/2006-10-02_hindus-on-the-hard-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/2006-10-02_hindus-on-the-hard-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/10/02/hindus-on-the-hard-problem/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We had earlier mentioned the interesting discussion we had with Marc and kalashajA on what the western philosophers admit is the hard problem of &lt;a href=&#34;http://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/06/we-are-zombies.html&#34;&gt;consciousness&lt;/a&gt;. Our other acquaintance of the clan of the kAshyapa-s, had asked me if the Indians had contributed anything to the problem. He intuitively felt they had done so, but could not place a finger on it. Marc, R and I had some further discussion, and realized I knew less of it than I thought I did. As a result it was not certain that I had a defensive argument for all my original stances on the matter, and definitely consider it an area of my thought that is still shaping.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti ritualism spiritual</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/anti-ritualism_spiritual/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/anti-ritualism_spiritual/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1876464436677845324&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the below should be taken with caution because our social intersections are limited, we get the sense that among the H 10-20 or more years younger than us there is a growing cadre of that type that claims to be &amp;ldquo;spiritual&amp;rdquo; but not &amp;ldquo;religious&amp;rdquo;. It seems that when they say they are not religious they are mostly uninterested in H ritual practice of the saMskAra type or even personal acts of rituals towards deities. It is not entirely clear to us what kind of spirits the cleave to.  But they show an inclination towards a certain class of nonsense to borderline nonsense beliefs of mostly occidental vintage. The most bizarre thing I heard one of them tell me was that DNA was once 12 stranded!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Focal-diversity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/focal-diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/focal-diversity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/convos/1645607881860055041&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Why do some, under a “śāstriya darśana” pretext, dismiss basic facts such as that the religion of the Vedasam̐hitās was primarily or started off primarily as Aindra? See below: 👇🏾 Even Skandapurāṇa recognizes &amp;amp; alludes to this rather obvious fact, expressly linking the Ṛṣis’ stutis &amp;amp; vākyas (Brāhmaṇas) with Aindra worship.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;तस्मात् काल-मुखे सर्वे&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;पतिता&lt;/strong&gt; नात्र संशयः॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;सर्वे श्रुतिपरा यूयम्&lt;br&gt;&#xA;इन्द्राद्या देवता-गणाः॥ १०.७७ ॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;प्ररोचन-पराः सर्वे&lt;br&gt;&#xA;क्षुद्राश् चेन्द्रादयो वृथा॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;नात्मानं&lt;/strong&gt; च प्रपञ्चेन&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;वेत्सि&lt;/strong&gt; त्वं हि शचीपते॥ १०.७८ ॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;कृतः प्रयत्नो&lt;/strong&gt; हि महान्&lt;br&gt;&#xA;अमृतार्थं त्वया शठ॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;अश्वमेध-शतेनैव&lt;br&gt;&#xA;यद् राज्यं प्राप्तवान् असि॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;अपि तच् च पराधीनं&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तन् &lt;strong&gt;न जानासि&lt;/strong&gt; दुर्मते॥ १०.७९ ॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;यैर् वद-वाक्यैस् त्वं मूढ&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;संस्तुतोऽसि&lt;/strong&gt; तपस्विभिः॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;ते मूढास् तोषयन्ति त्वां&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तत्-तद्-रागपरायणाः॥ १०.८० ॥&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fractal structure</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/fractal-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/fractal-structure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1837320811226521926&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Certain Hindu religious systems, like the great shaiva institutions (both pAshupata and aishAna), were characterized by what might be termed a scale-free network architecture in terms of maTha-s and temples. They had major hubs which were which were connected to smaller hubs and so on finally ending in terminal leaves. These leaves were the small temples in the grAma-s, while examples of hubs were big maTha-shrines like the one at golagi or Amardaka. Such a network structure is susceptible to an attack on the hubs and rather resistant to an attack on the leaves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hard problem of consciousness</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/hard-problem-consciousness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/hard-problem-consciousness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A timeline of its past lives as a TikZ diagram according to GPT (messed the TikZ initially). Heard a clip of the guy in red who was awarded the Nobel prize, pontificating on consciousness on a podcast. He gave a silly thought experiment paralleling Chalmers&amp;rsquo; philosophical zombie:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Replace every neuron in your brain with an artificial neuron that does the same thing as the original.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Then ask if you are conscious at every stage.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You would obviously answer yes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From that, he goes on to assert that it is an emergent property of the neural connectivity and not some independent entity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The interesting thing is that he was never able to say how it emerges beyond waving his hands. It seemed quite apparent that he was simply blind to the explanation gap and the issue of the hard problem. Almost 2 decades ago, I had the same discussion with a prolific condensed matter physicist from an Ivy League school, and he was also simply unable to perceive the gap despite multiple attempts. The same happened again with a neurobiologist and a physicist a few years ago. It is quite interesting that this insight needs something to fundamentally click that might not happen to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hindu literalism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/hindu-literalism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/hindu-literalism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good points. Agree with the proposal that most H are not equipped. Anecdotally speaking I&amp;rsquo;ve seen the same &amp;ndash; a certain H fragility &amp;ndash; a newly half-educate H who might &amp;rsquo;ve picked up a tome or 2 of Dick Dawkins &amp;amp; suddenly see himself as possessing a deep insight which obviates the the need for religion. Regurgitating Dick or someone like that he would bellow on to those who might listen or not how meaningless &amp;amp; useless religion is. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen similar transformations with H who encounter Marx &amp;amp; his cohorts, Ambedkar, the canon of nayonmAda or even a physics or a biology textbook. Then those newbies would lecture about how &amp;ldquo;irrational&amp;rdquo; religion is &amp;ndash; a polycephalous or therocephalous god is deemed an impossibility of a specimen for teratological+++(←abnormalities of physiological development)+++ investigation. The size of ghaTotkacha is given an analysis in terms of speed of neuronal conductance, etc. This indeed can lead to a denudation of religion &amp;amp; consequent exposure to self-wrought or enemy-engineered social devolution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Language</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/language/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/language/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/974497694558380032.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Three languages could be considered as candidates for the national language of India:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;English:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Pros: language of science/technology. Publishing your paper on your next greates discovery in Hindi or Tamil is not going to get you far. Becoming language of world system.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Cons: not many understand it well in India; language of erstwhile enemy of the Indian people; does not capture certain aspects of Indian experience.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hindi;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;pros:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;it is the modern successor of the pan-Indian vulgar registers of Aryan speech: modern version of apabhramsha which was once understood as a pan-Indian language and the prAkR^ita-s at even earlier period.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;It is a grammatically simpler than most other Indian languages once its logic is correctly taught.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Vocabulary mostly pan-Indian.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Cons:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;unfair advantage to northern speakers who are close to it natively&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Not language of knowledge, education or having independent technical flourish.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;schwa deletion is aurally vulgar.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sanskrit;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Pros:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;language of religion, India science, and education.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Intimately linked to the identity &amp;amp;unity of the Hindu nation.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sounds good to the ear.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Gives no undue advantage to any one group in the country.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Learning it can be a character-building experience that helps those with lower mental capacity to at least acquire some sense of educational worth.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;cons:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Difficult grammar, especially when there is a drive to adhere closely to pANini &amp;amp; his successors in entirity.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Good schemes for curricular delivery have not been done for schools,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;though paracurricular systems like SBh might be somewhat better.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;d say that Skt is the best choice though it will not be without difficulty.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I think it needs some course correction&lt;br&gt;&#xA;such as willingness to impart in both nAgarI and romanized or other scripts.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Willingness to jetision the idiotic fetish for long conjunct words in writing.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Deemphasizing kAvya and focussing on prose in practical education.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Being lax with more vulgar register of grammar at least to start with.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perennialism &amp; Multi-peaks</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/perennialism_multi-peaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/perennialism_multi-peaks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1647060778095083520.html&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is a tendency among many educated H to subscribe to philosophical perennialism of the form that all H religious systems, or even all world religious systems culminate in the same escathon. When I raised the question of why the escathons need to be the same, when there is no evidence for that from within the systems, I never received a satisfactory answer. For example, is prancing as gaNa in rudra&amp;rsquo;s retinue the same as a station on the moon as pitR^i? They tend to push those away as arthavAda concealing the same basic endpoint. Of course instead of the lunar station, if we ask them if it might be same as finding a place in the retinue of viShvaksena, more than one has tried to tell has rudra = viShNu = brahman (n).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Public ed Limits</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/public-ed-limits/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/public-ed-limits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SM has raised a bit of conflict in me thus: On one hand I think H should be educated about the texts as they are rather their second hand imaginations regarding them. On the other hand I agree with the below &amp;ndash; average H education is simply too poor for them to meaningfully apprehend &amp;ldquo;difficult&amp;rdquo; texts that need nuance &amp;amp; historical context. While this may sound elitist, this is exactly what SM has taught me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tantra end accounts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/tantra-end-accounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/tantra-end-accounts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One could question whether the Sandersonian term &amp;ldquo;shaiva age&amp;rdquo; is an entirely accurate term for the Indospheric religious landscape in the pre-Mohammedan medieval age (when the Indosphere peaked). A more general term could be the &amp;ldquo;tantra age&amp;rdquo; or even more generally the cosmopolitan Sanskrit age. Of course, most Occidental indologists and their Japanese and other fellow travelers are shy to tell you why this age ended (e.g., why did JS&amp;rsquo;s title of &amp;ldquo;ending the shaiva age&amp;rdquo; play out). Insofar as we can define certain markers of an end (e.g., in Kashmir, the Panjab,  the Doab and central India), the answer is simple and indisputable: it is the coming down of the green curtains of marUnmAda. The mlechCha cannot accept and articulate this because he is joined at the hip with marUnmAda in the form of the mlechCha-marUnmattAbhisaMdhi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ubhaya vidvattA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/ubhaya-vidvattA/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/ubhaya-vidvattA/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/blog_supplement/status/1940646016807535017&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is indeed notable most of the Occidental indologists (and sadly H students of the religion too) are not &amp;ldquo;ubhayavidvAn-s&amp;rdquo;.  Those are who are good at the arcana IE linguistics (its problems notwithstanding) and/or early Aryan philology &amp;ldquo;suck&amp;rdquo; at paurANika and tAntrika studies. Conversely, those who are good at the later think the world began ~ 250 BCE.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I agree Sanderson is a doyenne of tAntrika(+atimArga) studies but his paper titled something like &amp;ldquo;shaiva-s in atharvavedin territory&amp;rdquo; reflects a certain disconnect with an understanding of the earlier vaidika tradition, its contours and evolution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>महा-वाक्यानि</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/mahA-vAkyAni/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/MT/mahA-vAkyAni/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For some statements like aham brahmAsmi || or tat tvam asi || are vaidika mahAvAkya-s. For us:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;विश्वस्माद् इन्द्र उत्तरः॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;इन्द्रो विश्वस्य कर्मणो धर्ता॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;अस्कम्भने सविता द्याम् अदृंहत्॥&lt;br&gt;&#xA;इदं दयसे विश्वम् अभ्वम्॥&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
