<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Funerary similarity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/funerary-similarity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/funerary-similarity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; The fravašis thus help in war, and they give aid also in peace. They are &amp;ldquo;givers of &amp;hellip; a boon to the eager, of health to the sick, givers of good fortune to him who invokes them, worshipping, satisfying, bringing offerings” (Yt.13.24). In fact, like the Indian pitaras, the fravašis receive reverence and supplication in very much the same way as the gods themselves, and are held to have the same capacity to answer prayers and bestow boons. It seems probable that protective powers, perhaps early attributed to the heroic departed, were magnified with the development of the doctrine that blessed souls might hope to dwell with the gods them&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incest</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/incest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/incest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Xwedodah (Persian: خویدوده; khwēdōdah; Avestan: xᵛae¯tuuadaθa) is a spiritually-influenced style of consanguine marriage assumed to have been historically practiced in Zoroastrianism before the Muslim conquest of Persia.[1] Such marriages are recorded as having been inspired by Zoroastrian cosmogony and considered pious. It was a high act of worship in Zoroastrianism, and there were punishments for not performing it.[2][3] This form of direct familial incest marriage allowed Zoroastrians to marry their sisters, daughters, granddaughters, and their own mothers to take as wives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polytheistic dualsim</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/polytheistic-dualism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/polytheistic-dualism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the Zoroastrian Avesta begins with the words &amp;ldquo;In the name of the Gods&amp;rdquo; (pa nãm i ýazdã)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So much for &amp;lsquo;Zoroastrian monotheism&amp;rsquo; lmao. Funnily, the translation on avesta.org has cowardly chosen not to translate this line. Hilarious. They skip the first line and don&amp;rsquo;t translate it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://unrollthread.com/t/1514962456224755719/&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zoroastrianism (Mazdayasna) must be the only form of &amp;ldquo;monotheism&amp;rdquo; where the creator diety (Ahura Mazda) offers sacrifices to his own created beings. (Yasht 15) Or where the one God (Ahura Mazda) says that his own created beings are as worthy of worship as himself (Yasht 10). I find it very funny how so many modern day westernized Parsis or Iranian Shia converts actually believe &amp;ldquo;Zoroastrianism was the first monotheism!&amp;rdquo; Anyone with a basic understanding of Mazdayasna knows this is totally incorrect. Zoroastrianism was polytheistic dualism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presentation</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/presentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We worship all the Yazats &amp;amp; follow asha/arta &amp;amp; strive for the destruction of druj &amp;amp; agents of ahriman alongside ahriman himself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In medieval Sanskrit texts written by Parsis in India, that&amp;rsquo;s how it is represented. In English texts written under the British, it is monotheistic+&amp;ldquo;Aryan&amp;rdquo;, best of both. Same with contemporary Persian texts. In contemporary English texts written for Europeans, it is uber-Pagan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vedic-connection</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/vedic-connection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/vedic-connection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Btw, at their core, the Zoroastrian (Mazdean) &amp;amp; Vedic religions are about the same thing, that is, order (asha/rta/dharma) has to be maintained perpetually in a chaotic world, and this order is principally restored by engaging in relationships w the Gods focused around sacrifice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ofc, they differ a good bit also, but they are the most similar to each other. It&amp;rsquo;s like two sects of Christianity, obviously they will believe the same core things, but their differences will seem huge to each other as well, because they will differ on crucially important issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
