<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;02 Kings and Priests on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/02_Kings_and_Priests/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;02 Kings and Priests on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/02_Kings_and_Priests/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>06 The Consecration of the Monastic Compound at Mount Koya by Kukai</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/02_Kings_and_Priests/06_The_Consecration_of_the_Monastic_Compound_at_Mount_Koya_by_Kukai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/02_Kings_and_Priests/06_The_Consecration_of_the_Monastic_Compound_at_Mount_Koya_by_Kukai/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;David L. Gardiner&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although Japanese Buddhism is probably best known in popular circles for its  rich tradition of Zen teachings and practices, from a historical perspective it is  plausible to contend that no form has had more of a pervasive impact on the  overall development of Japanese religion than the esoteric or Tantric Buddhist  schools known in Japan as mikkyo (&amp;ldquo;secret teaching&amp;rdquo;). Mikkyo was first formally  represented in the Tendai and Shingon schools founded in the early ninth century,  but its roots are discernible in the eighth century and its branches, to continue  the metaphor, extend throughout virtually all the subsequent schools that  emerged in the Kamakura period (around the thirteenth century), in particular  in the Zen, Pure Land, and Nichiren schools, where its presence bore significant  and recognizable fruits. Among the variety of ways mikkyo seems to have influ enced religious expressions other than those formally identifiable as Tantric are  the inclusion of elaborate rites with a profusion of liturgical paraphernalia, the  employment of dharanis or mantras in recitation of prayers, and the utilization  of some form of painted mandala diagrams. In addition to these more concrete  instances, one might add the basic religious paradigm that mikkyo offered, which  encompassed elements such as the perfect identity of practitioner and Buddha (in  body, speech, as well as mind) and the generally affirmative view of the ordinary  world as being a manifestation of the sacred body of the Buddha.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 Praises of the Drunken Peacocks</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/02_Kings_and_Priests/07_Praises_of_the_Drunken_Peacocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/02_Kings_and_Priests/07_Praises_of_the_Drunken_Peacocks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Richard H. Davis&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Near the head of the Mahuar River in Madhya Pradesh, in the small backwater  village of Rannod, sit the ruins of an ancient Hindu monastery built sometime in  the tenth century C.E. On a wall of the veranda, carved on a stone tablet, a lengthy  inscription praises the community of Saiva monks who built and inhabited this  monastic retreat in medieval times. The poet speaks of the Saiva lineage called  the &amp;ldquo;Drunken Peacocks&amp;rdquo; (Mattamayura) as a stalk, &amp;ldquo;free of knots, its strong  branches spreading widely.&amp;rdquo; The poetic figure is historically apt, because other  inscriptions from the same period found in many different parts of the subcon tinent speak of more ascetics and teachers linked to the same lineage. The  Drunken Peacocks appear to have been a broadly dispersed, celebrated, and in&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Precepts for an Emperor</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/02_Kings_and_Priests/08_Precepts_for_an_Emperor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/02_Kings_and_Priests/08_Precepts_for_an_Emperor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Allan G. Grapard&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The document translated here represents the views of Kukai (774-835) on ritual  and power, and gives insights into his articulation of the relationship between  esoteric Buddhism and the imperial cultic system of Japan at the beginning of the  Heian period (794-1185). This document was written for an important occasion:  Emperor Heizei (774-824), who had withdrawn from public life in 809, asked  Kukai to confer upon him Shingon precepts, and to grant him an initiatory unc&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
