<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Lochtefeld - hinduism-encyclopedia on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/lochtefeld_hinduism-encyclopedia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Lochtefeld - hinduism-encyclopedia on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/lochtefeld_hinduism-encyclopedia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Index</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/lochtefeld_hinduism-encyclopedia/Tail/Index/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/lochtefeld_hinduism-encyclopedia/Tail/Index/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A&#xA;Abbott, Justin E., 79, 98, 99, 220,&#xA;[[257]]&#xA;, 312, 322, 409, 410, 459,&#xA;[[614]]&#xA;, 712&#xA;Abhang, 1&#xA;Abhava, 1, 55, 521, 537. See also&#xA;Philosophy&#xA;Abhaya Hasta, 1. See also Dance&#xA;Abhijnanashakuntala, 1–2, 211,&#xA;[[336]]&#xA;, 436, 621&#xA;Abhimanyu, 2–3, 138&#xA;Abhinavagupta, writer, 3, 376,&#xA;[[524]]&#xA;, 708&#xA;Abhinaya, 3, 171&#xA;Abhira. See Ahir&#xA;Abhisheka, ritual bathing, 3&#xA;Abortion, 3. See also Women&#xA;feticide, 227–228&#xA;Achala Ekadashi, 4, 218, 227&#xA;Achamana, 4, 658&#xA;Achamaniya, 4, 720&#xA;Achara, 4–5, 499&#xA;Acharya, 5&#xA;Achintyabhedabheda, 5, 242&#xA;Achyuta, 5&#xA;Act of truth, 5–6, 168, 457, 711. See&#xA;also Truth&#xA;Actors, Pilgrims, Kings and Gods&#xA;(Kapur), 389, 562, 651&#xA;Adharma, 6&#xA;Adhikamasa. See Intercalary&#xA;Month&#xA;Adhikara, 3, 6, 116, 266, 398, 411,&#xA;[[414]]&#xA;, 446, 492&#xA;Adhiratha, 6–7, 352, 400&#xA;Adhishthana, architecture, 7, 353&#xA;Adhvaryum, 7, 122, 576, 718&#xA;Adhyasa, 7–8, 12, 133, 623&#xA;Adi, 8, 685&#xA;Adigranth, 8–9, 23, 116, 328, 459,&#xA;[[511]]&#xA;, 553, 569&#xA;Adishesha. See Shesha&#xA;Aditi, 9–10&#xA;Primary references appear in boldface type.&#xA;Aditya, 10, 538&#xA;Adivasi communities, 10–11, 396,&#xA;[[484]]&#xA;, 572&#xA;Daita, 164–165&#xA;Gond, 255&#xA;Santal, 597&#xA;Adoption, 11, 81, 386, 661. See&#xA;also Women&#xA;Adriel, Jean, 435&#xA;Adultery, 11–12, 229, 406, 507&#xA;Advaita Vedanta, 12–13, 42, 124,&#xA;[[132]]&#xA;, 213, 214, 223, 242, 321,&#xA;[[388]]&#xA;, 389, 395, 396, 417, 433,&#xA;[[474]]&#xA;, 486, 502, 519, 524, 578,&#xA;[[607]]&#xA;, 610, 622, 636, 644, 673,&#xA;[[721]]&#xA;, 746, 767. See also&#xA;Vedanta&#xA;Bhamati branch, 49, 100–101&#xA;schools, 7–8, 320&#xA;Vivarana school, 486&#xA;Advaita Vedanta up to Samkara&#xA;and His Pupils (Potter), 8, 13,&#xA;[[320]]&#xA;, 487, 624, 673&#xA;Advani, Lal Krishna, 13, 104&#xA;Aerial cars, 13&#xA;Aesthetics. See Rasa&#xA;Agama, 13&#xA;Agastya, sage, 13–14, 231, 296,&#xA;[[392]]&#xA;, 455&#xA;Aghori, 14&#xA;Agni, 14–15, 16, 44, 53, 195, 236,&#xA;[[262]]&#xA;, 366, 572, 601, 628, 654,&#xA;[[741]]&#xA;. See also Fire&#xA;Agni Akhara, 15–16, 24&#xA;Agnihotra, 16&#xA;Agnikula, 16, 549&#xA;Agnipradakshinam, 9, 15, 16,&#xA;[[428]]&#xA;, 601&#xA;Agnipravesha, 16&#xA;Agnishtoma, 16–17&#xA;Agrahara, 17&#xA;Ahalya, 17, 245&#xA;[[807]]&#xA;Aham Brahmasmi, 17, 113, 408&#xA;Ahamkar, 17–18, 129, 224, 408,&#xA;[[415]]&#xA;, 588&#xA;Ahimsa, 18, 41, 63&#xA;Ahir, 19&#xA;Aihole, 19, 51, 751&#xA;Aims of Life, 19, 189, 222, 223, 262,&#xA;[[288]]&#xA;, 340, 342, 443, 536, 545.&#xA;See also Life&#xA;Aippasi, 19, 685&#xA;Airavata, 19. See also Elephant&#xA;Aiteraya Brahmana, 20, 123, 626&#xA;Aiyanar, 20&#xA;Aiyappa, 20, 20–21, 364, 410,&#xA;[[443]]&#xA;, 616&#xA;Aja Ekadashi, 21, 93, 218, 227&#xA;Ajamila, 21&#xA;Ajatashatru, 21, 21–22, 117&#xA;Ajita Keshakambalin, 22, 430. See&#xA;also Philosophers&#xA;Ajivika school, philosophy, 22, 226,&#xA;[[258]]&#xA;, 478, 639&#xA;Ajna Chakra, 22, 137. See&#xA;also Chakras&#xA;Akasha, 22–23, 217, 220&#xA;Akbar, 23, 25, 29, 70, 163, 273, 396,&#xA;[[422]]&#xA;, 442&#xA;Akhand Path, 23&#xA;Akhara, 23–24, 26, 35, 69, 97, 140, 474&#xA;Akhyati, 24, 223, 378, 516&#xA;Akkadevi, 24&#xA;Akrura, 24&#xA;Akshakumara, 24, 418&#xA;Akshamala, 24–25&#xA;Akshar Purushottam Samstha, 25,&#xA;[[521]]&#xA;, 626&#xA;Akshaya Trtiya, 25, 227, 501&#xA;Akshaya Vata, 25–26, 29&#xA;Alakananda River, 26, 77, 95, 184,&#xA;[[242]]&#xA;, 323, 340, 353, 416, 510,&#xA;[[576]]&#xA;, 577&#xA;Alakhiya Akhara, 26–27&#xA;Alambhusha, 27&#xA;Alamkaras, 27, 363&#xA;[[808]]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/lochtefeld_hinduism-encyclopedia/Introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/lochtefeld_hinduism-encyclopedia/Introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you drive through the cornfields of northern Illinois, just north of the town of&#xA;Aurora, you may see a massive brick building that seems out of place. It stands three&#xA;or four stories high with an elaborate facade depicting pillars and cornices. Topped by&#xA;towering spires with flapping banners, it looks as if it belongs to another world. In a&#xA;sense it does—the architectural style comes from southern India, and the building&#xA;itself is a Hindu temple.&#xA;I was there late on a Sunday morning, and the parking lot was about half full.&#xA;There were cars from as far away as Michigan. The building’s main entrance was a little&#xA;below ground level, and as is common with Hindu temples outside of India, the low-&#xA;est level had a lobby, a kitchen, and a large meeting room that was comparable to the&#xA;“church basements” of its Christian counterparts. The lobby was furnished austerely,&#xA;with folding tables and chairs. There were a few people sitting near the kitchen, drink-&#xA;ing tea and chatting informally.&#xA;By the staircases leading upstairs to the temple room were rows of simple shelves,&#xA;fronted by low benches. I removed my shoes, as is customary before entering a temple,&#xA;both to preserve the temple and to signify that one is walking on holy ground. The&#xA;staircase marked the threshold between two regions, the outer and the inner world.&#xA;Upstairs, the temple was richly decorated. The presiding deity was Venkateshvara, a&#xA;form of the god Vishnu, whose image was placed in the center of the temple, the most&#xA;important space. Yet, as in most Hindu temples, there were images of deities from&#xA;throughout the pantheon: Ganesh, Shiva, Subrahmanya, other forms of Vishnu, dif-&#xA;ferent forms of the Goddess, and various subsidiary deities. Most of the images were&#xA;carved from black South Indian granite and polished to a mirrorlike finish. Many were&#xA;housed in small shrines built out of white marble. The primary function of a Hindu&#xA;temple is to serve as the home for the deities it contains, and it was clear that the&#xA;people who had commissioned the temple had spared no efforts. The temple had&#xA;been lovingly built and has been carefully maintained.&#xA;The worshipers in the temple took little notice of me, and I was allowed to roam&#xA;as I wished. Even though Venkateshvara was the temple’s presiding deity, the primary&#xA;activity while I was there took place in front of one of the subsidiary shrines, an image&#xA;of the Goddess in the form of Kumari (“virgin”). Seated around the image were about&#xA;twenty members of an extended family. The young girls, who were clearly the focus of&#xA;the rite, sat directly in front of the shrine. Brahmin priests took various offerings from&#xA;the older women: plastic gallon jugs of milk, Ziploc bags of sugar, and Tupperware&#xA;containers of yogurt and honey. Each offering was poured over the image in turn. A&#xA;pitcher of water was poured over the image between each offering to wash it clean.&#xA;The temple priests performing the rite were dressed traditionally, with white dhotis&#xA;(garments worn around the waist, extending below the knees), bare chests, and the&#xA;sacred thread over their left shoulders. They bore crisp red tilaks (sectarian identifying&#xA;marks) on their foreheads, and intoned the rite in rapid-fire Sanskrit.&#xA;Although a Christian visitor might find the languages, deities, and rites completely&#xA;alien, many of the other elements of the day would be soothingly familiar: a group of&#xA;families coming for worship on a Sunday morning, dressed in their “Sunday best,”&#xA;with others chatting over coffee and sweets in the “church basement.” Except for a few&#xA;sari-clad older women, the people there were dressed no differently than anyone one&#xA;might encounter on the street—the men in suits and jackets, the girls and women in&#xA;long, flowing dresses.&#xA;Just as the Hindu temple in rural Illinois had introduced Indian customs to the&#xA;local community, it was clear that the influence of American culture had set this&#xA;temple apart from its traditional counterparts in India. Unlike in India, where temples&#xA;serve mainly as places of worship, Hindu temples in America often serve as cultural&#xA;centers for the Hindu community, sponsoring events such as dance, music, and&#xA;drama performances, along with language study programs and festival celebrations.&#xA;viIn many cases, the membership of Hindu temples in America cuts across the tradi-&#xA;tional barriers that divide Indian society—social status, regional background, sectar-&#xA;ian loyalty—giving these Hindu temples far more inclusive constituencies.&#xA;The cultural landscape of the United States has changed dramatically in recent&#xA;years. Today it possesses a plurality of cultures that my grandparents and their gener-&#xA;ation probably would have found inconceivable. The Hindu temple outside of Aurora,&#xA;Illinois, is but one small sign of the increasing visibility of Asian cultures in American&#xA;society. Another sign of this pluralism is the growing number of ways that Americans&#xA;are coming into contact with traditional Hindu culture—whether through practicing&#xA;yoga, through alternative medical systems such as ayurvedic medicine, or through the&#xA;piquant delights of Indian cuisine.&#xA;Despite the growing interchange between Indian and American cultures,&#xA;Hinduism is still often stereotyped and misunderstood. On one hand are the remnants&#xA;of an antiquated point of view that refuses to see the United States as anything but a&#xA;Christian nation. Those holding this view either dismiss Hinduism as an alien or exotic&#xA;set of rituals and beliefs or actively condemn it as idolatrous. On the other hand are&#xA;people searching for an alternative spirituality who idealize Asian cultures as founts of&#xA;ancient wisdom. At the very least, such an uncritical embrace ignores these cultures’&#xA;genuine tensions, problems, and inequities; at the extreme it can result in a “designer&#xA;religion,” in which beliefs and practices from various religious traditions are selec-&#xA;tively adopted, wrenching each of these elements from its roots in a living culture.&#xA;Outright condemnation and idealized acceptance overlook the richness and com-&#xA;plexity of India’s religious and cultural traditions. To gain a genuine understanding, it&#xA;is important that we discern the cultural context behind Hindu beliefs, practices, and&#xA;history. In learning about this context, one quickly encounters familiar ideas: hard&#xA;work, thrift, education, and the importance of the family. Along with these general&#xA;similarities to American cultural values, one finds equally profound differences. To&#xA;examine the nuances of Hindu culture is to enter into a rich and complex world with&#xA;its own inner logic and consistency. Encountering and understanding a different&#xA;world view can throw one’s own into sharper perspective, enriching it with new depth&#xA;and understanding.&#xA;What Is Hinduism?&#xA;The very word Hinduism is misleading. The word was coined by the British as an&#xA;umbrella term, referring to any and all forms of religion in India, many of which share&#xA;few if any common features. It was used to describe all sorts of beliefs and practices,&#xA;from simple nature worship to the most highly sophisticated ritual and philosophical&#xA;systems.&#xA;Hinduism is a vast religious tradition, encompassing various and contradictory&#xA;strands and ideas. It has usually defied all the usual strategies for categorization and&#xA;classification. There is no founder, no definitive scripture, no centralized authority, no&#xA;single supreme god, no creed of essential beliefs, and no heresy. Thus, it would be&#xA;more accurate to think of the religion as Hinduisms rather than Hinduism, since this&#xA;would reflect the rich diversity one encounters.&#xA;India is a land of contrasts and cultural variety. The subcontinent contains almost&#xA;every type of environmental ecosystem, the inhabitants of each possessing their own&#xA;local and regional culture. There are over a dozen distinct languages, each of which&#xA;establishes and nourishes a regional identity that many Indians maintain with great&#xA;care wherever they live. The combinations of language, regional identity, sectarian&#xA;affiliation, and social status have given rise to overwhelming variation. For Hindus,&#xA;diversity is a basic trait of Hindu life, and thus one person’s practice may be very dif-&#xA;ferent from another’s. This has given Hinduism little in the way of centralized&#xA;doctrine or dogma, but its grounding in everyday life has made it extraordinarily&#xA;resilient and adaptable.&#xA;viiBasic Beliefs&#xA;Hinduism is first and foremost a way of life. This means that Hinduism has tended to&#xA;be orthoprax (stressing correct behavior) rather than orthodox (stressing correct&#xA;belief). It tends to be woven through the differing elements of everyday life, rather&#xA;than only performed as practices or rituals for certain days and times. Hindu religious&#xA;expression is conveyed through every facet of society: music, dance, art and architec-&#xA;ture, philosophy, politics, literature, and social life.&#xA;Some of the most important aspects of everyday life in the Hindu tradition are a&#xA;person’s family and social affiliations. Despite the incredible variety of Hindu belief&#xA;and practice, each family and local community is tightly and carefully organized.&#xA;Every individual, as a member of a particular family, has a well-defined role and an&#xA;obligation to fulfill specific duties. As in any culture, one’s individual identity is&#xA;strongly shaped by the linguistic, regional, or sectarian characteristics of his or her&#xA;family. This familial influence persists whether the family lives in its ancestral home or&#xA;moves to a different region of India or a foreign country.&#xA;Families, of course, are members of a larger community. These communities share&#xA;certain beliefs about a person’s proper role in society based on status, age, and gender.&#xA;Traditional Indian society was sharply hierarchical. According to the traditional social&#xA;groupings, there should be four status groups: the brahmins, who are scholars and&#xA;religious technicians; the kshatriyas, who are warriors and rulers; the vaishyas, who&#xA;are artisans and farmers; and the shudras, who serve the others. Each person is born&#xA;as a permanent member of a particular group. Society is seen as an organic whole, in&#xA;which some parts have higher status than others, but every part is necessary for the&#xA;whole to function smoothly. A common metaphor for social organization is the&#xA;human body, which has many different parts performing many different functions, all&#xA;of which are necessary for the body’s maintenance and well-being. In actual practice,&#xA;the picture was far more complex. Each of these four groups was split into hundreds&#xA;of subgroups known as jatis. Jatis were most often identified with a certain hereditary&#xA;occupation, and a jati’s status in a particular place was subject to all kinds of local vari-&#xA;ables. These variables could include whether or not members of a jati owned land or&#xA;the degree to which a jati’s occupation was economically vital to its community.&#xA;These beliefs about social status are becoming less important in modern India,&#xA;and have even less importance for Hindus who live abroad. In modern India, society&#xA;is still functionally divided into four groups: brahmins; “forward castes,” which tend to&#xA;control land, money, or power; “backward castes,” which have historically had very&#xA;little influence, although the situation is changing rapidly; and Dalits (“oppressed”).&#xA;Once called “untouchables,” many Dalits live in poverty and oppressive social condi-&#xA;tions. Except for the brahmins, these social divisions bear little relationship to the four&#xA;groups in the earlier model.&#xA;Reincarnation is still a pervasive belief within Hinduism, as it is in other Indian&#xA;religions such as Jainism, Buddhism, and Sikhism. Almost all Hindus have generally&#xA;accepted that although our bodies are transient, our souls are immortal. After the&#xA;death of a particular body, the soul will inhabit a different body. The nature of one’s&#xA;incarnation in a future life is determined by the quantity and quality of one’s karma.&#xA;Karma literally means “action,” but it also can be generated by words or even thoughts.&#xA;It is not produced only by the things one does or says, but also by one’s underlying&#xA;motives. An individual’s good karma will bring a favorable rebirth in heaven as a god&#xA;or on earth as a wealthy or high-caste human being. Bad karma will bring an unfavor-&#xA;able rebirth. A person’s current social status reveals how properly he or she lived in the&#xA;previous life. The notion of karmic rewards and punishments is a central justification&#xA;for the traditional social hierarchy in India.&#xA;Karma is thought of as a purely physical process, like gravity, operating without&#xA;any need for a divine overseer. An action one performs, for good or for ill, is seen as&#xA;viiithe cause, with the future reward or punishment as the effect. Some of these con-&#xA;sequences occur in this life, while others occur in future lives. Since karma reflects&#xA;the overall tone of one’s life, it is comparable to the notion of a person’s “character”:&#xA;Both are formed over a long period of time, both are measures of the whole person,&#xA;and both reflect how our habitual ways of feeling, thinking, and acting tend to&#xA;shape who we are.&#xA;It is tempting to envision reincarnation as an opportunity to rectify past mistakes&#xA;or to learn lessons still unlearned. For Hindus, as for Buddhists, Sikhs, and Jains, noth-&#xA;ing could be further from the truth; reincarnation is never seen as an opportunity, but&#xA;invariably as a burden. This is because all states of being, both good and bad, are ulti-&#xA;mately impermanent and thus provide no sure refuge. Even the gods, who are enjoy-&#xA;ing the rewards of their past actions, will be born elsewhere when their stored merit is&#xA;exhausted. Others are enduring punishment for their sins, but when this is done they&#xA;will be reborn elsewhere.&#xA;Although most Hindus would grant that liberation from reincarnation (moksha) is&#xA;the ultimate goal, traditional Hindu culture has sanctioned three other goals, all of&#xA;which are more compatible with a normal life in society: the search for pleasure&#xA;(kama); the quest for wealth, fame, and power (artha); and, above all, the search for a&#xA;righteous, balanced life (dharma). This stress on multiple goals reflects the flexibility&#xA;of Hindu religious life. Each person can pursue different goals according to his or her&#xA;inclinations, although certain goals are considered to be more appropriate for partic-&#xA;ular stages of life. In this way a person is free to express his or her individual religious&#xA;identity, although that identity is inevitably shaped by forces arising from a larger&#xA;familial, social, and cultural context.&#xA;The Roots of Hinduism&#xA;The influences and developments of Hinduism are as expansive as the roots and&#xA;branches of a banyan tree. A banyan tree is unusual in that in addition to the tree’s&#xA;upward spreading branches, it also has branches that grow down, take root, and&#xA;become trunks in their own right. An old banyan tree can be hundreds of feet in diam-&#xA;eter, and it is often difficult to discern which is the original trunk. In the same way, the&#xA;religion that we call Hinduism is constantly evolving. New religious forms arise from&#xA;the older ones, while many of the older ones continue to exist. Despite Hinduism’s&#xA;complex origins, its religious history can be roughly divided into six periods, corre-&#xA;sponding to the development of varying religious tendencies and ideas.&#xA;The earliest and most mysterious of these is the period of the Indus Valley&#xA;Civilization, named for the large ruined cities found throughout the Indus Valley and&#xA;beyond. The ruins of prominently placed storage granaries indicate that the civiliza-&#xA;tion’s economic base was agricultural, and the striking uniformity of the ruins of these&#xA;cities leads one to believe that the people were bound by some strong central author-&#xA;ity. Archaeologists have recovered a wealth of physical artifacts, revealing a great deal&#xA;about the layout of the cities, what the inhabitants ate and wore, and the animals they&#xA;domesticated. At the same time, nothing is certain about the religious life of these&#xA;people, although certain artifacts have raised intriguing speculations. It is not even&#xA;known whether the religion and culture of the Indus Valley Civilization have contin-&#xA;ued to affect Indian culture, although some scholars have been more inclined to infer&#xA;this than others.&#xA;This culture seemed to lose its vitality sometime around 2000 B.C.E. Within a few&#xA;centuries it had largely disappeared from the Indus Valley, although it remained vital&#xA;for much longer in outlying regions, particularly Gujarat. According to some theories,&#xA;its decline was the result of a prolonged drought. The latter part of its decline was&#xA;marked by the arrival of the Aryans. This brought Hinduism into its second period of&#xA;religious history. The Aryans were a nomadic cattle-herding people whose earliest reli-&#xA;gious text, the Rg Veda, is believed to have been preserved unchanged for almost four&#xA;ixthousand years. The later strata of the Vedas were composed as the Aryans moved&#xA;through the Punjab into the Ganges basin. These later parts of the Vedas included the&#xA;Brahmana literature, which stressed the importance of sacrifice, and the later&#xA;Aranyakas and Upanishads, which tended to focus on more speculative and philo-&#xA;sophical questions. During the period in which the Aranyakas and Upanishads were&#xA;composed, asceticism became an increasingly important element of Hinduism.&#xA;Asceticism denotes the use of physical discipline and deprivation as a way to attain&#xA;religious insight and liberate the soul from the cycle of reincarnation. Part of the rea-&#xA;son for asceticism’s prominence was the growth of competing groups, such as the Jains&#xA;and the Buddhists, whose monks lived an ascetic life. Asceticism has had an important&#xA;place in Indian religious life since that time.&#xA;The period after the composition of the Vedic literature is sometimes called the&#xA;Epic period. Between roughly 300 B.C.E. and 500 C.E., many of the ideas most impor-&#xA;tant to classical Hinduism were developed and codified. This time was marked by the&#xA;initial composition of the two great Hindu epics, the Ramayana and the&#xA;Mahabharata, although their final revisions came centuries later. The early part of&#xA;this period also saw the composition of the religious literature known as the Kalpa&#xA;Sutras. In theory, each Kalpa Sutra had three parts: a shrauta sutra, a grhya sutra, and&#xA;a dharma sutra, but this neat ordering is belied by the scarcity of complete three-part&#xA;collections, and the abundance of one or another of these sections without its corre-&#xA;sponding parts. Shrauta sutras are manuals for Vedic sacrifice, which had become so&#xA;complex that additional reference material was needed. The shrauta sutra is the only&#xA;element of the three that has not retained great importance in modern Hindu life.&#xA;The grhya sutras are manuals for domestic sacrifices, which include the life-cycle&#xA;rites known as samskaras. Some elements of the grhya sutras still remain vital and&#xA;vibrant parts of modern Hindu religious life, probably because of their connection&#xA;with the central transitions in human life: birth, marriage, and death. The dharma&#xA;sutras provide prescriptions for an organized and stable society by means of a rigid&#xA;social hierarchy. The prescriptions in the dharma sutras were later expanded in the&#xA;dharma shastras, which are the theoretical basis of the Hindu social structure.&#xA;Aside from the epics and the Kalpa Sutras, this period was also notable for the&#xA;development of the six classical philosophical schools: the Nyaya, Vaisheshika,&#xA;Samkhya, Yoga, Mimamsa, and Vedanta (although the defining figure in the Vedanta&#xA;school, Shankaracharya, is generally dated in the early ninth century). The philo-&#xA;sophical system developed by each of these six schools had a common goal: liberat-&#xA;ing the soul from the bondage of reincarnation. Each of the schools believed that the&#xA;soul could be liberated by avoiding conceptual errors and apprehending universal&#xA;truths, although there was considerable disagreement about the nature of these uni-&#xA;versal truths. The foundational texts for each of these schools laid out their basic&#xA;philosophical position; in some cases, these texts buttressed their position by&#xA;appealing to authoritative religious texts such as the Vedas. Over the following cen-&#xA;turies these foundational texts received further elaboration through multiple layers&#xA;of commentaries, which in some cases have continued to be written almost up until&#xA;contemporary times.&#xA;This period is also marked by the rise in importance of the deities Shiva, Vishnu,&#xA;and the Goddess, who are still the primary deities worshiped in modern Hinduism.&#xA;These deities had a central place in the sectarian literature known as the puranas,&#xA;another of the important types of text composed in this period. The puranas’ most&#xA;notable feature is their sectarian character, as they often exalt one particular deity over&#xA;the others. They also include information on many other aspects of religious life,&#xA;including sacred places, sacred times, instructions for various religious rites, and even&#xA;descriptions of the heavens and hells. The final type of religious text first composed in&#xA;this period were the tantras, which laid out esoteric and often hidden ritual traditions.&#xA;xIn later times, both the puranas and the tantras have been the subject of extensive&#xA;commentaries. In addition, this period saw the development of new artistic and archi-&#xA;tectural styles. Many of the forces manifested or formed in this period remain integral&#xA;parts of contemporary Hindu life.&#xA;The period following this was marked by the growth and flowering of the devo-&#xA;tional (bhakti) tradition, which for more than a millennium has been one of the most&#xA;powerful religious forces in Hindu culture. Bhakti stresses the necessity of a direct and&#xA;personal relationship with God, in whatever form that deity is conceived. Its propo-&#xA;nents tended to be contemptuous of the neatly constructed social order detailed in&#xA;the dharma shastras, which stressed birth rather than devotional capacity as the most&#xA;important criterion. Much of medieval Hindu thought was formed out of the tension&#xA;between these two competing ideals, dharma and bhakti, and there was often no easy&#xA;resolution of the conflict between their differing perspectives.&#xA;The growing presence of Europeans in India marked the next period in&#xA;Hinduism’s history. Although there had been a European presence in India since the&#xA;mid-1500s, when the Portuguese colonized Goa, the introduction of British colonists&#xA;presented the greatest challenge to Indian society. In the early 1600s, the British East&#xA;India Company gained its first foothold with a trading station at Surat in modern&#xA;Gujarat and gradually put down additional roots in Bombay, Madras, and the Bengal&#xA;region. With the effective collapse of the Moghul empire in the mid-1700s, the nobil-&#xA;ity that ruled peripheral regions such as Bengal began to function independently. This&#xA;allowed the British to displace the indigenous rulers as the political authorities and&#xA;the recipients of land revenue. The East India Company was a commercial venture,&#xA;and its primary goal was to make money for its shareholders. Yet the Indian body&#xA;politic was so fragmented that the company encountered little effective resistance&#xA;and aggressively expanded its sphere of influence from Bengal up the Ganges River&#xA;valley and into central India. In some cases the company would simply absorb small&#xA;kingdoms under the pretense of protecting law and order, especially when the leader-&#xA;ship had no clear line of succession. In other cases it would make agreements with&#xA;local nobility to create small princely states, some of which survived until Indian inde-&#xA;pendence in 1947. General discontent with the company’s aggressive expansion&#xA;finally exploded in the rebellion of 1857–58, after which India was governed as part of&#xA;the British Empire.&#xA;The company was primarily driven by economic motives, but it justified its pater-&#xA;nal presence by portraying the Indians as unable to govern themselves effectively.&#xA;Although the company’s policy was not to interfere with its subjects’ religious lives,&#xA;since any such tensions would be bad for business, the company’s board of directors&#xA;in England was under strong domestic pressure to open up their dominions to&#xA;Christian missionary activity. Contemporary missionary polemics against Hinduism&#xA;usually stressed repugnant practices such as sati (the burning of a widow on her hus-&#xA;band’s funeral pyre), child marriage, the pitiable plight of many widows, or Hindu&#xA;“idolatry.” Such political and religious critiques assumed the implicit superiority of&#xA;European Christian culture and provided the moral sanction for colonialism that&#xA;Rudyard Kipling described as the “white man’s burden.”&#xA;Hindus responded to these critiques in several ways. The most violent response&#xA;came in the rebellion of 1857–58, in which popular discontent led various groups to&#xA;try to drive the British out of India. Although there was widespread opposition to&#xA;British rule, it was never unified, allowing the British to defeat their adversaries one by&#xA;one. A far more effective response came in religious terms, as progressive Hindus&#xA;attempted to respond to the missionary critiques. One result of this was the formation&#xA;of various societies, such as the Brahmo Samaj, Prarthana Samaj, and Arya Samaj. The&#xA;first two of these attempted to reform Hindu religious life by removing certain offen-&#xA;sive practices in response to criticism from outsiders. These practices included the&#xA;xicaste system, child marriage, and the ban on widow remarriage. The Arya Samaj was&#xA;formed to regenerate and revitalize Hinduism, with the explicit position that&#xA;Hinduism was far superior to Christianity and Islam.&#xA;The end of the nineteenth century was also marked by the gradual establishment&#xA;of Hinduism as a viable religious tradition in the West, as Hindu teachers arrived in&#xA;Europe and America. Some of the early figures were Swami Vivekananda and&#xA;Paramahamsa Yogananda, and the more recent ones are Prabhupada, Muktananda,&#xA;Yogi Bhajan, Guru Maharaj Ji, Krishnamurti, and Shri Chinmoy. This recent group of&#xA;teachers had an explicit missionary goal, aiming to gain followers among native-born&#xA;Europeans and Americans.&#xA;The most recent period in the development of Hindu religious traditions is&#xA;marked by the emigration of Indians to America. Many Indians have settled abroad&#xA;seeking education or to pursue specialized careers. They have established centers of&#xA;Hindu worship, like the temple Aurora, to serve the needs of the Indian community,&#xA;including the need to pass on a sense of Hindu identity to their children. Yet despite&#xA;their efforts to preserve their traditions and culture, their very presence in a different&#xA;society is causing changes in their religious lives. American society has made certain&#xA;traditions more difficult to preserve. For example, the community often celebrates&#xA;religious festivals on the weekend following the traditional festival day, since this is&#xA;when people have more spare time. Life in American society and the influence of&#xA;American values have also made it difficult to conform to certain traditional patterns.&#xA;The traditional requirement that Hindus marry within their jati has been assailed both&#xA;by the American emphasis on the importance of a “love marriage” and by the poten-&#xA;tial shortage of suitable partners. In the same way, certain dietary restrictions become&#xA;harder to maintain but have greater complexity. A Hindu in America must decide not&#xA;only if he or she should simply avoid eating beef but also whether to avoid any place&#xA;where beef is served.&#xA;In India, the twentieth century has been marked by the development of an&#xA;assertive and militant Hindu nationalism. Hindu nationalism’s “founding father” was&#xA;V. D. Savarkar, but the most important body promoting this idea in the recent past has&#xA;been the Rashtriya Svayamsevak Sangh (RSS). The RSS is the mother organization for&#xA;many different affiliates, ranging from labor unions to student organizations to social&#xA;relief bodies. Its two most important affiliates for promoting Hindu nationalism are&#xA;the Vishva Hindu Parishad (VHP), a religious organization, and the Bharatiya Janata&#xA;Party (BJP), a mass-based political party. In the early 1990s, both organizations were&#xA;instrumental in radical Hindu politics, particularly in the destruction of a mosque&#xA;alleged to have been built on the site of the god Rama’s birthplace in the North Indian&#xA;city of Ayodhya. Since that time, the VHP has retained its radical edge, but the BJP has&#xA;not. The BJP has put greater distance between itself and the VHP, seeking to move&#xA;toward the political center and thus expand its reach in electoral politics. It has begun&#xA;stressing issues that are vital to a broader spectrum of Hindu voters, such as corrup-&#xA;tion and the rising cost of living.&#xA;This encyclopedia offers the student of religion a place to begin exploring the key&#xA;elements of Hindu religious culture and practice. I hope that the entries will be a&#xA;springboard for further study of this great, living religious tradition.&#xA;xiiHow to Use This Book&#xA;This encyclopedia includes the following features:&#xA;•The Contents by Subject lists related entries in the following categories: Art,&#xA;Architecture, and Iconography; Astrology and Cosmology; Biographical Entries;&#xA;Calendar and Time; Ceremonies, Practices, and Rituals; Communities, Groups,&#xA;and Organizations; Dance; Dynasties; Geography; Literature, Language, and&#xA;Drama; Medicine, Physiology, and Alchemy; Music, Hymns, and Prayers;&#xA;Mythology and Beliefs; Philosophy and Logic; and Yoga and Tantra.&#xA;•Cross-referenced terms within entries are indicated in boldface type.&#xA;•Parenthetical citations are used to refer to selections from primary Hindu texts.&#xA;For sources from the Vedas, the first number refers to the book and the second to&#xA;the hymn. For later sources, including the Upanishads, the Bhagavad Gita, and all&#xA;of the dharma literature, the first number refers to the chapter and the second to&#xA;the verse.&#xA;•Lineage charts for characters in the Hindu epics the Mahabharata and the&#xA;Ramayana appear on pages 401 and 556, respectively.&#xA;•Words with distinctive pronunciations are listed in the back of the book with&#xA;diacritical marks—symbols above or below the letters to indicate their&#xA;proper pronunciation.&#xA;•Abbreviated bibliographic citations appear at the end of some entries. The full&#xA;citations are grouped together in the bibliography.&#xA;Note on Dates&#xA;In many cases, determining dates for the lives of Indian figures is problematic&#xA;because there are not good records for many figures, even in comparatively modern&#xA;times. The most definite dates tend to be from inscriptions, and thus this evidence is&#xA;best for kings and others who were able to commission inscriptions. Philosophers,&#xA;devotional poets, and writers often could not. In this book, a question mark follows&#xA;dates that scholars have determined by inference (for example, based on internal&#xA;evidence in texts, such as references to historical events) but are not backed up by&#xA;documentary evidence.&#xA;xiii&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
