<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Battle offering</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/battle-offering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/battle-offering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/GraniRau/status/1281169049431552000&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gizurr&#34;&gt;Gizurr&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;we offer you battle. On the downs of Dun-heath and in Dylgia-vales I bid y…&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Afraid are your hosts, fey is your leader&lt;br&gt;&#xA;You have angered Óthin: we offer you battle  .&#xA;On the downs of Dun-heath and in Dylgia-vales&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I bid you battle, ’neath the Iassar-fells’ brow  .&#xA;May Óthin o’erawe Angantýr’s foes&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and may this spear fly o’er you as I do bid it.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;-Hlöðskviða&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Geatish king Gizurr inviting the Huns to come fight the Goths. Hloth (half brother of Gothic king Angantyr) wants to attack Gizurr, who rode up to the Huns and shouted this, but the Hun king Humli refuses, because it is dishonorable to harm a messenger. Gizurr was all for war.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trollaukin</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/trollaukin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/trollaukin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://x.com/Sagnamadr/status/1966980021916233835&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Trollaukin: further insight into berserkrgangr.&#xA;As late as the 19th century, a practice that was forbidden in Icelandic wrestling (Glíma) was trollaukin; a term meaning “possession by trolls/spirits”, with the intent of gaining increased strength and fighting ability.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Jón Árnason, an invocation would be said, such as “Stand by me, my troll!”, or “Stand by me fiend/troll, now possessing me!”. By this time, “troll” had become a blanket term for all manner of supernatural entities, especially those who aided in sorcery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>wayland</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/wayland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/wayland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wayland lives as a nomadic hunter with his two brothers. One day while passing by a lake, they find three beautiful swan-maidens (women who can turn into swans). They are walkirries. The brothers each take a wife, and they settle down in a valley.&#xA;They live happily for nine years, but increasingly the swan-maidens are troubled by their abstention from their duty, namely to preside over battles for Woden. A winter day when the brothers are out hunting, they fly away.&#xA;The three return and find the halls deserted. The two brothers travel in different directions to find their wives, but Wayland alone stays. He forges golden armlets for his wife, and gets increasingly depressed.&#xA;Somehow the neighbouring tyrant Nithad learns about him, and in the night goes with his heavily armed troupe to Wayland&amp;rsquo;s house. He sees the rings, and takes a single one for his daughter.&#xA;Wayland returns with a caught she-bear to roast, and as he sits by the hearth-fire he counts his rings. He finds that one is missing, and thinks that it might be his wife who is come back. He falls asleep weeping, looking into the fire.&#xA;When he wakes he is bound, and asks who has bound him. Nithad asks him where he stole the gold, but Wayland replies that he&amp;rsquo;d give all of it to see his wife and brothers again. When Nithad’s cunning wife sees him being taken out of the forest to the royal residency she is frightened, and so tells him to hamstring him and place him on a small island.&#xA;Wayland is forced to stay on the island, forging jewelry and weapons for Nithad. One day the two sons of Nithad (affectionately called his ‘bear-cubs’) go to the island to see the rings. Wayland tells them to return another day, and they wake up early, excited for the trip. When they arrive and look into the chest, he beheads them, and then makes bowls out of their skulls, gemstones out of their eyes and brooches out of their jaws, which Nithad gives to his wife and daughter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
