<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;03 Devotees and Deities on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/03_Devotees_and_Deities/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;03 Devotees and Deities on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/03_Devotees_and_Deities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>09 Raising Snakes in Bengal</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/03_Devotees_and_Deities/09_Raising_Snakes_in_Bengal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/03_Devotees_and_Deities/09_Raising_Snakes_in_Bengal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Raising Snakes in Bengal: The Use of Tantric Imagery  in Sakta Poetry Contests&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rachel Fell McDermott&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What is Tantra in Bengal? The Sanskrit Tantras important to the region since the  fifteenth century list several central elements: selection of the proper teacher;  initiation; mantra repetition; fire worship; construction of mystic diagrams (yan tras); image worship; the honoring of young girls as embodiments of the Goddess;  cremation-ground rituals performed to gain mastery over death; and the notorious  &amp;ldquo;five M&amp;rdquo; ritual, in which wine, fish, meat, a type of intoxicating grain, and sexual  intercourse (these are the makaras, all of whose Sanskrit and Bengali names begin  with M) are used in controlled ritual circumstances - either literally (the hero&amp;rsquo;s  way), through comestible alternatives (the bestial way), or by enjoying mental  substitutes (the divine way). Meditative techniques are also crucial to Tantra. The  most famous of these is kundalini yoga, or the practice of raising the serpent  power through the seven lotus-shaped spiritual centers in the body (cakras) to  the top of the head, where she unites with her consort Siva. Each of these cakras - muladhara (at the base of the spine), svadhisthana (at the genitals), manipura (at  the navel), anahata (at the heart), visuddha (in the throat), ajna (between the  eyebrows), and sahasrara (at the top of the head) - has a different number of  petals, with letters of the alphabet engraved on them, and is assigned a resident  god, goddess, animal, element, one-syllabled mantra, and sound to be enjoyed as  one passes through it. These lotuses are strung on a subtle channel called the  susumna, &amp;ldquo;the path of knowledge&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;the path to liberation.&amp;rdquo; Flanking it are two  more channels, the ida to the left, symbolized by the moon, and the pingala to  the right, which represents the sun, whose influence is said to be poisonous,  causing attachment to the senses. Especially significant are the beginning, middle,  and end points of the journey: the muladhara, where the serpentine kundalini  lies coiled three and a half times around the Siva linga, waiting to be awakened  and induced to enter the door to the susumna; the anahata, where the Goddess  is installed and visualized in the heart; and the sahasrara, where Siva and Sakti,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 The Wedding of Siva and the Goddess</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/03_Devotees_and_Deities/10_The_Wedding_of_Siva_and_the_Goddess/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/03_Devotees_and_Deities/10_The_Wedding_of_Siva_and_the_Goddess/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Wedding of Siva and the Goddess&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;in the Kulalikamnaya&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Teun Goudriaan&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In our endeavor to understand the Hindu scriptural tradition in its astounding  variety, we have to set up a number of distinctions as guidelines for our analysis.  But such distinctions should not be understood as so many watertight compart ments, because these hardly ever exist in Hindu religiosity. Two instances of such  analytical preliminaries are the distinction between &amp;ldquo;ideology&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;practice&amp;rdquo; in  the Tantric traditions, and that between &amp;ldquo;Tantric&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Puranic&amp;rdquo; religiosities or  literary traditions. The translated Sanskrit text presented below, Kulalikamnaya  3.1-39 (this is the main version of the Kubjikamata Tantra [KMT]), provides.a  good illustration of their relative validity. It contains a version, admittedly unique,  of one of the best-known myths of the Epic-Puranic religious tradition; and it  firmly connects mythological timelessness with the psychosomatic realization of  spiritual truth and power which is the goal of Devi&amp;rsquo;s rebirths&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 An Advertised Secret: The Goddess Taleju and the King of Kathmandu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/03_Devotees_and_Deities/11_An_Advertised_Secret_The_Goddess_Taleju_and_the_King_of_Kathmandu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/03_Devotees_and_Deities/11_An_Advertised_Secret_The_Goddess_Taleju_and_the_King_of_Kathmandu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bronwen Bledsoe&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The text presented here is an inscription from Nepal, a praise-poem named Sar vaparadhastotra, which King Pratap Malla had hammered into the golden doors  of the temple of the Tantric goddess Taleju in the middle of the seventeenth  century. A public and literary text, the Sarvaparadhastotra offers a concise - if  difficult - instance of Tantra&amp;rsquo;s deployment in one historically specific social  world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mise-en-scene&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In late medieval Nepal, the temple of the goddess Taleju commanded the skyline  of the city-kingdom of Kathmandu, while her principal servants - rulers of a  dynasty named Malla - commanded the world of the Newar people. No structure  in the realm could be build higher than the goddess&amp;rsquo;s imposing temple in the  royal palace at the heart of the mandala-patterned city-kingdom. The Tantric  goddess Taleju was literally and conceptually the most exalted being of the realm.  No one could miss the fact of the goddess&amp;rsquo;s existence or her power, yet access to  her sanctuary was jealously restricted. Full initiation into the method of her wor ship amounted to consecration into kingship itself in the late Malla period (ca.  1600-1768 C.E.).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Tantric Rites in Antal&#39;s Poetry</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/03_Devotees_and_Deities/12_Tantric_Rites_in_Antals_Poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/03_Devotees_and_Deities/12_Tantric_Rites_in_Antals_Poetry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;D. Dennis Hudson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Shoot me into Krsna,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Antal told desire,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and performed the rites that made it happen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The poet known as Antal, who called herself Goda, lived in the early ninth cen tury, in the deep south of the Indian subcontinent. She performed Tantric rites  of the Bhagavatas and described them in her poems, excerpts of which follow.  Bhagavata theology and the stories of her life will introduce them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
