<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Tolerance - Sanderson on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Tolerance - Sanderson on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00 Comments</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/00_Comments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/00_Comments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-of-the-authors-thesis&#34;&gt;Summary of the author&amp;rsquo;s thesis&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bulk of the paper is about presenting shaiva view about vaidika-s (and - to a much lesser extant - vice versa), and shakily foisting a thesis of &amp;ldquo;absence of inherent tolerance&amp;rdquo; on to various Hindu traditions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the juridical view that all religions other than those considered criminal or subversive should be accepted by the state, and the evidence of royal patronage extended  to religious traditions other than those to which monarchs claimed to be especially devoted suggest that there was indeed a high degree of official tolerance of  religious diversity to be found in the various states of early mediaeval India. But the evidence presented above also shows that this tolerance was not innate to the individual traditions that had been absorbed, however incompletely, into this  consensus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Introduction</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/03_Introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/03_Introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is generally believed that already in the early mediaeval period from the fifth century of the Christian era onwards, if not earlier, there existed a single Hindu religion, embracing Vaidika orthopraxy in accordance with primary and secondary Vedic revelation (Śruti and Smr̥ti) together with the sectarian traditions of the worship of Viṣṇu, Śiva, Devī, and the Sun God (Sūrya), to mention only the foremost among the deities that attracted personal devotion, that is to say, those whose worship is attested not only in countless temples surviving from that period in the Indian subcontinent and much of South East Asia but also in numerous donative inscriptions and extensive bodies of prescriptive literature. It is also widely believed that this complex unity displays an exemplary degree of religious tolerance, not only between Vaidikas, Vaiṣṇavas, Śaivas, Śāktas, and Sauras, but also between these and the followers of the other two major Indian faiths of the age, namely Buddhism and Jainism.1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Vaidika Exclusivity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/04_Vaidika_Exclusivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/04_Vaidika_Exclusivity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let us now begin by looking at the extremes that reject or contradict this unity.  Any claim that tolerance of religious diversity is at the heart of Hinduism must overlook the view of the Vaidikas, whose theoreticians flatly denied the validity of any religious practice that was undertaken on the authority of texts lying outside the Veda (vedabāhyāni), that is to say, outside the Vaidika scriptural corpus of Śruti and such secondary literature (Smr̥ti) as was accepted to derive from it. Thus in the ninth or tenth century Medhātithi 6 states in his erudite commentary on the Manusmr̥ti: 7&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 The Śaivas’ Inclusivist View of Their Own and the Vaidikas’ Religion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/05_The_shaivas_Inclusivist_View_of_Their_Own_and_the_Vaidikas_Religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/05_The_shaivas_Inclusivist_View_of_Their_Own_and_the_Vaidikas_Religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As for the Śaivas, they likewise seem to undermine the unity of Hinduism by insisting not merely on the validity of their own scriptures but also on their superiority to the Vaidika scriptures and indeed to the scriptures of all non-Śaiva systems. This was already so in the earliest known Śaiva initiatory system, that of the  Pāñcārthika Pāśupatas of the Atimārga, whose ascetic initiates were to see themselves as having severed all ties with the Vaidika religion, leaving behind their former obligations to the gods and ancestors to focus their devotion on Śiva/ Rudra alone;33 and it continued to be so in the Mantramārga, even though this  later form of the religion, in evidence from about 450–550 onwards, expanded  the community of the initiated beyond that of ascetics, important though they  continued to be, by opening up initiation to householders, allowing them, indeed requiring them, to remain in this status after they had received initiation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 The Properly Śaiva Attitude of Śaivas Towards Their Vaidika Rites</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/06_The_Properly_shaiva_Attitude_of_shaivas_Towards_Their_Vaidika_Rites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/06_The_Properly_shaiva_Attitude_of_shaivas_Towards_Their_Vaidika_Rites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now this extension from the purely Śaiva domain of the ascetic in the Atimārga  into the Vaidika domain of the Śaiva householder added in the Mantramārga  opened the door to a process of Śaiva-Vaidika hybridization, in which rites of  both kinds were maintained and co-ordinated without a proper sense of their  distinctness. The Śaivas’ theoreticians, aware that this development had the  potential to produce a blurring of the boundary between the two domains  that would undermine the faith of Śaivas in the independence and supremacy  of Śaivism, ruled that while initiated Śaiva householders were thus subject to  two bodies of injunction – both the Śaiva and the Vaidika – their attitude  towards adherence to the latter was to differ fundamentally from that of the  Vaidikas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 The Śākta-Śaiva Attitude Towards Vaidika Observance Among Initiates</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/07_The_shAkta-shaiva_Attitude_Towards_Vaidika_Observance_Among_Initiates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/07_The_shAkta-shaiva_Attitude_Towards_Vaidika_Observance_Among_Initiates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The view seen in the Sarvajñānottara that the Śaiva should conform to Vaid ika injunction only for the sake of others tended not to be emphasised in the later Saiddhāntika exegetical literature, which seems to be more eager to stress  conformity with Vaidika injunctions than to justify this from a properly Śaiva standpoint. But the Śākta-Śaiva scholars of such traditions as the Krama and  Trika, whose ritual practice was further distanced from Vaidika norms than the Saiddhāntikas’, preserved a strong emphasis on Śaivism’s transcendence,46 even arguing that the true reason for conformity with Vaidika observance was spiritual immaturity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 The Loss of Transcendence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/08_The_Loss_of_Transcendence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/08_The_Loss_of_Transcendence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This double religion, combining the Vaidika religion and Śaivism under royal  authority, was from the point of view of all Śaiva theoreticians a two-tiered hierarchy with Śaivism on top and the Vaidika religion below. The theoreticians’  ahistorical and fundamentalist presentation depicts no overlap between the two  levels, no encroachment of one upon the other, or rather it uses theory to outlaw  any such encroachment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, when we see that the Vaidika domain has been so comprehen sively accommodated we are bound to look for evidence of a weakening of the  orthoprax Vaidikas’ rejection of Śaivism and also of a commensurate adoption  by Śaivas themselves of a view of their religion that surrendered the doctrine of  its transcendence. We may well imagine Śaivas who had abandoned all sense of  their religion as a path above the Vaidika, who saw themselves simply as Śaivas  by birth, who claimed for their scriptures no more than that they apply to them  as Śaivas, that there is nothing special about initiation, that it is merely a rite  of passage into ritual activities peculiar to their group, and that these activities  are much like the practices of other groups, Vaiṣṇava and orthoprax Vaidika, of  similar social standing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Jayanta</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/09_Jayanta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/09_Jayanta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We do indeed find evidence of both these developments. The earliest appears on the  Vaidika side near the end of the ninth century in the Nyāyamañjarī of the Kashmirian  philosopher Bhaṭṭa Jayanta, minister of king Śaṇkaravarman (r. c. ad 883–902) and  author of the Āgamaḍambara, the humorous play about the religious tensions of the  day that I have cited above. He states that he undertook the monumental Nyāya-mañjarī in order to protect the authority of the Vedas; and this commitment is apparent throughout.61&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Bhaṭṭa Rāmakaṇṭha II’s Śaivas without Pride of Transcendence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/10_bhaTTa_rAmakaNTha_IIs_shaivas_without_Pride_of_Transcendence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/10_bhaTTa_rAmakaNTha_IIs_shaivas_without_Pride_of_Transcendence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Having established that Jayanta’s view of Saiddhāntika Śaivism as a valid from of  religion is unlikely to have been a minority view in the general Vaidika population  outside Śaiva circles, we must wonder whether it is likely that this view could  have been as general as he says it was in the absence of Śaivas who subscribed to  it themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are indeed indications that an ideologically emasculated Śaivism of the  kind outlined by Jayanta did exist and therefore that the great Kashmirian Naiyāyika was indeed expressing the view of an already established segment of the Śaivas themselves. Furthermore, we may suspect that this had become the majority view among them, and that the learned theories of the Śaiva theologians, which  demonstrate how Śaivism is superior to the Vaidika religion, how its rituals and  meditations work on an altogether higher level and its doctrines penetrate far beyond the reach of its rival, were not so much articulations of established, common  belief as fundamentalist attempts to revitalize and recover a tradition that was fast losing a sense of its original calling. Thus Bhaṭṭa Rāmakaṇṭha, writing in the tenth  century, when Saiddhāntika learning in Kashmir was at its height, tells us that one  of his reasons for writing his commentary on the Saiddhāntika scripture Mataṅga-pārameśvara was to counteract attempts to draw the understanding of the text  into the Vaidika domain, by going back to the foundational doctrines of Sadyo-jyotis and Br̥haspati and sweeping away what he saw as the inauthentic interpretations of the Siddhānta that had developed since the time of these two founding fathers of Saiddhāntika exegesis.81&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Aparāditya’s Śaivas by Birth</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/11_aparAdityas_shaivas_by_Birth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/11_aparAdityas_shaivas_by_Birth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A comparable situation is revealed by Aparāditya, the Śilāhāra king of North  Konkan, writing in the early twelfth century, through one of the Śaiva arguments  for acceptability that he puts up to refute in in his commentary on Yājñavalkya smr̥ti. The Śaiva is made to argue that since the adherents of the Vaidika religion  hold that the injunctive force of the Veda is directed only to specific, restricted  classes of persons, they can have no reason to deny that the Śaiva scriptures are  valid for Śaivas as members of a similar community of birth, which suggests that  its members, when asked why they engage in their special Śaiva rituals, would  have responded like Georg Bühler’s Śaiva brahmin informants in Kashmir in 1875  that they attached no special importance to them but did them because this was  the long-established custom of their community.84&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Religion and the State: A Maximally Tolerant View of What Is Acceptable in Matters of Religion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/12_Religion_and_the_State_A_Maximally_Tolerant_View_of_What_Is_Acceptable_in_Matters_of_Religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/12_Religion_and_the_State_A_Maximally_Tolerant_View_of_What_Is_Acceptable_in_Matters_of_Religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Jayanta’s play Āgamaḍambara we have seen the uncompromising Vaidika camp  attempt and fail to impose its Manu-inspired vision of a society free of all but  properly Vaidika religion. When the suppression of an extreme fringe cult leads to panic among the Śaivas, the king, a Śaiva himself, not necessarily an initiate  but a publicly declared loyal devotee of Śiva (paramamāheśvaraḥ),93 who had at  the beginning of his reign founded temples for the installation of Śivas whose  names incorporated those of himself (Śaṇkaragaurīśvara) 94 and his chief queen (Sugandheśvara), intervenes and ensures that the status quo is maintained. The  play ends with an orchestrated debate between the Vaidikas and the preceptors  of the other faiths held in the Vaiṣṇava Raṇasvāmin temple in Srinagar on the  subject of whether the Pañcarātra and the scriptures of the other non-Vaidika  systems are or are not valid. In front of an audience of thousands, including the  former Snātaka Saṁkarṣaṇa, now turned ultra-tolerant minister of religious  affairs,95 the Naiyāyika Sāhaṭa, also called Dhairyarāśi, appointed as adjudictor  by the order of the king himself (nr̥pādeśāt), hears the various disputants put their  cases and then delivers his judgement. In this he rejects the narrow Vaidika view  of validity and advocates one with the greatest latitude, stopping short only of approving transgressive, licentious, and violent cults such as were certainly present  in Kashmir and elsewhere at this time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>13 Persecution</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/13_Persecution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/13_Persecution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The emergence of the orthoprax consensus reported by Jayanta and confirmed  by other evidence, in which Vaidikas, Vaiṣṇavas, and Śaivas were seen by others and themselves as equipolent aspects of a single loosely defined faith, the juridical view that all religions other than those considered criminal or subversive should be accepted by the state, and the evidence of royal patronage extended  to religious traditions other than those to which monarchs claimed to be especially devoted suggest that there was indeed a high degree of official tolerance of  religious diversity to be found in the various states of early mediaeval India. But the evidence presented above also shows that this tolerance was not innate to the individual traditions that had been absorbed, however incompletely, into this  consensus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>14 References</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/14_References/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/articles/sanderson_tolerance/14_References/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;texts&#34;&gt;Texts&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Abhidhnaratnaml of Halāyudha, ed. Th. Aufrecht. London: Williams &amp;amp;  Norgate, 1861.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;aṣṭaprakaraṇa, ed. Vrajavallabha Dvivedī. Yogatantra-granthamālā 12. Vara nasi: Sampurnananda Sanskrit University, 1988.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Aṣṭdhyy of Pāṇini → böhtlingk 1887.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Āgamaḍambara of Jayanta → dezső 2005.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Āgamaprmṇya of Yāmunācārya, ed. Rāma Miśra Śāstrī. Varanasi, 1937. Re print from The Pandit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kumraplacaritrasaṅgraha, compiled by Jinavijaya Muni. Siṅghī Jaina  Granthamālā, 41. Bombay: Bharatīya Vidyā Bhavana, 1956.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kularatnoddyota. National Archives, Kathmandu MS 1-16, Nepal-German  Manuscript Preservation Project Reel No. A 206/10; paper; Newari script; manuscript completed on Tuesday, Śrāvaṇa śudi 14, [Nepālasaṁvat] 754 (ad 1634).&#xA;214&#xA;33211 Honoris Causa 3P.indd 214 11/18/15 5:22 PMtolerance, exclusivity, inclusivity, and persecution . . .&#xA;Kr̥ṣṇayamritantra, ed. S. Rinpoche and V. Dwivedi. Rare Buddhist Text&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Series, 9. Sarnath: Central Institute of Higher Tibetan Studies, 1992.&#xA;Jainataraṅgiṇ of Śrīvara = Rājataraṅgiṇī of Śrīvara, Taraṅgas 1–2 in the criti cal edition of Kaul (1966).&#xA;Tantravrttika of Kumārīla, commentary on Śabarasvāmin’s commen&#xA;tary (-bhāṣya) on Mīmāṁsāsūtra 1.2.1 et sqq., ed. Mahāmahopādhyāya Pt.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Gaṅgādhara Śāstrī. Benares Sanskrit Series, 5, 7, 16, 23, 27, 29, 32, 34, 36, 39,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;60, 62, 72. Benares, 1903.&#xA;Tantrasra of Abhinavagupta, ed. Mukund Rām Shāstrī. Kashmir Series of&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Texts and Studies, 17. Bombay, 1918.&#xA;Tantrloka of Abhinavagupta, with the commentary (-viveka) of Rājānaka Ja&#xA;yaratha. Ed. Mukund Ram Sastri. Kashmir Series of Texts and Studies, 23,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;28, 30, 35, 29, 41, 47, 59, 52, 57, 58. Bombay and Srinagar, 1918–38.&#xA;da tang xiyuji of Xuanzang. See Beal 1884 (tr.).&#xA;Davatracarita of Kṣemendra, ed. Durgāprasād and Kāśīnāth Pāṇdurang&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Parab. Kāvyamālā, 26. Bombay: Nirnaya-sāgara Press, 1891.&#xA;Devymata. National Archives, Kathmandu MS 1-279, Nepal-German Manu&#xA;script Preservation Project Reel no. A 41/15 (‘Niśvāsākhyamahātantra’); palm&#xA;leaf; early Newari script; penned in ad 1060.&#xA;Narevaraparkṣ of Sadyojyotis with the commentary (-praka) of Bhaṭṭa&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Rāmakaṇṭha, ed. Madhusudan Kaul Shastri. Kashmir Series of Texts and&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Studies, 45. Srinagar, 1926.&#xA;Narmaml of Kṣemendra → baldissera 2005.&#xA;Nmaliṅgnusana of Amarasiṁha, ed. M. M. Paṇḍit Śivadatta Dādhimatha&lt;br&gt;&#xA;with the commentary (-sudhā) of Bhānujidīkṣita. Brajajivan Prachyabharati&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Granthamala, 1. Delhi: Chaukhamba Sanskrit Pratishthan, 1995. Reprinted&lt;br&gt;&#xA;from the 1915 edition of the Nirnaya Sagar Press, Bombay.&#xA;Nitydisaṁgrahapaddhati, compiled by Rājānaka Takṣakavarta. Pune,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Bhandarkar Oriental Research Institute, MS 76 of 1875–76 (wrongly&lt;br&gt;&#xA;‘Bhr̥ṅgeśasaṁ hitā’); paper; Śāradā script.&#xA;Naimittikakriynusaṁdhna of Brahmaśambhu. Calcutta, Asiatic Society&lt;br&gt;&#xA;of Bengal, MS G 4767: palm-leaf; Newari script; incomplete; undated but&lt;br&gt;&#xA;probably of the eleventh century.&#xA;215&#xA;33211 Honoris Causa 3P.indd 215 11/18/15 5:22 PM&#xA;Honoris Causa&#xA;Nyyabhṣaṇa of Bhāsarvajña, ed. Svāmī Yogīndranātha. Vārāṇasī:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;ṣaḍdarśanaprakā-śanasaṁsthānam, 1968.&#xA;Nyyamañjar of Jayanta with the ṭippaṇi Nyāyasaurabha by the editor. Ed.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;K. S. Varadacharya. 2 vols. Oriental Research Institute Series, 116 and 139.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Mysore: Oriental Research Institute, 1969 and 1983.&#xA;Nyyamañjar-Āgamaprmṇya: Āgamaprāmāṇya section of the Nyāyamañ jarī of Jayanta → kataoka 2004.&#xA;Nyyamañjargranthibhaṅga of Cakradhara, a commentary on the Nyāyamañ&#xA;jarī of Jayanta, 3 vols., ed. Gaurinath Sastri. M.M. Śivakumāraśāstri&#xA;Granthamālā, 5. Varanasi: Bhāgīratha Prasāda Tripāṭhi, 1982–1984.&#xA;Pañcartrarakṣ of Vedāntadeśika, ed. M. Duraiswami Aiyangar and&lt;br&gt;&#xA;T. Venugopalacharya. Adyar Library Series, 36. Madras: Adyar Library, 1942.&#xA;Pañcrtha (=Pāśupatasūtra) with the commentary (pañcrthabhṣya) of&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Bhagavat Kauṇḍinya, ed. R. Anantakrishna Sastri. Trivandrum Sanskrit Se ries, 143. Trivandrum: University of Travancore, 1940.&#xA;Partriṁikvivaraṇa of Abhinavagupta → gnoli 1985.&#xA;Puratnaprabandhasaṁgraha, compiled by Jinavijaya Muni. Singhi Jaina&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Series, 2. Calcutta: Adhiṣṭhātā-Siṅghī Jaina Jñānapīṭha, 1936.&#xA;Pryacittasamuccaya of Trilocanaśiva. Institut français de Pondichéry,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Manuscript Transcript no. 1060.&#xA;Br̥hatsaṁhit of Varāhamihira with the commentary of Bhaṭṭotpala, ed. Sud hákara Dvivedi. 2 parts. Vizianagaram Sanskrit Series, 10. Benares: Lazarus,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;1895&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brahmastrabhṣya of Bhāskara, ed. Vindhyeśvarīprasāda Dvivedin. Chowk hamba Sanskrit Series, 70, 185, 209. Benares: Chowkhamba, 1903–1915.&#xA;Brahmastrabhṣya of Śaṇkara with the commentary bhmat of Vā caspatimiśra, the subcommentary kalpataru of Amalānanda, and the&lt;br&gt;&#xA;sub-subcommentary parimala of Appayadīkṣita, ed. Anantakrishna Sas tri. Second edition, ed. Bhārgav Sāstrī, Bombay: Nirṇaya Sāgara Press,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;1938.&#xA;Bhmat of Vācaspatimiśra, a commentary on the Brahmasūtrabhāṣya of Śaṇ-&#xA;kara, ed. ḍhuṇḍhirāja Śāstri. 2 vols. Benares: Chowkhamba Sanskrit Series&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Office, 1935–1937.&#xA;216&#xA;33211 Honoris Causa 3P.indd 216 11/18/15 5:22 PM&#xA;tolerance, exclusivity, inclusivity, and persecution . . .&#xA;Bhairavamaṅgal. National Archives, Kathmandu MS 1-687, Nepal-German&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Manuscript Preservation Project Reel no. B 27/21; palm-leaf; Licchavi script;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;undated, c. ninth century ad.&#xA;Mañjuriyamlakalpa: Āryamañjuśrīmūlakalpa, ed. P. L. Vaidya. Buddhist&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Sanskrit Texts 18. Darbhanga: Mithila Institute, 1964. Essentially a reprint&lt;br&gt;&#xA;of the editio princeps of T. Ganapati Śāstrī, 1920, 1922, 1925 (Trivandrum San&#xA;skrit Series, 70, 76, and 84).&#xA;Mataṅgapramevara (Kriyāpāda, Yogapāda, and Caryāpāda) with the com&#xA;mentary (-vr̥tti) of Bhaṭṭa Rāmakaṇṭha II, ed. N. R. Bhatt. Publications de&lt;br&gt;&#xA;l’Institut français d’Indologie, 65. Pondicherry: Institut français d’Indologie,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;1982. Manuscript: P = Pune, Bhandarkar Oriental Research Institute, MS&lt;br&gt;&#xA;235 of 1883–84: paper; Śāradā script.&#xA;Matasra. National Archives, Kathmandu MS 3-379, Nepal-German Manu&#xA;script Preservation Project Reel no. B 28/16 (‘Śrīvidyāpīṭhamatasāra’): palm leaf; Pāla script; no date.&#xA;Manubhṣya → Manusmr̥ti.&#xA;Manustravivaraṇa of Bhāruci → derrett 1975.&#xA;Manusmr̥ti with the commentary (manubhṣya) of Medhātithi, ed.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Gangānātha Jhā. Bibliotheca Indica. 256. 3 vols. Allahabad: Asiatic Society&lt;br&gt;&#xA;of Bengal, 1932–1939.&#xA;Mahbhrata. For the first time critically edited by V. S. Sukthankar, with the&lt;br&gt;&#xA;cooperation of S. K. Belvalkar, A. B. Gajendragadkar, V. Kane, R. D. Kar&#xA;markar, P. L. Vaidya, S. Winternitz, R. Zimmerman, and other scholars and&lt;br&gt;&#xA;illustrated by Shrimant Balasaheb Pant Pratinidhi. (Since 1943 ed. S. Bel&#xA;valkar.) 19 vols. Pune: Bhandarkar Oriental Research Institute, 1927–1959.&#xA;Mr̥gendra, Vidypda and yogapda, with the commentary (-vr̥tti) of Bhaṭṭa&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Nārāyaṇakaṇṭha, ed. Madhusudan Kaul. Kashmir Series of Texts and Stud ies, 50. Srinagar, 1930.&#xA;mokṣakĀrikĀ of Sadyojyotis with the commentary (-vr̥tti) of Bhaṭṭa Rā makaṇṭha. In aṣṭaprakaraṇa.&#xA;mohacrottara. National Archives, Kathmandu MS 5-1977, Nepal-German&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Manuscript Preservation Project Reel no. A 182/3; paper; Nepalese Devanāgarī&lt;br&gt;&#xA;script.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
