<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Ludovici on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/Neitzesche/Will_to_Power/1_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/Ludovici/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Ludovici on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/Neitzesche/Will_to_Power/1_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/Ludovici/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>0</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/Neitzesche/Will_to_Power/1_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/Ludovici/0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/Neitzesche/Will_to_Power/1_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/Ludovici/0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;PREFACE.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Concerning great things one should either be silent or one should speak loftily:—loftily—that is to say, cynically and innocently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What I am now going to relate is the history of the next two centuries. I shall describe what will happen, what must necessarily happen: &lt;em&gt;the triumph of Nihilism.&lt;/em&gt; This history can be written already; for necessity itself is at work in bringing it about. This future is already proclaimed by a hundred different omens; as a destiny it announces its advent everywhere, for this music of to-morrow all ears are already pricked. The whole of our culture in Europe has long been writhing in an agony of suspense which increases from decade to decade as if in expectation of a catastrophe: restless, violent, helter-skelter, like a torrent that will &lt;em&gt;reach its bourne,&lt;/em&gt; and refuses to reflect—yea, that even dreads reflection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 NIHILISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/Neitzesche/Will_to_Power/1_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/Ludovici/1_NIHILISM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/Neitzesche/Will_to_Power/1_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/Ludovici/1_NIHILISM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nihilism As an Outcome of the Valuations and Interpretations of Existence Which Have Prevailed Heretofore.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What does Nihilism mean?—&lt;em&gt;That the highest values are losing their value.&lt;/em&gt; There is no bourne. There is no answer to the question: &amp;ldquo;to what purpose?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thorough Nihilism is the conviction that life is absurd, in the light of the highest values already discovered; it also includes the &lt;em&gt;view&lt;/em&gt; that we have not the smallest right to assume the existence of transcendental objects or things in themselves, which would be either divine or morality incarnate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2 HISTORY OF EUROPEAN NIHILISM</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/Neitzesche/Will_to_Power/1_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/Ludovici/2_HISTORY_OF_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/Neitzesche/Will_to_Power/1_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/Ludovici/2_HISTORY_OF_EUROPEAN_NIHILISM/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CONCERNING THE HISTORY OF EUROPEAN NIHILISM.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(a)&lt;/em&gt; Modern Gloominess.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;57&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My friends, we had a hard time as youths; we even suffered from youth itself as though it were a serious disease. This is owing to the age in which we were born—an age of enormous internal decay and disintegration which, with all its weakness and even with the best of its strength, is opposed to the spirit of youth. Disintegration—that is to say, uncertainty—is peculiar to this age: nothing stands on solid ground or on a sound faith. People live for the morrow, because the day-after-to-morrow is doubtful. All our road is slippery and dangerous, while the ice which still bears us has grown unconscionably thin: we all feel the mild and gruesome breath of the thaw-wind—soon, where we are walking, no one will any longer &lt;em&gt;be able&lt;/em&gt; to stand!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
