<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;mAya on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/amerindian/mAya/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;mAya on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/amerindian/mAya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Christian mask</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/amerindian/mAya/christian-mask/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/amerindian/mAya/christian-mask/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;traditionalist-catholicism&#34;&gt;Traditionalist Catholicism&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;status-under-christianity&#34;&gt;Status under Christianity&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Traditionalist Catholicism” refers to a broad set of religious beliefs, traditions, and practices that generally align with Roman Catholicism, but intermingle Indigenous polytheism and practices to form a local syncretic faith.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Traditionalists are part of a loosely organized North American denominational movement often called Old Catholicism. This movement adopts and affirms Roman Catholic traditions and theology while asserting independence from Rome. While they are often conservative, Old Catholic denominations can differ widely among themselves and with Rome on issues such as the ordination of women, divorce, and homosexuality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>popol vuh</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/amerindian/mAya/popol_vuh/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/amerindian/mAya/popol_vuh/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;0&#34;&gt;0&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;acknowledgements&#34;&gt;ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This volume is the culmination of nearly twenty-five years of collaboration with friends and colleagues who have been more than generous with their time, expertise, encouragement, and at times, sympathy. It has become a somewhat clichéd and expected thing to claim that a work would not be possible without such support. It is nonetheless true, at least from my experience, and I am indebted to all those who helped move the process along.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
