<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Suchness तत्त्वम् on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Suchness तत्त्वम् on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conflict सङ्ग्रामः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/eternal_conflict/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/eternal_conflict/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The conflict between Good (eg. dharma) and Evil (eg. counter religions) is endless.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Via MT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One major difference between the Abrahamistic counter-religions of the Messianic variety and the Indo-European religions is the single endpoint utopianism preached by the former. This is the driving force behind its secular mutations, including that in whose grip the modern Occident is currently convulsing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In contrast, at least since the break up between us and our Iranian cousins (of the Zoroastrian flavor) both sides had ingrained in them the concept of the eternal or repeated episodic struggle of the deva-s and asura-s. It probably was already present in the ancestral matrix of the the religion. On the Iranian side, Zarathustra caricatures it in the form the lands the airya-s being repeatedly invaded by Angra Mainyu. In fact, this dualism is very important to the philosophy of the Zoroastrian branch of the Iranians. On our side, the Mahābhārata and the purāņa-s emphasize the repeated cycles of the devāsura-samgrāma with neither side gaining total victory. Individual victories might be achieved: Namuci, Vţtra, Naraka, Prahlāda, Andhaka and so on might be eliminated but new ones arise.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creation and suffering</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/creation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Was there a creation? Then, there is the question of the creator - was it intelligent? Unlike abrahamisms which consider it as an unquestionable axiom, the Hindu vaidika tradition considers it requiring support from argument and speculation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Varied views:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;kumArIla-bhaTTa the mImAMsaka rejects the notion of a creator or creation as implausible and hard to establish (&lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/stream/slokavartika015341mbp#page/n427/mode/2up&#34;&gt;eng_gj&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.org/details/in.ernet.dli.2015.273885/page/n667&#34;&gt;sa_kb&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Samkhyakarika accepts the notion of higher selves or perfected beings but rejects the notion of God. [&lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.co.in/books?id=PoaMFmS1_lEC&amp;amp;pg=PA258#v=onepage&amp;amp;q&amp;amp;f=false&#34;&gt;sk&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Various other darshana-s suppose that an intelligent Ishvara created the universe.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;whence-creation-and-suffering&#34;&gt;Whence creation and suffering&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Whence creation? Whence suffering (negative experiences) in the world?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mundane decline cause</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mundane-decline-cause/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mundane-decline-cause/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;परव-पकष&#34;&gt;पूर्व-पक्षः&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vedanta and bhakti introduced scriptural certitude and magical thinking. Despite that, the quality of works Hindus produced was much superior to what the Christians and Muslims produced. However, it was a pale reflection of the great heights our ancestors had scaled. Naiyayikas, Lokayatas, mathematicians, yogis, and grammarians made individual contributions of great significance. However, the market was flooded with Vedanta apologetics and self-abasing bhakti outpourings that truly significant works became increasingly less frequent and less noticeable. By the time the Europeans had begun dominance, India had very little to contribute in terms of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Science and magic</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/science-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/science-magic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;magic-and-supernatural-phenomena&#34;&gt;Magic and supernatural phenomena&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Supernatural claims were used to motivate and preserve &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; behavior (see &lt;a href=&#34;../devaH/&#34;&gt;deities&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;../Rtam/&#34;&gt;karma&lt;/a&gt; and rituals) - just as one does in good legends and drama. They can, of course, be accepted in that sense from an aesthetic standpoint.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It was also supposed that one could attain one&amp;rsquo;s goals (bringing rain, death of enemies, wealth, poetic abilities, freedom from debt, recovery of health etc..) through various rituals (chanting a mantra or a stotra, adoring a deity in certain ways).&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;GA said: &amp;ldquo;Too many people think tantra is about churning out supernatural effects that defy the operating laws of the universe at an extremely visible, public level. NO. Such effects are known &amp;amp; do exist, albeit at a private level.&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;physical-effect-in-which-life&#34;&gt;Physical effect (in which life?)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is no systematic credible evidence to support many of these claims (controlling for psychological effects) - as far as this life is concerned.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;However, a natural resolution is that the goals are achieved in the next life (References in &lt;a href=&#34;../Rtam/karma/&#34;&gt;karma&lt;/a&gt; section).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;psychological-effects&#34;&gt;Psychological effects&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nevertheless, the rituals are themselves certainly useful in developing appropriate sentiments for the task. This applies to tasks and rituals involving multiple people (eg: a war party, or a family or even enemies observing the ritual) as well. Other benefits of rituals are discussed elsewhere.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is the psycho-somatic connection when it comes to health (including the placebo effect).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hexing-and-counter-hexing&#34;&gt;Hexing and counter-hexing&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Efficacy of magic based in rival traditions were recognized. Examples:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some bauddha texts recognized the efficacy of vaidika mantras and rites. [manjushrI mUlakalpa]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Several spells and rituals attempt to bring misfortune to enemies (through the agency of various deities). Other spells and rituals counter these.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This might involve infilitration and planting of special ritual objects (valaga-s) in enemy territory.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In other traditions: Jewish [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BpXVt0kQwgY&amp;amp;app=desktop&#34;&gt;YT5&lt;/a&gt;], Vodoo (with dattAtreya &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/Qd5kcqJPm1E?t=120&#34;&gt;YT1&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This might go to the extant of asking one deity to destroy another! Some incantations may even threaten deities!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;science-vs-scripture-non-conflict&#34;&gt;Science vs scripture non-conflict&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The dominant fraction of Hindu thought did not see any conflict between the body of knowledge acquired by systematic application of the scientific method, which we call science, on one hand and other knowledge (such as concepts such as dharma, RNa) on the other. Cheers to Darwin! Examples:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>चित् Consciousness</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/chit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/chit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;सत&#34;&gt;सत्&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We exist.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;First: can we question our own existence? If yes, even such questions will be the product of our own existence.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://indiafacts.co.in/foundations-of-hinduism/&#34;&gt;SG_IF15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;चत&#34;&gt;चित्&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are aware, to some extant at least. And we may even like it. This is because we are conscious.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Consciousness is fundamental constituent of the universe, more fundamental than time, space, matter and energy. We suppose this given the &amp;ldquo;hard problem of consciousness&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Consciousness is all-pervasive. A stone or dead wood is conscious but they are generally almost entirely of the guNa tamas.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;आननद&#34;&gt;आनन्दः&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is also interesting to note that sorrow cannot be generated internally, for our true state is bliss and not agony.&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://indiafacts.co.in/the-pillars/&#34;&gt;SG_IF15-2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>प्रकृतिः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/prakRtiH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/prakRtiH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;लोक-प्रकृतिषु भेदो वर्तते।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;गणवभग&#34;&gt;गुणविभागः&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;गुण-त्रयम् मन्युष्येषु लक्षन्ते - तमः, रजः, सत्त्वम्। गीतासु १४-तमे ऽध्याये।&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;तत्रात्मा निर्गुण एवेत्य् अद्वैतवेदान्तिनः।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;आयुर्-वेदोक्त&amp;ndash;शरीर-दोष-त्रय-वद् व्यामिश्रम् एव वर्तन्ते, यद्यपि कस्मिंश् चित् कस्यचिद् गुणस्य प्राबल्यं स्यात् कदाचिद् बहुदा वा।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;तमस्य् आलस्यम् अधिकम्। तामसिके जने न तावान् उल्लासः। किञ्च विश्रान्त्यै तम अपेक्षितम्।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;रजसि क्रियाशीलता, फलतृष्णा, ऽतृप्तिः। फल-प्राप्तेः सन्तोषस् तु कश्चन भवति। महत्कार्यसिद्ध्याय् अत्यन्तम् आवश्यकम् - राज्यविस्तारे, महाक्रीडास्पर्धायां जये च यथा।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;सत्त्वे चिन्तनशीलता, ज्ञानम् - चौर्यादाव् अपि - तत्र सत्त्वगुणो लक्षणीयः। चौर्यादौ रजोऽधीनः सत्त्वगुणः। धर्मिष्ठेषु सक्रियेषु तु सत्त्वाधीनो रजोगुणः।&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;सत्त्वाधिक्य-लक्षणानि - निर्मल्यम् मनसि, अनाकुलता। समाधानम्। ज्ञानसङ्घः।&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
