<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;sthAneshvaraH on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/sthAneshvaraH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;sthAneshvaraH on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/sthAneshvaraH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mantra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/sthAneshvaraH/sthAneshvara_mantra_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/sthAneshvaraH/sthAneshvara_mantra_intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;S. Timalsina. &amp;ldquo;Mantra,&amp;rdquo; Encyclopedia of Hinduism. Shared by the author on FB.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;meaning&#34;&gt;Meaning&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mantras are at the center of religious experience in India: they are found in all modes of ritual and practices, and they accompany all life events from birth to death. While mantras ground meditative practice and the many paths to liberation, they are also applied for magical power, alchemical transformation and medicinal purposes, and for prosperity in various phases of life.  Found in the earliest Vedic literature, mantras transcend Hindu culture and are also found in Buddhist, Jain, and Sikh traditions.  Even within Hindu culture, mantras defy a single interpretation.  The understanding of mantra found in the Vedas, Tantras, and folk traditions often overlap and shift.  Subsequent traditions utilize some of the earlier mantras, shifting their meaning, ritual, and visualization.+++(5)+++  In the classical sense, the term mantra is derived from two different verbal roots: the first is √matri + ac or ghañ which means ‘speaking secretly’ (Sāyaṇa), and the second is √man+tran, meaning ‘to contemplate’ (Yāska).+++(5)+++  Tantras often derive this term from two other verbal roots, √man (to contemplate) +√trai (to protect) (KT 17.54).  Stemming from different verbal roots and referring to distinct concepts, mantra can be considered as wholly discrete terms.  Among the prominent meanings of the Vedic or Tantric mantras, including secret counseling and the elevated self-awareness (pramātṛ) +++(5)+++ identified in the Trika system as ‘mantra,’ this essay focuses the first meaning of the term.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
