<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;01 Gurus and Adepts on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/01_Gurus_and_Adepts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;01 Gurus and Adepts on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/01_Gurus_and_Adepts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 The Tantric Guru</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/01_Gurus_and_Adepts/01_The_Tantric_Guru/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/01_Gurus_and_Adepts/01_The_Tantric_Guru/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Andre Padoux&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The importance accorded to the spiritual master, the guru or acarya, was a general  characteristic of Indian culture from very early times, and the trait was developed  and intensified in Tantric Hinduism and Buddhism. It goes back to the Vedic  period and is still visible in India today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A reason for the guru&amp;rsquo;s importance may lie in the fact that Indian traditions  always gave precedence to the oral/aural/verbal, rather than to the written, form  of religious or spiritual teachings. The Vedic Revelation is not scripture. It is sruti,  that which has been heard and which is transmitted by word of mouth. The  Buddha and the Jina taught orally, and their teaching was long committed to  memory only. The various Tantric doctrines, though they seem to have been  written down early (by the fifth or sixth century C.E., perhaps, for Hindu Tantras,  earlier for the Buddhist ones), were also deemed to have been revealed - that is,  told, orally expressed - by a deity to a first master and then transmitted in the  same oral fashion to initiates alone, through a succession of masters (gurupar amparya), to succeeding generations of believers or adepts. Tantric texts that  embody this sort of teaching in writing are therefore often couched in the form  of a dialogue between a deity and a mortal, or between two deities speaking in  mythical times - one asking to be taught, the other revealing orally his/her teach ing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 King Kunji&#39;s Banquet</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/01_Gurus_and_Adepts/02_King_Kunjis_Banquet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/01_Gurus_and_Adepts/02_King_Kunjis_Banquet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Matthew I. Kapstein&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The traditions concerning the Indian Tantric adepts known as the Siddhas (&amp;ldquo;per fected ones&amp;rdquo;) have long fascinated scholars of the Tantric religions. This reflects  the great popularity of these traditions in the arts and literature of India, Nepal,  and Tibet, and the fact that several of the living Tantric communities, both Saivite&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and Buddhist, trace themselves back to the inspiration of the Siddhas.  Although some of the Siddhas were no doubt purely mythical personages, many  were famed teachers and adepts who lived in India during the last centuries of  the first millennium C.E. and the first centuries of the second. The tales concerning  the lives of all of them, however, are entwined in sacred legend, so that in most  cases it is very difficult to arrive at precise historical conclusions about these  figures. Several traditions speak of a collective grouping of eighty-four Mahasid dhas (&amp;ldquo;Great Siddhas&amp;rdquo;), and though the precise enumeration of the eighty-four  differs somewhat from one lineage to another, a Buddhist version of the Lives of  the Eighty-four Mahasiddhas, as compiled by the Indian adept Abhayadatta and  preserved in a Tibetan translation done close to the year 1100, has become the  most widely known source for the legendary accounts of their lives.  The Lives is itself only one part of a larger collection of Buddhist literature  relating to the Mahasiddhas that was introduced into Tibet during the same pe riod. Also important is a short verse collection, the Anthology of the Essential Re alizations of the Eighty-four Siddhas, compiled initially by an Indian teacher named  Viraprabha. This work parallels the Lives and has an extensive commentary re cording the oral commentary of Abhayadatta upon it. The three works just men tioned, however, do not yet constitute the totality of the collection. Unnoticed by  scholars so far is a peculiar text called the Garland of Gems, translated for the first  time below, which is also accompanied by a commentary attributed to the col laboration of Abhayadatta and his Tangut disciple Mondrup Sherap (Smon-grub shes-rab). This work, like the commentary on the anthology of songs, was cer tainly written in Tibetan, possibly on the basis of the Indian master Abhayadatta&amp;rsquo;s  instructions, but it is not the direct translation of an Indian text.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Interviews with a Tantric Kali Priest:</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/01_Gurus_and_Adepts/03_Interviews_with_a_Tantric_Kali_Priest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/01_Gurus_and_Adepts/03_Interviews_with_a_Tantric_Kali_Priest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Feeding Skulls in the Town of Sacrifice&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;June McDaniel&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Skulls are widely used in Bengali folk Tantra. They empower buildings and  grounds, like the relics in early and medieval churches. They are buried in tem ples, under the altar or in a corner, and they turn the building into sacred ground.  They are also buried at the foot of sacred trees, and they make ordinary ground  into an empowered meditation seat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 A Parody of the Kapalikas in the Mattavilasa</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/01_Gurus_and_Adepts/04_A_Parody_of_the_Kapalikas_in_the_Mattavilasa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/01_Gurus_and_Adepts/04_A_Parody_of_the_Kapalikas_in_the_Mattavilasa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;David N. Lorenzen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Mattavilasa is a one-act comic farce written in Sanskrit and Prakrit and at tributed to a Pallava ruler of south India named Mahendra-varman, who ruled  from his capital at Kanchi from about 600 to 630 C.E. The principal character in  the play is a drunken Kapalika adept named Satyasoma.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Kapalikas or Kapalins are one of the earliest mentioned sectarian groups  of Tantric adepts. Unfortunately no texts survive that can unambiguously be as signed to Kapalika authors. We have, instead, many texts written by their op ponents who criticize or parody Kapalika beliefs and practices, and a few inscrip tions that record donations to or from Kapalika adepts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 A Trance Healing Session with Mataji</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/01_Gurus_and_Adepts/05_A_Trance_Healing_Session_with_Mataji/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/01_Gurus_and_Adepts/05_A_Trance_Healing_Session_with_Mataji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kathleen M. Erndl&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bimla Devi, or Passu Mataji (Respected Mother from village Passu) as she is called  by her clients and devotees, is a female trance healer living in a village near  Dharamsala, Kangra district, Himachal Pradesh. She is regularly possessed by the  Hindu Goddess Vaisno Devi. Mataji maintains a small temple attached to her  home, where three days a week she goes into trance and, as the Goddess Vaisno  Devi, answers questions and offers cures for people. Those who come, mostly  women, consult her for a variety of problems including mental and physical  health, family relationships, employment, and spiritual concerns.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
