<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;0 on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/0/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;0 on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/0/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Author’s Preface</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/0/Authors_Preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/0/Authors_Preface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mantra is the key to Yoga in the deeper sense and to awakening a higher intelligence within us. Yet mantra remains a subject filled with mystery, illusion and misapplication that would benefit from a clear, systematic and in-depth explication, such as other aspects of Yoga have already received. I have aimed at such a presentation here, not just an introductory book on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the past few decades, I have written several books on different aspects of Yogic knowledge, Ayurvedic healing and Vedic astrology, in which I have alluded to various mantras and their application. At the same time, I was conducting research for a book devoted entirely to the subject of mantra, which has now come to fruition. I have tried to distill what is most essential and easiest to apply from that greater study and placed it in the present volume.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foreword</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/0/Foreword/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/0/Foreword/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr. David Frawley, Pandit Vamadeva Shastri, is a modern Renaissance man for Eastern mystical studies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If one is interested in Vedic Astrology, he has insightful books filled with information and wisdom about this ancient science.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If one is drawn to the ancient science of healing called Ayurveda, again David Frawley has books that will illumine the subject for you and guide you to further reading and studies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If your interests lie in the area of classical tantric practices – and I don’t mean of the sexual variety, but of the true mystical approaches – then you again will do well to consult the books expertly rendered by David Frawley.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introductory Note by Sampadananda Mishra</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/0/Introductory_Note_by_Sampadananda_Mishra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/0/Introductory_Note_by_Sampadananda_Mishra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Mantra, as Sri Aurobindo puts it, “is a word of power and light that comes from the overmind inspiration or from a very high plane of intuition.” (&lt;em&gt;The Future Poetry&lt;/em&gt;, SABCL, vol 9, p. 369) A Mantra is thus an inspired and intuitive and rhythmic utterance, a revealed seeing. It comes out of the “realisation of some inmost truth of God and self and man and Nature and cosmos and life and thing and thought and experience and deed.” (&lt;em&gt;The Future Poetry&lt;/em&gt;, SABCL, Vol. 9,P. 199)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introductory Note by Swami Veda Bharati</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/0/Introductory_Note_by_Swami_Veda_Bharati/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/0/Introductory_Note_by_Swami_Veda_Bharati/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Those who know (vidvaamsah) will confirm that the works of Shri Vamadeva Shastri are distinguished by their authenticity. This is so because they are based on (1) his personal quest and experience (2) deep dwelling into the texts and (3) oral learning received from many authentic teachers who are experts in their areas of knowledge. Shri Vamadeva Shastri has done this great service to many that he has offered access into knowledge that was often hitherto inaccessible to an average western seeker. He has done so not merely as a scholar of ‘words, lexicons and translations’, sometimes dubbed in the traditional circles of India as modern ‘index aachaaryas’. They provided profound research tools with their untiring efforts. It is a matter of profound delight that we can use their work as well as the first hand of knowledge of the keepers of the Traditions. Those who wish to dive deep into the spiritual treasure beyond words are now more and more highly recognized even in academic circles. Shri Vamadeva Shastri is of the generation that now respects the Traditions and articulates the ancient knowledge of those who would otherwise remain inarticulate because they do not always speak the languages of our contemporary world power structures. The present work on Mantra-yoga by Shri Vamadeva Shastri is a delight to read as it leaves out no corner of multigonic truths unexplored with regard to the complex science of mantras.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Note on Spelling and Pronunciation of Mantras</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/0/Note_on_Spelling_and_Pronunciation_of_Mantras/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/0/Note_on_Spelling_and_Pronunciation_of_Mantras/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The book uses the ‘transliterated Sanskrit alphabet’ to indicate the proper pronunciation of the mantras. Please note that the transliterated alphabet has its own phonetics that are not always equivalent to how these letters are pronounced in English. Sanskrit letters do not always correspond with English letters or even with English phonetics. This transliterated alphabet, though perhaps a little cumbersome to use at first, allows us to pronounce Sanskrit correctly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orientation of the Book</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/0/Orientation_of_the_Book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/0/Orientation_of_the_Book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1) The first section of the book explores the background of Mantra Yoga, the use of mantra for improving our karmas or actions in life, and the profound philosophy that mantra is based upon. This is to enable the reader to approach the practicalities of mantras with awareness, insight and discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2) The second section explains the main bija mantras, starting with the letters of the Sanskrit alphabet, leading up to the Mantra Purusha or body of sound, which is a very important practice in Mantra Yoga that has not been afforded much examination in the existing literature. Shakti bija mantras are also explored in detail, along with their application with the Mantra Purusha. This can help the reader understand the energies and indications of the bija mantras that they are using and how to adapt them for greater efficacy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Table of Contents</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/0/Table_of_Contents/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/tattvam/mantraH/articles/frawley/0/Table_of_Contents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foreword by Thomas Ashley-Farrand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introductory Note by Swami Veda Bharati&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introductory Note by Sampadananda Mishra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author’s Preface&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note on Spelling and Pronunciation of Mantras&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orientation of the Book&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part I Mantra Yoga And Mantra as a Karmic Tool&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 1: Mantra and Primal Sound&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 2: Mantra and Classical Yoga&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 3: Managing Your Karma with Mantra&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 4: Energizing Mantras with Power and with Grace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chapter 5: Mantra, the Divine Word and Cosmic Manifestation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
