<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Pre-Christian Religions  on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Pre-Christian Religions  on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>00</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/00/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/00/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;contents&#34;&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Volume ii&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;list of illustrations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;vii&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19&lt;/strong&gt; – Historical and social Contexts&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;aNDERs aNDRéN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;391&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20&lt;/strong&gt; – laws and assemblies&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;sTEfaN BRiNK&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;445&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21&lt;/strong&gt; – Ethics&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JoHN liNDoW&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;479&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22&lt;/strong&gt; – gender&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JUDy QUiNN&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;509&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23&lt;/strong&gt; – Kings and Rulers&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JENs PETER sCHJøDT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;529&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24&lt;/strong&gt; – Warrior Bands&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JENs PETER sCHJøDT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;559&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25&lt;/strong&gt; – Various Ways of Communicating&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;JENs PETER sCHJøDT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;589&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26&lt;/strong&gt; – Magic and Religion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;sTEPHEN a. MiTCHEll&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 – Historical and Social Contexts</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/19_Historical_and_Social_Contexts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/19_Historical_and_Social_Contexts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;anders andrén&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study of pre-Christian religions of the North (PCRN), as it is known from the icelandic literary tradition and latin and arabic sources, has links primarily to south scandinavian society from about 200 bce to about 1100 ce (è9). This scandinavian period can best be described as a kind of protohistory. The society is briefly described in a handful of well-known foreign sources, such as the writings of Tacitus, Jordanes, Procopius, Rimbert, and adam of Bremen. aspects of scandinavian society, such as raids and named kings, also appear in, for instance, the anglo-saxon Chronicle and the Carolingian annals. furthermore, scandinavian society is described in retrospective accounts such as saxo’s &lt;em&gt;Gesta Danorum&lt;/em&gt;, snorri’s &lt;em&gt;Heimskringla&lt;/em&gt;, and many of the sagas of icelanders. However, all these descriptions can be regarded as external, since they were written by contemporary outsiders or by later authors looking back to a past that may have been more or less imagined.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 – Laws and Assemblies</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/20_Laws_and_Assemblies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/20_Laws_and_Assemblies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;stefan Brink&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We have to assume that some kind of legal societies existed already during the first millennium in scandinavia. The legal custom at that early stage seems to have been closely tied to prevalent religious customs (cf., e.g., Brink 2003b).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a striking piece of evidence to this is the case of &lt;em&gt;Enhelga&lt;/em&gt;, discussed below — a small island with the name &lt;em&gt;Guþø&lt;/em&gt;, ‘the island dedicated to the gods’, which was also a thing assembly for a &lt;em&gt;hundari&lt;/em&gt; district (‘hundred’).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 – Ethics</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/21_Ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/21_Ethics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;John lindow&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By ethics we mean constraints on behaviour imposed by notions of what is socially accepted, or socially valued or scorned. since in our view PCRN per-meated all aspects of human life — that is, the religious view was ever-present&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;— notions of ethics were always imbued with the religious. While such a view might not hold in a modern or post-modern world, there is a far more fundamental difference. Today we think of ethics as involving decisions made by individuals when faced with various kinds of choices of behaviour within some sort of implicit or explicit notion of what is right and what is wrong. Ethical decisions are made by individuals, and ethics is an individual matter. in the pre-Christian and almost certainly medieval and even early modern North, ethics was a public matter, a matter that was socially and publicly enforced,1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>22 – Gender</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/22_Gender/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/22_Gender/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Judy Quinn&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;an investigation into gender in the social context of PRCN necessarily relies to a large extent on traces of supplanted traditions preserved in texts of later centuries. These textual traces suggest that one of the most radical changes brought about by the conversion to Christianity across scandinavia, as an exclusively male priesthood was progressively established by the church, was the consequent disempowerment of women in the public sphere of religious and social activity and the redefinition of male roles in line with Christian ideology. The traces relating to females include lexical evidence (such as the term &lt;em&gt;hofgyðja&lt;/em&gt;, meaning ‘temple-priestess’),1 information about legal changes (such as prohibitions against women officiating in religious ceremonies or participating in certain secular entertainments such as the exchanging of erotic verses), saga descriptions of women performing prophecy and magic as well as ‘preaching’&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>23 – Kings and Rulers</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/23_Kings_and_Rulers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/23_Kings_and_Rulers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jens Peter schjødt&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That there is some relation between the ruler and the gods within PCRN is a fact which no scholars have disputed. This said, however, almost everything else connected to this relation has been heavily debated, and as we have already seen several times, at the basis of the disagreement are varying opinions about the sources and how they should be used, which shall not be discussed again at this place. instead, we shall begin with some general considerations concerning the relation between rulers and the other World.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>24 – Warrior Bands</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/24_Warrior_Bands/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/24_Warrior_Bands/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jens Peter schjødt&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;it has often been maintained, and rightly so, no doubt, that the religion and mythology of the late (and perhaps also the Early) iron age to some extent reflected a warrior ideology, and that religion and war were strongly intertwined aspects.1 Thus, it has been said about the military band that it was ‘as much religious as it was martial’ (Kershaw 2000: 18). Therefore, the character of the military bands, the &lt;em&gt;Männerbünde&lt;/em&gt;, as they are often called, the retinue or the warrior bands, which is the term we will use here, is of great interest in dealing with the social consequences of the religious world-view (è1).2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>26 – Magic and Religion</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/26_Magic_and_Religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/26_Magic_and_Religion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;stephen a. Mitchell&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction: Magic as a Concept&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Categories of religion geared to contacting unseen power, often referred to in the research literature by the Polynesian term mana, in efforts to know the future and influence its events, have a complex history in modern scholarship (cf. Cunningham 1999). largely shaped by the colonial discourses of earlier eras, discussions by nineteenth- and early twentieth-century writers framed such activities as bearing a special relationship to, but being separate from, religion and science. one of the most influential of these authors, James george frazer, extended Edward B. Tylor’s earlier views about magic, arguing that magic, science, and religion were to be understood within an evolutionary scheme: magic was perceived as faulty reasoning about causality, which over time was replaced by religion, and that, in turn, would give way to science. Edmund leach (1964: 398) captured the essence of the debate in a particularly succinct locution, noting: ‘The core of the magical act is that it rests on empirically untested belief and is an effort at control — the first aspect distinguishes it from science, the second from religion’. However, debates about the suitability of hiving these sorts of categories off from other religious pursuits have persisted, with many scholars concluding that such special treatment of these areas, the ‘frazerian hangover’, is unwarranted (cf. Tambiah 1990). summarizing the discussion for many, Dorothy Hammond (1970: 1355) concludes: ‘Magic is not an entity distinct from religion but a form of ritual behavior and thus an element of religion’.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>27 – Ritual Space</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/27_Ritual_Space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/27_Ritual_Space/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Torun Zachrisson and anders andrén&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;as a ‘primary’ religion, PCRN was above all defined by ritual practice. it was called siðr, meaning ‘custom’, ‘habit’, or perhaps ‘tradition’ (è25). However, very few written sources concerning rituals in scandinavia are preserved (Clunies Ross 2002a), which means that archaeology is very important in any attempts to characterize PCRN. Rituals may have been more or less imbed-ded in everyday life (cf. Carlie 2004), but they were also carried out in spaces that were set aside from mundane life (è25). in this context, above all more specific ritual spaces will be treated, apart from burials, which will be discussed elsewhere (è33).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>28 – Ritual Time and Time Reckoning</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/28_Ritual_Time_and_Time_Reckoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/28_Ritual_Time_and_Time_Reckoning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;andreas Nordberg&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;a society can only function if there is a common perception of and a more or less agreed-upon system for the calculation of time. for the individual and family, time is governed by mundane and periodic tasks. for settlements and larger regions, time regulates collective social arrangements, political, judicial and economic harmony, and, not least, both private and public religious life. The anthropologist Edmund leach has expressed it thus:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>30 – Crisis Rituals</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/30_Crisis_Rituals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/30_Crisis_Rituals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jens Peter schjødt&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;according to the classification suggested in (è25),1 ‘Crisis Rituals’ is one of the main categories in religions worldwide (cf. also DuBois 2006: 74). They are characterized by the aim of bringing a negative condition back to normal.2 The goal of these rituals may be oriented towards an individual or a collective, that is, poor health on the part of an individual or threats against the whole of society such as war or famine. Divination is often an important part of crisis rituals: in order to detect the reason for a crisis and thus the most efficient means to solve it, it is necessary to obtain knowledge of what or who has caused it. This is also what we see in some of the examples dealt with below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>31 – Cyclical Rituals</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/31_Cyclical_Rituals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/31_Cyclical_Rituals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jens Peter schjødt&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of the more spectacular descriptions of rituals in the old Norse sources seem to be occupied with so-called cyclical rituals, that is, recurring rituals, celebrated at certain times of the year (è28) or perhaps on a daily basis, such as, for instance, the Vǫlsi ritual, as we shall return to below, or within other cyclical periods. Many cyclical rituals have as an important function, besides manipulating the supernatural beings to be benevolent, to establish a calendar to be used in the agricultural work. as in the previous chapter on crisis rituals (è30), we shall be occupied mainly with some of the most famous and spectacular ritual descriptions in the sagas and in other sources, some of which we will quote quite extensively, although there are many more hints to rituals of this kind (Näsström 2001: 106–14; è25).1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>32 – Passage Rituals</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/32_Passage_Rituals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/32_Passage_Rituals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jens Peter schjødt&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The classification of rituals was discussed above (è25), and whereas crisis rituals and cyclical rituals have not been theorized separately from a classificatory perspective, this is, on the contrary, the case with passage rituals.1 The very notion can be dated to 1909, with the appearance of arnold van gennep’s book Les rites de passage. Van gennep had a broader definition of rites de passage than the one we have chosen here (è25), since he included many rituals which we have classified as ‘cyclical’ (van gennep 1960: 178–83). Nevertheless, van gennep’s analyses of passage or transitional rituals ( rites de passage) are still important, even fundamental, to the ritual interplay between this and the other World. This is mainly due to his famous distinction between the various parts or phases of such rituals: namely, separation rites (rites symbolizing separation from the previous mode of existence), liminal rites (rites symbolizing the transitional stage proper; van gennep 1960: 21), and rites of incorporation (rites symbolizing reintegration into society with a new status). Much research on the phenomenon of passage rituals, in particular initiation rituals, has, of course, taken place since the early twentieth century, both within the general study of religion and more specifically within PCRN (cf. schjødt 2008: 22–57). suffice it to note here, however, that much of this research has focused on social and psychological aspects of initiation, which will not be discussed 1 a research historical account of these rituals, especially in connection with initiation outside as well as inside of the Nordic area, is found in schjødt (2008: 22–57).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>34 – Worlds of the Dead</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/34_Worlds_of_the_Dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/34_Worlds_of_the_Dead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;John lindow and anders andrén&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;graves — the world(s) of the dead — surrounded living people. The dead, insofar as they could influence the lives of the living, constituted the sort of other beings whom we take in this work to be characteristic of a religious worldview. Worlds of the dead can be related both to various mythological death realms and to places where the dead actually rested. The extent to which there was a relation between ideas of death realms and resting places of the dead is disputed, but the possibility is not unlikely. from a spatial point of view, the living in ancient scandinavia were always surrounded by the dead, in the form of more or less visible graves. in well-preserved contexts, it is clear that graves could be placed either close to settlements (for example, liedgren 1992: 96–120) or at the borders of settlements, surrounding farms, and villages (for example, fallgren 2006: 45–86). as is clear from (è33), not all dead received a formal grave, and those who were buried in formal graves must have been&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>35 – Fate</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/35_Fate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/35_Fate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;John lindow&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The idea of fate — in the world of gods, in the world of heroes, and in the world of ordinary people — finds expression in numerous rather varied outlets in the older written sources and has also captured the imagination of later scholars and artists. The concept was a staple of the older study of germanic culture and religion, but some more recent scholarship has recognized classical and Christian influences. Briefly, fate may be defined as what must happen to a person or persons, beyond his or her control, usually beyond his or her knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>36 – The Divine, the Human, and In Between</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/36_The_Divine_the_Human_and_In_Between/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/germanic/articles/pre-christian-religions/36_The_Divine_the_Human_and_In_Between/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;John lindow and Jens Peter schjødt&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;in his famous book from 2011, Religion in Human Evolution, Robert N. Bellah writes: ‘in archaic societies, complex chiefdoms, and the tribal societies […]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;gods, powerful beings, ancestors, and humans exist on a continuum — there are no absolute breaks between these categories’ (202).1 This is not to say, of course, that an awareness of the opposition between sacred and profane did not exist: certain places, times, persons, and other beings were definitely seen as more ‘sacred’ than others (è25). it simply means that between this and the other World there was room for entities occupying intermediate stages: some were more, others less sacred, but there were ‘no absolute breaks’. since the pagan germanic societies in the first millennium ce, including those of scandinavia, must be considered complex chiefdoms, we should expect Bellah’s 1 The three categories of religions mentioned here can all be equated with the ‘primary religions’ of Jan asmann (2006). Concerning the relation between ‘powerful beings’ and ‘gods’, Bellah is never quite clear, but his main criterion for making the distinction (cf. Bellah 2011: 95–96) seems to be whether these other World beings are venerated or not. since the powerful beings are not as powerful as gods (at least in the Judeo-Christian tradition), they are not gods.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
