<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/kemet/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;Articles on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/kemet/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Porphyry on priests</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/kemet/articles/porphyry_on_priests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/kemet/articles/porphyry_on_priests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Porphyry, On abstinence from animal food (1823) Book 4. pp. 110-138.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;solitariness&#34;&gt;Solitariness&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chaeremon the Stoic, therefore, in his narration of the Egyptian priests, who, he says, were considered by the Egyptians as philosophers, informs us, that they chose temples, as the places in which they might philosophize. For to dwell with the statues of the Gods is a thing allied to the whole desire, by which the soul tends to the contemplation of their divinities. And from the divine veneration indeed, which was paid to them through dwelling in temples, they obtained security, all men honouring these philosophers, as if they were certain &lt;strong&gt;sacred animals&lt;/strong&gt;. They also led a solitary life, as they only mingled with other men in solemn sacrifices and festivals. But at other times the priests were almost inaccessible to any one who wished to converse with them.+++(5)+++ For it was requisite that he who approached to them should be first purified, and abstain from many things, and this is as it were a common sacred law respecting the Egyptian priests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Priest purity</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/kemet/articles/priest-purity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/kemet/articles/priest-purity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Known as the purer ones, the high priests of ancient egypt, both male and female bathed in the holy lake in the temple twice daily &amp;ndash; morning and, at night. they removed all their body hair using razors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A clean mouth was important as they were to speak the words before the gods, so they used natron salt. they wore reed woven sandals, robes of pure white linen, even used metal mirrors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sacred-animals</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/kemet/articles/sacred-animals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/kemet/articles/sacred-animals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eternal Measures and Symbols of Egyptian Sages 95&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;And farther still, the Egyptian priests, from their transcendent wisdom and association with divinity, discovered what animals are more acceptable to the Gods [when dedicated to them] than man. Thus they found a hawk is dear to the sun, since the whole of its nature consists of blood and spirit&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In a similar manner, the Egyptians philosophize about the ram, the crocodile, the vulture, and the ibis, and, in short, about every animal; so that, from their wisdom and transcendent knowledge of divine concerns, they came at length to venerate all animals&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Temple ritual</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/kemet/articles/temple_ritual/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/kemet/articles/temple_ritual/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source &lt;a href=&#34;https://threadreaderapp.com/thread/1269985785341546496.html&#34;&gt;GA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;sanctuary-design&#34;&gt;Sanctuary design&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The concept of a main sanctuary for a main deity of a temple with subsidiary sanctuaries for other deities with the main sanctuary being a small, dark chamber &amp;amp; daily rites being done to it at morning, mid-day &amp;amp; evening — paralleling the गर्भगृह-परिवार-नित्यार्चन model of आगम-s. Note that the Egyptian temple is a microcosmic image of creation, with innermost sanctuary of the temple representing the primeval island which emerged out of the primordial ocean &amp;amp; creation of life begun. The temple pillars represent the waves of that primordial ocean.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
