<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;05 Tantric Paths on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/05_Tantric_Paths/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;05 Tantric Paths on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/05_Tantric_Paths/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>17 Emptiness and Dust: Zen Dharma</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/05_Tantric_Paths/17_Emptiness_and_Dust_Zen_Dharma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/05_Tantric_Paths/17_Emptiness_and_Dust_Zen_Dharma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Transmission Rituals&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;William Bodiford&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although the Shingon lineage of Kukai (774 - 835) and the Tendai lineage of  Saicho (767 - 822) can be most readily identified as the Tantric mainstream  within Japanese Buddhism, we must not overlook the pervasive influence of Tan tric rituals, Tantric deities, and Tantric symbolism on Japanese religious traditions  in general. Even today fire invocations (homa in Sanskrit, goma in Japanese), for  example, are ubiquitous not just in Shingon and Tendai, but also in Hosso, Ni chiren, and Zen lineages, as well as in Shinto (Japan&amp;rsquo;s so-called &amp;ldquo;native&amp;rdquo; religion),  mountain asceticism (shugendo), and many New Age religions, such as Agonshu.  In medieval times, before the eighteenth-century renaissance of Buddhist schol arship gave birth to a heightened sense of sectarian identity among these lineages,  Tantric imagery was even more common than it is now. For this reason, scholars  of Japanese culture often refer to medieval Japanese religions as kenmitsu (com bined exoteric and esoteric Tantric) Buddhism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>18 The Necklace of Immortality: A Seventeenth-Century Vaisnava Sahajiya Text</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/05_Tantric_Paths/18_The_Necklace_of_Immortality_A_Seventeenth-Century_Vaisnava_Sahajiya_Text/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/05_Tantric_Paths/18_The_Necklace_of_Immortality_A_Seventeenth-Century_Vaisnava_Sahajiya_Text/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Glen A. Hayes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Vaisnava Sahajiyas were Hindu tantrikas who lived in northeastern India,  especially in the region of greater Bengal (Bengal, Bihar, Orissa, Assam), from  approximately the sixteenth through the nineteenth centuries. Many things about  the medieval Vaisnava Sahajiyas remain unclear to modern scholars, including  their origins, social standing, major personalities, esoteric practices, authorship  of texts, and their continued existence into current times. Although much about  their beliefs and practices is elusive - we have, for example, no existing written  commentaries to help us in understanding key words and phrases, and apparently  no living connections to the medieval teachers - what we do know suggests a  truly distinctive approach to Tantric expression and experience. This chapter  explains why the medieval Vaisnava Sahajiyas are unique, and selected passages  from an important text, The Necklace of Immortality (Amrtaratnavali) of Mukunda dasa (ca. 1650 C.E.) will illustrate this distinctiveness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>19 The Tibetan Practice of the Mantra Path</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/05_Tantric_Paths/19_The_Tibetan_Practice_of_the_Mantra_Path/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/05_Tantric_Paths/19_The_Tibetan_Practice_of_the_Mantra_Path/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Tibetan Practice of the Mantra Path&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;According to Lce-sgom-pa&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yael Bentor&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The text translated here is an exposition of the Buddhist Tantric path written in  Tibet in about the twelfth or thirteenth century. It was chosen for the present  volume because of its relatively concise and straightforward style of explaining  Tibetan Tantra. The uncertainty concerning the author&amp;rsquo;s exact identity, dates, and  sectarian affiliation need not concern us here. According to the testimony of the  text itself, its author relies (specifically in the section on the completion process)  on the authority of Naropa. The work from which our selection is taken, The  Outline of the Jewel Mound of Instructions (Man-ngag-rin-chen-spungs-pa&amp;rsquo;i-dkar-cha&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20 The Ocean of the Heart: Selections from</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/05_Tantric_Paths/20_The_Ocean_of_the_Heart_Selections_from/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/05_Tantric_Paths/20_The_Ocean_of_the_Heart_Selections_from/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;the Kularnava Tantra&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Douglas Renfrew Brooks&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Few Sanskrit texts within Saiva and Sakta Hindu Tantra provide as clear and  concise a vision of basic tenets, beliefs, and values as the &amp;ldquo;Ocean of the Kula&amp;rdquo; or  Kularnava Tantra. Traditionally regarded as the fifth section of the Urdhvamnaya  Tantra, a work that has never been recovered, the Kularnava Tantra as we know  it today consists of some 2,060 verses divided among seventeen chapters called  ullasas or &amp;ldquo;waves.&amp;rdquo; Usually dated between about 1000 and 1400 C.E., the text is  as much a repository of traditional materials defining the movement or school  called the Kula or Kaulism as it is a singular, original document.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>21 Tantric Buddhism and Chinese Thoughtin East Asia</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/05_Tantric_Paths/21_Tantric_Buddhism_and_Chinese_Thoughtin_East_Asia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/tantrAgamAH/tantra-in-practice/05_Tantric_Paths/21_Tantric_Buddhism_and_Chinese_Thoughtin_East_Asia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fabio Rambelli&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The text translated below from the Chinese, entitled Ritual of the Secret Dharanis  of the Three Siddhis for the Destruction of Hell, the Transformation of Karmic Hin drances, and the Liberation from the Three Conditioned Worlds (hereafter, Ritual), is  a short but comprehensive summary of the doctrines and meditative practices of  East Asian esoteric Buddhism. The ideas and practices presented in this text cir culated in various forms in China between the late Tang and the early Song  periods (ninth and tenth centuries), and became very influential in Japan from  the twelfth century onward. The earliest known surviving versions were edited in  Japan in the early nineteenth century.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
