<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;सहिष्णुता Tolerance on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;सहिष्णुता Tolerance on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apologetics</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/apologetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/apologetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;hindu-desecration&#34;&gt;Hindu desecration&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;False claim: Hindu kings desecrated temples with equal frequency too .. (Or the &amp;ldquo;rare idol abduction = frequent idol desecration&amp;rdquo; false equivalence.) [The same probably applies in the Mesopotamian case.]&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Koenraad Elst&amp;rsquo;s Eaton &lt;a href=&#34;http://koenraadelst.bharatvani.org/articles/ayodhya/eaton.html&#34;&gt;rebuttal&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hinduhumanrights.info/dr-llewelyn-morgan-another-hindu-phobic-from-oxford/&#34;&gt;LM&lt;/a&gt;).&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;So, what is the &amp;ldquo;dominant pattern&amp;rdquo; in the sixteen remaining cases? As we saw in the case of the Lankan idols in Kanchipuram, the looted (or otherwise acquired) idols were respectfully installed in a temple in the conqueror&amp;rsquo;s seat of power, e.g., a solid image of Vishnu Vaikuntha, seized earlier by the Pratihara king Herambapala, &amp;ldquo;was seized from the Pratiaharas by the Candella king Yasovarman and installed in the Lakshamana temple of Khajuraho&amp;rdquo;. So, the worship of the image continued, albeit in a new location; and the worship of the old location was equally allowed to continue, albeit with a new idol as the old and prestigious one had been taken away. In both places, the existing system of worship was left intact.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In fact, the movement of the gaNapati statue from vAtApI by the pallava king is well known (thanks in no small part to the karNAtaka &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lGuuavo2JHU&#34;&gt;sangIta song&lt;/a&gt; ). This movement of revered persons (maybe idols in your lingo) of worship from one place to another was not necessarily condemnable &amp;ndash; certainly not the same way their breaking, use in latrines etc.. were/ are.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There is NO hindu text that glorifies movement of mUrti-s from one shrine to another (much less their destruction). By contrast, Islam does.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;example-occurances&#34;&gt;Example occurances&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;In 642 A.D., according to local tradition, the Pallava king Narasimhavarman I looted the image of Ganesha from the Chalukyan capital of Vatapi. Fifty years later armies of those same Chalukyas invaded north India and brought back to the Deccan what appear to be images of Ganga and Yamuna, looted from defeated powers there.&amp;rdquo; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.frontline.in/static/html/fl1725/17250620.htm&#34;&gt;Eaton&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;buddhist-interchange&#34;&gt;Buddhist interchange&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;repurposement&#34;&gt;Repurposement&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Buddhist temples were repurposed as Hindu temples and Hindu temples were repurposed as Buddhist temples (Bayon Temple, Preah Vihear, Angkor Wat, Vat Phou, etc.), but the goal was not to erase the other religious beliefs. When the Turks destroyed temples, they buried the idols under the courtyards of mosques so that the believers could trample over them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Royal sectarianism</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/royal-sectarianism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/royal-sectarianism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;identification&#34;&gt;Identification&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Declaration by kings can be direct - eg, AmuktamAlya-dA by kRShNadevarAya.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Particular shrines - &amp;ldquo;When Chola kings built shrines for Sharabha and Lingodbhava (latter in the place of Vishnu in Shiva temples), they were very much showing that they held Vishnu to be inferior.&amp;rdquo; - RL&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;misidentification&#34;&gt;Misidentification&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Donation to or patronizing shaivas or jainas does not make one a shaiva or jaina.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;mangala-shloka in stray inscriptions are not conclusive - especially if it contradicts other evidence.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eg. viShNu praying to gaNapati in some kRShNadevarAya inscription. Such mangala-shlokas were obviously inserted by the officer who was assigned to make the edict (the rAya likely had greater concerns to care for). Otherwise can&amp;rsquo;t square it with AmuktamAlyada etc..&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Auxiliary initiations&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Contrary to popular perception, being a viShNu-supremacist does not necessarily perclude taking dIxa-s pertaining to other deities&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tolerance-and-support&#34;&gt;Tolerance and support&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hindu kings were not iconoclasts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;And even if they did belong to one sampradaya, they did not have any issue in supporting other sampradayas or even getting rituals done through the priests/acharyas of the other sampradayas.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Saiva Cholas had rituals to Vishnu done for their welfare. But that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make them non-Saiva or syncretic or Smarta. There were sandhis (pujas) done in the name of Chola and Pandyan kings even in Jain temples for which these royals gave special endowments. They were certainly not Jainas either.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;vaishnava-kings&#34;&gt;vaiShNava kings&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;kRShNadeva was not only a vaiShNava but a shrIvaiShNava - if one bothers to read his own words in Amukta-mAlyadA.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>पर-मताङ्गीकारः</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/para-matAngIkAraH/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/meta/cult-competition/tolerance/para-matAngIkAraH/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;परमतानाम् सीमितो ऽप्य् अङ्गीकारो दृश्यते प्राचीनेषु। तेषाम् अस्मिन् सूत्रे सङ्ग्रहो ऽस्तु।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;श्रीवैष्णवाः &lt;a href=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/rAmAnujIyam/tattvam/venkaTa-nAtha-shAkhA/vishvAsaH/vAde_bhAvaH&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;शाङ्कराः &lt;a href=&#34;https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AgamaH_brAhmaH/shAnkara-darshanam/tattvam/vishvAsaH/vAde_bhAvaH&#34;&gt;TW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;तरक-शव&#34;&gt;त्रिक-शैवाः&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;अभिनवगुप्तः -&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;शास्त्रं&lt;/strong&gt; च &lt;strong&gt;परमेश्वर-भाषितम्&lt;/strong&gt; एव प्रमाणम्  -&lt;br&gt;&#xA;अपर-शास्त्रोक्तानाम् अर्थानां तत्र वैविक्त्येन +++(अस्माभिः शैवैर्)+++ +अभ्युपगमात्,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;तद्-अर्थातिरिक्त-युक्ति-सिद्ध-निरूपणाच् च।&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(तत्र मुकुन्दरामः - &amp;ldquo;अपर-शास्त्रोक्तानाम् अर्थानां = बौद्ध-वैष्णवादिभिः स्वस्वाम्नायेष्व् अनुशिष्टानाम् । ते च +अर्था अपरशास्त्रोक्ता बौद्ध-वैष्णवादि-शास्त्राभिहिताः।&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the 8th sūtra of प्रत्यभिज्ञाहृदयम्, Kṣemarāja (क्षेमराज) says that all the siddhāntas or theses of all the darśanas, are just the different aspects of the one Ātman (आत्मा).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
