<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;02 Studies in the Early History and Culture of North India on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;02 Studies in the Early History and Culture of North India on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 A Theatre of Broken Dreams</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/01_A_Theatre_of_Broken_Dreams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/01_A_Theatre_of_Broken_Dreams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vidiśā in the Days of Gupta Hegemony&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Prologue&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In his monumental Geschichte Indiens Hermann Kulke depicts the relation ship between the Gupta and Vākāṭaka dynasties as basically an unproblematic one, an alliance that was dominated by the Guptas and secured a peaceful coexistence till their fall.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Vermutlich in der Phase der Vorbereitung seines Krieges gegen die Kshatrapa gab dann aber Candragupta seine Tochter dem K¨onig Rudrasena II. zur Ehe, um den Rücken für seinen Kampf im Westen frei zu habeṇRudrasena starb jedoch schon nach fünfjähriger Regierung etwa im Jahre 390 ṇChr. Auf Candraguptas Rat hin übernahm daraufhin seine Tochter Prabhavatigupta die Regentschaft für ihre S¨ohne. Während ihrer etwa zwanzigjährigen Regentschaft geriet das Vakataka Reich zunehmend unter direkten einfluß der Gupta und geh¨orte de facto bald zu deren Reichsverband. Zwar wurde die Unabhängigkeit der Vakatakas unter Pravarasena II. (ca. 410 bis 440 ṇChr.), von dem eine große Zahl Inschriften bekannt ist, wiederhergestellt. Doch hatte das Reich der Vakatakas aufgeh¨ort, eine potentielle Bedrohung für die Guptas zu seiṇBis zum Untergang der Guptas bestanden statt dessen überaus enge Beziehungen zwischen beiden Reichen, so daß man in der Geschichtsschreibung bisweilen sogar vom Vakataka-Gupta-Zeitalter spricht. Diese engen Beziehungen trugen wesentlich zur Ausbreitung der Gupta Kultur nach Zentralindien bei. (Kulke 1998, 114)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Royal Patronage and Religious Tolerance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/02_Royal_Patronage_and_Religious_Tolerance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/02_Royal_Patronage_and_Religious_Tolerance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Formative Period of Gupta–Vākāṭaka Culture&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Udayagiri&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When, at the beginning of the 5th century, the royal elephant carrying his majesty climbed the slopes of the Udayagiri for a visit to the sacred complex, Emperor Candragupta made sure not to give offence to any of the parties involved in his grand project. His aim was clearly defined in the inscription that records his visit, namely the winning of the entire earth:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Rāma’s Hill</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/03_rAmas_Hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/03_rAmas_Hill/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Transgression and Atonement on a Hill in the South&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;and the Inadequacy of Substitutes&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Preamble&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Coming from a part of the world where there are neither holy places nor moun tains, it may seem strange that my professional career has been marked by the research of these two phenomena. Curiosity to discover unknown fields, no doubt, lies at the base of every scholarly endeavour, but in my case there may have been a more compelling factor, namely the fascination for the cultural and religious world of India. Studying the religious heritage of the Subcontinent means that one cannot miss the holy places: they are simply ubiquitous, and many of them are mountains. 1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 A New Interpretation of Rāmagiri Evidence</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/04_A_New_Interpretation_of_rAmagiri_Evidence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/04_A_New_Interpretation_of_rAmagiri_Evidence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;1 Trivikrama: Word and Statue∗&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Preamble&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A long series of seminars at the Institute of Indian Studies of the University of Groningen came to its preliminary conclusion in 1993. In these seminars, in which Rob Adriaensen, Harunaga Isaacson and Hans Bakker took part, the newly discovered stone inscription in the Kevala–Narasiṁha Temple (KNT) on top of the Rāmagiri (Ramtek Hill) had been studied; this study resulted in the publication of the inscription with a translation and commentary (Bakker &amp;amp; Isaacson 1993; above, pp. 113 ff.).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 Skandagupta’s Bhitarī Stone Pillar Inscription</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/05_Skandaguptas_bhitarI_Stone_Pillar_Inscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/05_Skandaguptas_bhitarI_Stone_Pillar_Inscription/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Note on Skandagupta’s Bhitarī Stone Pillar Inscription, verses 8–12∗&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Commemorating the Dead&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ajay Mitra Shastri&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the dear memories I have of Prof Dr Ajay Mitra Shastri is the moment that the doors of the arrival hall of Amsterdam Airport opened and I saw my learned friend leaving the ‘nothing to declare’ behind him. He came as a an invited speaker of the biennial conference of the European Association of South Asian Archæologists, held in Leiden in the summer of 1999. The journey had been a safe one and evidently Ajay was much relieved when he saw a familiar person at the place of landing. A happy smile passed over his face. And I was glad that, finally, I had an opportunity to return some of the kind hospitality that had been bestowed on me every time I had come to Nagpur. Taking its start from a common interest, our relationship had developed from mutual respect to friendship.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 Jaunpur Stone Inscription</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/06_Jaunpur_Stone_Inscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/06_Jaunpur_Stone_Inscription/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The So-called ‘Jaunpur Stone Inscription of Īśvaravarman’∗&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Preamble&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Few scholars can claim mastery of such a wide range of different fields within the discipline of Indology as Prof Dr Oskar von Hinüber. One of the branches of learning that owes a great deal to his studies is Indian epigraphy. My con tribution here is meant as a humble tribute to Oskar and his work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We possess two inscriptions that undisputably belong to that branch of the Maukhari family which eventually turned the ancient Kānyakubja (Kanauj) into their new capital, viz. the well-known Haraha Stone Inscription of Īśānavarman of Vikrama Samvat 611 (ad 554), in which Īśānavarman’s son Sūryavarman records his renovation of a dilapidated Siva temple, and an ´ inscription found in Jaunpur. 1 The Jaunpur Inscription is merely ‘a fragment of a very much larger inscription’. 2 It deserves a detailed examination.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 The Temple of Maṇḍaleśvarasvāmin</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/07_The_Temple_of_maNDaleshvarasvAmin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/07_The_Temple_of_maNDaleshvarasvAmin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Muṇḍeśvarī Inscription of the Time of Udayasena&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reconsidered&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hill near the village Ramgarh, on whose top (height 184 m) the so-called ‘Muṇḍeśvarī Temple’ is found, 1 belongs to the northern spurs of the Kaimur Range, the eastern embranchment of the Vindhyas. It is situated in the Kaimur District of southwest Bihar, 70 km SE of Vārāṇasī, 170 km SW of Patna, 60 km NW of Rohtasgarh on the River Son, and 8 km SW of Bhabua, as the crow flies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Monuments to the Dead in Ancient North India</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/08_Monuments_to_the_Dead_in_Ancient_North_India/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/08_Monuments_to_the_Dead_in_Ancient_North_India/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Preamble&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The scope of this study is limited to funerary practices within the brahmini cal (Hindu) fold of the ancient period, i.e. North India from the Vedic Age to the reign of King Harṣavardhana (7th century). Funerary practices in South India, Dravida country, and Southeast Asia seem to have differed significantly from those in North India. 1 They deserve a study of their owṇIn late me dieval North India new forms of commemoration (samādhis, chatarīs) emerged, possibly under Islamic influence. 2&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Rāma Devotion in a Saiva Holy Place ´</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/09_rAma_Devotion_in_a_Saiva_Holy_Place/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/09_rAma_Devotion_in_a_Saiva_Holy_Place/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Case of Vārāṇasī&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do homage to Sarasvatī and Gaṅgā,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;both holy and enchanting streams;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the latter washes away the sin of him&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;who bathes therein and drinks of its waters;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;the former destroys the ignorance&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;of him who speaks or hears of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;(RCM 1 C15.1, tr. Hill)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the eulogizing stanzas that precede the Acts of Rāma, Tulsīdās makes a curious remark:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[I do homage] to Hara, too, and Girijā, who for the good of the world and with regard to the evil of this age composed a number of spells in a barbarous tongue, incongruous syllables, meaningless mutterings, whose influence is manifest by the power of Maheśa. (RCM 1 C15.3, tr. Hill)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 The Hindu Religion and War</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/10_The_Hindu_Religion_and_War/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/02_Studies_in_the_Early_History_and_Culture_of_North_India/10_The_Hindu_Religion_and_War/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Preamble&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although, since Mahatma Gandhi, India is known by many as the country where the principle of ahiṁsā, ‘not killing’, has being invented and imple mented, this ancient principle had originally little or nothing to do with how warfare was conducted and conceived in Hindu society. War was endemic in South Asia and seen as the right and duty of the Hindu king. This warfare, however, was regulated by some rules, which were humane in some respects. Battle was sometimes conceived of as a form of ritual, in which the soldiers were the sacrificial victims, but this does not entail that Hindu kings went to war for the sake of religion.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
