<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/kaumAraH/MT_lekhAH/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;मानसतरङ्गिणीकृल्-लेखाः on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/kaumAraH/MT_lekhAH/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>shrI rAmAnuja deshika, one of the last great kaumAra tantrics</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/kaumAraH/MT_lekhAH/2007-01-14_shri-ramanuja-deshika-one-of-the-last-great-kaumara-tantrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/kaumAraH/MT_lekhAH/2007-01-14_shri-ramanuja-deshika-one-of-the-last-great-kaumara-tantrics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2007/01/14/shri-ramanuja-deshika-one-of-the-last-great-kaumara-tantrics/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The below note is neither meant as a sectarian effusion nor a historical&#xA;account. It is a hagiography and just that.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;sarva-bhUtAmakaM manmanobodhakaM sat-kR^ipAsAgaraM devasenApate pAhi mAM&#xA;pAhi mAM pAhi mAM deva tubhyaM namo deva tubhyaM namo deva tubhyaM namaH&#xA;||&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The shrI-vaiShNava AchArya, sudarshana sUrI, was proceeding to&#xA;shrIperaMputtur after visiting the old temple of viShNu at venkaTagiri&#xA;(not Tirupati) and consecrating a shalagraman there. On his way back on&#xA;his horse cart he had to pass by the shrine housing the great vAyu&#xA;li~Nga of the terrible rudra, kAlahasti. rudra’s presence was felt here&#xA;in the form in which he had destroyed gajAsura. The zealous vaiShNava&#xA;who did not recognize the greatness of The god, asked his henchmen to&#xA;draw the curtains in his cart and he closed his eyes so that even by&#xA;error he might not cast his eyes on the shrine of rudra. When he was a&#xA;safe from kAlahasti distance he opened his eyes but to his horror he had&#xA;turned blind. Shocked he uttered the verse:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;sarvAtmatA te shrutiShu prasiddhA satyaiva sA kAlakarIsha nUnaM |&lt;br&gt;&#xA;apashyatastvA madhunA samastaM yato na me dR^iShTipathaM prayAti ||&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mahAkaumara mantras in AstIka and nAstIka parlance</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/kaumAraH/MT_lekhAH/2006-09-06_the-mahakaumara-mantras-in-astika-and-nastika-parlance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/kaumAraH/MT_lekhAH/2006-09-06_the-mahakaumara-mantras-in-astika-and-nastika-parlance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2006/09/06/the-mahakaumara-mantras-in-astika-and-nastika-parlance/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;|| OM namaH kumArAya ||&lt;br&gt;&#xA;namo.astu te raktavarNAya shaktidharAya nilakaNThavAhanAya mahAsvamine&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We bow to the great red-hued wielder of the shakti, who is seated atop a&#xA;fierce peacock.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sadly, many of the great tantras pertaining to the god kumAra appear to&#xA;have been lost. However, the obscure tantric manuals like the&#xA;skandArchana-kalpadrUma and mahA-kaumAra-kalpa preserve several of the&#xA;mantras that are used, and those well-versed in the kaumara ritual use&#xA;them to perform the various rites of kArttikeya. Amongst these mantra&#xA;are the tryAkShara mahAvidyA that is recommended especially when one is&#xA;a youth, the mahAkumAra vidyA and the bhUtaDAmara mantra that was&#xA;mastered by the great Eastern kaumArAchArya-s from the va~Ngadesha who&#xA;latter settled in Bellary. Interestingly, variants of these mantras were&#xA;adopted by the nAstIka-s early in the development of their tantric&#xA;literature. These mantra-s in a bauddhized form appear in the&#xA;ma~NjushrI-mUla-kalpa one of the few Sanskrit originals of the tantras&#xA;of the nAstIkas that survived in India. It was discovered by gaNapati&#xA;shAstrI in the midst of the nambuthiris in early 1900s of CE (but in the&#xA;discussion below I am following the text provided by the Vaidya&#xA;edition). This appears to be one of the earliest tantric manuals of the&#xA;bauddhas probably going back to the period around 500-600 CE at the&#xA;earliest. In this tantra ma~NjushrI is identified with kumAra and a&#xA;bauddhized “myth” is created to incorporate him into the nAstIka fold.&#xA;The tantra itself is composed in a peculiar vulgar Sanskrit: It is&#xA;understandable, but probably not that of a well-educated brahmin&#xA;tantrik.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Royal kumAra worshippers</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/kaumAraH/MT_lekhAH/2005-10-28_royal-kumara-worshippers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/kaumAraH/MT_lekhAH/2005-10-28_royal-kumara-worshippers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/10/28/royal-kumara-worshippers/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Shunga coins: The late Maurya and Shunga period has the square coins&#xA;of the Ujjain series bearing the image of kumAra. They installed some&#xA;idols of kumAra in Mathura (175-50 BC).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Shakas:&lt;/strong&gt; The Shaka king Ayalisha (Azilises-I) has kumAra on his&#xA;coin. Another Indianized Shaka mentions construction of a well in the&#xA;name of skanda. The exact date of this inscription is unclear: mentioned&#xA;as year 201 in some era.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mayurashikhA</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/kaumAraH/MT_lekhAH/2005-03-03_mayurashikha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/kaumAraH/MT_lekhAH/2005-03-03_mayurashikha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2005/03/03/mayurashikha/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;om senApataye namaH &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hello.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/pbh.gif&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://i0.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/pbh.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Posted by&#xA;Hello&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://photos1.blogger.com/img/133/1300/640/kumara.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;figure class=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/img/133/1300/400/kumara.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;https://i2.wp.com/photos1.blogger.com/img/133/1300/400/kumara.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; title=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&#xA;    &#xA;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;aiM huM kShuM klIM kumArAya namaH //&lt;br&gt;&#xA;oM shrIM e i u na shrIM rIM kumArAya namaH //&lt;br&gt;&#xA;We worship the awful skanda praised by in the most glorious of secret&#xA;tantras, embraced by the beautiful ShaShThi and holding a cock-banner, a&#xA;shakti, a vajra and a trishula.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The most secret vidyAs of the great god kumAra are revealed in the&#xA;saMhitAs of the skanda yAmala also known as the senApati yAmala. Having&#xA;worshipped the goddess chatushpatha niketA, the dreadful lohitAyani, and&#xA;mahAmayUrI, and then having propitiated skandApasmara, shishu and the&#xA;goat-head bhadrashAkha I shall narrate the lineage of transmission of&#xA;this vidyA:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The deadly foe-destroying yoga of brahmaNya deva</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/kaumAraH/MT_lekhAH/2004-09-12_the-deadly-foe-destroying-yoga-of-brahmanya-deva/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/branches/kaumAraH/MT_lekhAH/2004-09-12_the-deadly-foe-destroying-yoga-of-brahmanya-deva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;https://manasataramgini.wordpress.com/2004/09/12/the-deadly-foe-destroying-yoga-of-brahmanya-deva/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“We pacify the six-headed being, of fiery birth, who is lost in the&#xA;embrace of the beautiful daughter of the god of the gods indra. May his&#xA;lethal darts not harm us and instead strike our foes.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the heart of the kaumara tantric rite lies the great secret yoga&#xA;which destroys ones foes. The skandArchana kalpadruma and other obscure&#xA;kaumAra texts refer to this secret yoga, the configuration of the&#xA;incantation for which is normally revealed only by oral tradition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
