<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;02 The Nature of the Embodied Soul on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/02_The_Nature_of_the_Embodied_Soul/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;02 The Nature of the Embodied Soul on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/02_The_Nature_of_the_Embodied_Soul/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>05 The Descent of the Soul</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/02_The_Nature_of_the_Embodied_Soul/05_The_Descent_of_the_Soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/02_The_Nature_of_the_Embodied_Soul/05_The_Descent_of_the_Soul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One must take into account the&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;differences between the universal&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;soul and our own…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;gnostic-context&#34;&gt;Gnostic context&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iamblichus’s teachings on the soul&lt;br&gt;&#xA;were an essential correlate to his theurgical system,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;yet to be understood properly&lt;br&gt;&#xA;they must be seen in the context of alternative developments in Platonic schools&lt;br&gt;&#xA;from the second to the fourth century c.e.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Iamblichus’s emphasis on the descent of the soul&lt;br&gt;&#xA;was a response to what he perceived as unorthodox and dualistic forms of Platonism.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;The most significant in Iamblichus’s era&lt;br&gt;&#xA;was the Gnostics’ reversal of the Platonic creation myth&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and their reinterpretation of the Demiurge and World Soul.+++(4)+++&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Though Gnostics drew their dramatis personae from Jewish myths,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;their cosmological framework was taken from Plato’s &lt;em&gt;Timaeus&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and to some degree from the &lt;em&gt;Phaedo&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Phaedrus&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 Soul as Mediator</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/02_The_Nature_of_the_Embodied_Soul/06_Soul_as_Mediator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/02_The_Nature_of_the_Embodied_Soul/06_Soul_as_Mediator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;*The existence of souls is lowest, *&#xA;&lt;em&gt;deficient, and imperfect…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;De Anima&lt;/em&gt; &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Iamblichus outlined his differences with Plotinus on the doctrine of the soul&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and developed his own position in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although the treatise is valuable as a doxography of the philosophical schools of antiquity,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Iamblichus’s own position is evident,&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and the rationale for his psychology lends support to his adoption of theurgy&lt;br&gt;&#xA;as the praxis necessary for the embodied soul.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 The Constraints of Embodiment</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/02_The_Nature_of_the_Embodied_Soul/07_The_Constraints_of_Embodiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/02_The_Nature_of_the_Embodied_Soul/07_The_Constraints_of_Embodiment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*The soul possesses a double life. *&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Aristotle’s conception of the soul as &lt;em&gt;entelecheia&lt;/em&gt; of the body may well have influenced Iamblichus more than his Platonic predecessors; the limits of the soul as conceived by Iamblichus were the limits of its mortal body. Yet despite this, Iamblichus did not limit the soul’s existence to its corporeal form, and in the &lt;em&gt;De Anima&lt;/em&gt; he says that sometimes the soul is not in a body:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 The Freedom of Immortal Bodies</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/02_The_Nature_of_the_Embodied_Soul/08_The_Freedom_of_Immortal_Bodies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/02_The_Nature_of_the_Embodied_Soul/08_The_Freedom_of_Immortal_Bodies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The aetherial body is . . . free&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;from centrifugal or centripetal&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;tendencies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Receiving the gods was not without danger. For Iamblichus, the incorporeal world was just as complex as the corporeal, and one could easily be misled without a discerning guide.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iamblichus is reported by Eunapius, for example, to have exposed a fraudulent séance led by a deceased gladiator posing as the god Apollo (Eunapius, Vit. Soph. 473). According to Iamblichus, such phenomena were caused by errors in the theurgic art, “for inferior entities assume the appearance of more venerable orders and pre-tend to be those entities whose appearance they have adopted and hence they make boastful claims that exceed the power available to them.”1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 The Paradox of Embodiment</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/02_The_Nature_of_the_Embodied_Soul/09_The_Paradox_of_Embodiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/02_The_Nature_of_the_Embodied_Soul/09_The_Paradox_of_Embodiment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That which is immortal in the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;soul is filled completely with&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;mortality…&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;he repercussions of viewing the Platonic soul through Aristotle’s doctrine that essences ( ousiai) are revealed by activi-Tties ( energeiai) have been examined by Carlos Steel in a brilliant monograph on Neoplatonic psychology, The Changing Self.1 Steel outlines Iamblichus’s view of the soul by examining the Iamblichean fragments preserved in Priscianus’s (Simplicius’s?) commentary on Aristotle’s De Anima.2 At the outset of his commentary Priscianus says that he “will hold to the truth of the matter as much as possible according to the interpretation of Iamblichus 1. Carlos G. Steel, The Changing Self: A Study on the Soul in Later Neoplatonism: Iamblichus, Damascius, and Priscianus, trans. E. Haasl (Brussels: Paleis der Academien, 1978).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Descending to Apotheosis</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/02_The_Nature_of_the_Embodied_Soul/10_Descending_to_Apotheosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/02_The_Nature_of_the_Embodied_Soul/10_Descending_to_Apotheosis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The divine is joined with itself . . .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In her classic study, Le Dualisme chez Platon, le Gnostiques et les Manichéens,1 Simone Petrément characterizes dualism as follows: “In religions and philosophies where it appears, dualism seems tied to the belief in a transcendent, to an unknown which is not simply not yet known, to an invisible which is not simply not yet seen, but to that which essentially goes beyond anything seen and known” (3). Although Iamblichus was not a dualist, this definition is perfectly applicable to his theurgical Platonism. Petrément’s thesis is that genuine experiences of transcendence occur beyond one’s understanding and that these ruptures in the continuity of consciousness lead naturally to the postulation of a “two-world” cosmology. “To speak of two worlds,” she says, “is to speak of total change” (8). Petrément argues convincingly that cosmological dualism is rooted in experiential dualism and that soteriology necessarily precedes cosmology. In this I believe she is correct, but for Iamblichus the dualism that derives from a transcendent rupture:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Eros and the One of the Soul</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/02_The_Nature_of_the_Embodied_Soul/11_Eros_and_the_One_of_the_Soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/mediterranian/platonism/iamblichus/articles/shaw_theurgy_soul/02_The_Nature_of_the_Embodied_Soul/11_Eros_and_the_One_of_the_Soul/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is another principle of the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;soul . . .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Iamblichus’s doctrine of the “one of the soul” provided important theoretical support for the practice of theurgy. Because the soul carried the presence of the One it had the capacity to rise above itself, be homologized to the cosmos and united with its divine cause. The fact that the soul possessed correspondences to the entire cosmos meant that, like the cosmos, it possessed a principle that preceded its multiplicity. Iamblichus called this principle “the one of the soul” ( to hen tes psuches), and he identified it with the&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
