<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;00 on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/00/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;00 on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/00/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 PREFACE</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/00/01_PREFACE/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/00/01_PREFACE/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;THE present work is based on six lectures given in 1975 in the series of Ratanbai Katrak lectures founded at Oxford in memory of his wife by the late Dr. Nanabhai Navroji Katrak. I am indebted to the Electors for inviting me to give these lectures, and to the Oxford University Press for allowing me to expand them for publication. Even with this concession, much necessarily remains still unrecorded which I learnt from the Zoroastrians of Sharifabad-e Ardekan, a little village at the northern end of the Yazdi plain. While on leave from the School of Oriental and African Studies, University of London, I spent twelve months in Iran during 1963–4, and most of this time I was able to pass in Sharifabad, thanks to the great kindness and hospitality of Agha Rustam Noshiravan Belivani and his wife Tahmina Khanom. To them and to their children I owe the warmest debt of gratitude. I was shown much helpfulness too by their relatives and friends, and by the Zoroastrian villagers at large, who received an unexpected stranger in their midst with truly remarkable tolerance and kindness. Since what I leart of the Sharifabadis was so striking and admirable, I trust that the following pages will constitute both a faithful record of what they taught me, and at the same time a tribute to them themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 LIST OF PLATES</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/00/02_LIST_OF_PLATES/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/00/02_LIST_OF_PLATES/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TAI-11&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;facing page I a The moment of the first congregational response during&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;an Afrinagan-e Gahambar. b Piruza, Agha Rustam&amp;rsquo;s second daughter, giving the com-e&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;swa.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;II a Banu of Mazra Kalantar about to eat melon during no-swa. .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;b Piruza-e Dinyar giving Hajji Khodabakhsh a drink of 49&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;water during no-swa.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;..&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;III a D. Khodadad making the libation to water in a garden&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;at Hasanabad. Part of the company at the evening meal eaten by the dakhma at the Dadgah-e Tir-Mah.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 ABBREVIATIONS</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/00/03_ABBREVIATIONS/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/00/03_ABBREVIATIONS/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;T4174114 NETY- WR.VYRWHYTE TXISTUTTARIT&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: for abbreviated titles of books which follow an author&amp;rsquo;s name see under that name in the bibliography.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AMI&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;B. BSOAS D. JAOS JRAS&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Riy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Archaeologische Mitteilungen aus Iran Bundatiān Bulletin of the School of Oriental and African Studies Dastur (general courtesy title for a Zoroastrian priest) Journal of the American Oriental Society Journal of the Royal Asiatic Society Rivāyats (sce under Dhabhar, B. N., and Unvala, M. R. in the&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 BIBLIOGRAPHY</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/00/04_BIBLIOGRAPHY/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/00/04_BIBLIOGRAPHY/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I. BOOKS Note: abbreviated book-titles are set in square brackets at the end of the appropriate entries. ANKLESARIA, T. D. (ed.), The Datistan-i Dinik, Pt. I, Bombay, n.d. BAILEY, H. W., Zoroastrian problems in the ninth-century books (Ratanbai&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Katrak lectures), O.U.P., Oxford, 1943. BIANCHI, U., Zaman i Ohrmazd, storia e scienza delle religioni, Torino,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol start=&#34;1958&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;BOYCE, Mary, A History of Zoroastrianism (Handbuch der Orientalistik,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ed. B. Spuler, i. 8.1.2), vol. i: The Early Period, E. J. Brill, Leiden,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 GENERAL INDEX</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/00/05_GENERAL_INDEX/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/iranic/zoro/articles/boyce_persian-stronghold/00/05_GENERAL_INDEX/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;74&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note; in the alphabetic order no distinction is made between č and ch, šaod sh, a and e, The Greek letters &amp;amp; and y are set after d and respectively, and Arabic Cain is ignored, as are differences in vowel-lengths. Ābān Niyāyes, 190&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ardāfravaš, 214 n. 5 ablutions before religious rites, 37, Ardekān, 10, 26, 40, 96 , 4&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;167, 216, 246, 259&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ardvahišt, 17, 50, 51, 68 Ābshāhi, 8, 24 . 49&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
