<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>&#43;01 Early Studies 1986–2000 on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</title>
    <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/</link>
    <description>Recent content in &#43;01 Early Studies 1986–2000 on आगमे विश्वासटिप्पन्यः</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>01 An Indian Image of Man</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/01_An_Indian_Image_of_Man/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/01_An_Indian_Image_of_Man/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An Inquiry into a Change of Perspective&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;in the Hindu World-view&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In his Einleitung in die Geschichte der Philosophie the renowned German philosopher G.W.F. Hegel made the following observation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dieses Hervortreten des Geistes hängt nach der geschichtlichen Seite damit zusam men, daß die politische Freiheit aufbluht; und die politische Freiheit, die Freiheit ¨ im Staate, hat da ihren Beginn, wo das Individuum sich als Individuum fuhlt, wo ¨ das Subjekt sich als solches in der Allgemeinheit weiß, oder wo das Bewußtsein der Pers¨onlichkeit, das Bewußtsein, in sich einen unendlichen Wert zu haben, zum Vorschein kommt,—indem ich mich fur mich setze und slechtin f ¨ ur mich gelte. [. . . ] ¨ Da fällt uns zuerst der Orient auf; [. . . ] denn [. . . ] der Geist geht wohl im Orient auf, aber das Verhältnis ist so, daß das Subjekt, die Individualität nicht Person ist, sondern als untergehend im Objektiven bestimmt ist. Das substantielle Verhältnis ist da das Herrschende. Die Substanz ist da teils als Ubersinnliches, als Gedanke, ¨ teils auch mehr materiell vorgestellt. Das Verhältnis des lndividuums, des Beson deren ist dann, daß er nur ein Negatives ist gegen das Substantielle. Das H¨ochste, wozu ein solches Individuum kommen kann, ist die ewige Seligkeit, welche nur ein Versinken in dieser Substanz, ein Vergehen des Bewußtseins, also Vernichtung des Subjekts und somit des Unterschieds zwischen Substanz und Subjekt ist. Das h¨ochste Verhältnis ist so die Bewußtlosigkeit. Insofern nun die Individuen diese Seligkeit nicht erlangt haben, sondern noch irdisch existieren, so sind sie aus dieser Einheit des Substantiellen und lndividuellen heraus; sie sind im Verhältnis, in der Bestimmung des Geistlosen, sie sind Substanzlose und—in Beziehung auf politi sche Freiheit—Rechtlose. Der Wille ist hier kein substantieller, sondern ein durch Willkur und Zuf ¨ älligkeit der Natur (z.B. durch Kasten) bestimmter, – ein Wesen der innerlichen Bewußtlosigkeit. 1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>02 Die indische Herausforderung</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/02_Die_indische_Herausforderung/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/02_Die_indische_Herausforderung/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hegels Beitrag zu einer europäischen&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;kulturhistorischen Diskussion&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Einleitung&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In den Jahren 1979, 1980 und 1981 erschienen drei Bucher, die sich jeweils ¨ mit Hegels Indien-Konzeption als zentralem Thema befasseṇDer Tatsache ih res kurz aufeinanderfolgenden Erscheinens ist es wahrscheinlich zuzuschreiben, daß die Autoren dieser drei Arbeiten wenig Gelegenheit hatten, um die Beiträge jeweils der beiden anderen zur Kenntnis zu nehmeṇUnd dementsprechend las sen sich diese drei Monographien als relativ unabhängige Forschungsbeiträge der Orient-Rezeption Hegels betrachteṇUmso bemerkenswerter ist es, obwohl die drei Bucher in Aufbau und Umfang sehr unterschiedlich sind, daß die drei ¨ Autoren darin ubereinstimmen, gegen die weitverbreitete Auffassung Stellung ¨ zu beziehen, daß sich Hegels Interpretation der indischen Kultur hauptsächlich auf sekundäre und dubiose Informationen stutzte, die ihm ausschließlich da- ¨ zu dienten, seine Vorurteile uber den Wert nichteurop ¨ äischer kultureller Lei stungen zu bestärkeṇVorurteile, die mit einem absoluten, rigiden Interpre tationsschema verbunden wären, mit dem Hegel versuchte die Diversität der Weltgeschichte zu einer Einheit zusammenzuschmieden, und die eine unbefan genen Kenttnisnahme und wissenschaflichen Urteilsfindung im Wege gestanden hätten.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>03 Ayodhyā : le nom et le lieu</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/03_ayodhyA_le_nom_et_le_lieu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/03_ayodhyA_le_nom_et_le_lieu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ayodhya conc¸ue : le nom ¯&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mais si ces noms absorb&lt;code&gt;erent &lt;/code&gt;a tout jamais l’image que j’avais de ces villes, ce ne fut qu’en la transformant, qu’en soumettant sa r´eapparition en moi `a leurs lois propres; ils eurent ainsi pour cons´equence de la rendre plus belle, mais aussi plus diff´erente de ce que les villes de Normandie ou de Toscane pouvaient ˆetre en r´ealit´e, et, en accroissant les joies arbitraires de mon imagination, d’aggraver la d´eception future de mes voyages. 1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>04 Ayodhyā: A Hindu Jerusalem</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/04_ayodhyA_A_Hindu_Jerusalem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/04_ayodhyA_A_Hindu_Jerusalem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An Investigation of ‘Holy War’ as a Religious Idea&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;in the Light of Communal Unrest in India&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the cultural discovery of India in the late eighteenth and early nineteenth century, Indian culture and society have been widely regarded as more than ordinarily pacifistic and moral. Johann Gottfried Herder (1744–1803), for ex ample, speaks of the brahmins as a ‘gentle race of men’, ‘happy lambs’ whose idea of God is ‘great and beautiful’ and whose ‘morals are pure and lofty’ (Bakker 1988, 99). This idealized image was enhanced in the twentieth century by the manner in which India freed itself from colonial rule; the non-violent resistance that Mahatma Gandhi both preached and practised. On the other hand, as every student of India knows, there have been few periods, even up to the present century, during which the South-Asian subcontinent has been free of war. And this fact seems to have been accepted by the Indians them selves as more or less in the natural order of things. Until the establishment and enforcement of the Pax Britannica, the waging of wars against rival rulers was generally regarded as one of the natural political tasks of kings and the aristocracy. 1&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>05 The Ramtek Inscriptions I</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/05_The_Ramtek_Inscriptions_I/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/05_The_Ramtek_Inscriptions_I/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The hill of Ramtek (21◦ 28´ N, 79◦ 28´ E), c. 45 km NE of Nagpur (Maha rashtra), merits special attention because it appears to be one of the few places in India where an uninterrupted historical development from the fourth century ad to the present day can be investigated through a series of archaeological monuments which, although partly restored or built over in later periods, seem never to have been exposed to destructive and iconoclastic forces. From at least the fifth century onwards the hill, also known as Rāmagiri, Sindūragiri, or Tapaṁgiri (Tapogiri), served as a regional centre of religious activity and, probably, also had a more secular function as an outstanding strategic base controlling the highway that connected, and still connects, the central and eastern part of the basin of the Ganges with the northern DeccaṇThis could possibly explain, at least in part, why the religious structures on top of the hill have attracted the attention and care of the rulers of the area from a very early date.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>06 The Ramtek Inscriptions II</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/06_The_Ramtek_Inscriptions_II/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/06_The_Ramtek_Inscriptions_II/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Vākāṭaka Inscription in the&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Kevala–Narasiṁha Temple&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hans ṬBakker &amp;amp; Harunaga Isaacson&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In The Ramtek Inscriptions I (hereafter RI) mention was made of a Vākāṭaka inscription in the Kevala–Narasiṁha Temple on Ramtek Hill, 1 the discovery of which was reported in IAR 1982–83, 137. The credit for first discussing, as well as editing the text goes to the Director of the Archaeological Survey and Museums of Maharashtra, Dr. A.P. Jamkhedkar. In an article which appeared in 1986 in R̥Parimoo (ed.), Vaiṣṇavism in Indian Arts and Culture (pp. 335– 41), 2 Jamkhedkar attributed the inscription to Prabhāvatī Guptā (Jamkhedkar 1987a, 340), an attribution for which he adduced arguments in a subsequent article that was published in ṀṢNagaraja Rao (ed.), Kusumāñjali, vol. I in 1987 (Jamkhedkar 1987b, pp. 217–23). In the latter publication the text of the inscription was edited and an interpretation of it was given (op. cit. 220 f.). In the same year Ajay Mitra Shastri’s Early History of the Deccan appeared, chapter V (pp. 45–81) of which deals with ‘The Vākāṭaka: fresh epigraphic evidence’. This chapter is for the greater part a reprint of the author’s earlier publication in the Nagpur University Journal (vol. 35 (1984–86), 130–64) with the exception of the Appendix (pp. 68–74). The appendix may have been added to the book in a late phase of its production, since the text of the endnotes&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>07 Throne and Temple</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/07_Throne_and_Temple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/07_Throne_and_Temple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Political Power and Religious Prestige in Vidarbha&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1983 a volume of Essays on Gupta Culture (ediṭby Bardwell ḶSmith) appeared in which two articles have a special relevance for the matter discussed in the present paper. Burton Stein, in his contribution entitled Mahānavamī. Medieval and Modern Kingly Ritual in South India (op. cit. 67–90), analyses the difference in status or nature of the kings of the Gupta period (4th–5th centuries) and those of Vijayanagara one millennium later, a difference that may be understood from the different (royal) rituals performed or organized by them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>08 Little Kr̥ṣṇa’s Play with the Moon</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/08_Little_kRShNas_Play_with_the_Moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/08_Little_kRShNas_Play_with_the_Moon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The literary evidence&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Within the collection of hymns (Tirumolī) attributed to Viṭṭucittaṉ, also known as the ‘Great Saint’, Periyāḻvār (9th century ad), we find ‘a series of indepen dent songs, [in which] Periyāḻvār envisages the childhood of Kr̥ṣṇa through various games and ceremonies such as a real South Indian child would play and go through’ (Hardy 1983a, 406). Friedhelm Hardy, from whose Viraha–Bhakti I derive this information, styled this section the Bālacarita. It contains folk songs which, Hardy observes, afterwards came to form part of the genre styled piḷḷaitamiḻ, ‘songs accompanying the games etc. of children’ (Hardy ibid.), ‘de picting the child-life of a hero or god’ (Zvelebil 1974, 102). In one of the ten stages which constitute this genre, the mother, Yaśodā, calls the moon to play with the child Kr̥ṣṇa. 1 ‘Whence’, Hardy asks, ‘did Periyāḻvār derive the inspi ration for his Bālacarita?’ This scholar points to the Harivaṁśa (HV 60.15), in which, just as in one of the Aḻvār’s songs (III.5), Kr̥ṣṇa is said to eat a ‘lake of&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>09 Puranic Literature Methodology</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/09_Puranic_Literature_Methodology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/09_Puranic_Literature_Methodology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some Methodological Considerations with&#xA;Respect to the Critical Edition of&#xA;Puranic Literature∗&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Remarkably, two much-debated issues appear to have had little or no conse quence for the editing of classical Sanskrit texts. I am thinking of Paul Hacker’s methodology for the investigation of anonymous Sanskrit literature, 1 as well as of a field of study that might be referred to as ‘oral poetics’. Neither Hacker him self nor any of his pupils whose investigations were concerned with the historical development of Viṣṇu’s avatars have provided us with solid text-editions to un derpin their findings. 2 On the other hand, although Indian literature avowedly comprises one of the world’s greatest oral traditions, Sanskritists have seldom had recourse to the theories about oral poetry developed by scholars of other languages, nor has Sanskrit material been taken into account in, for instance, C.ṀBowra’ s Heroic Poetry, in A.B. Lord’s The Singer of Tales, or in such general works as Oral Poetry. Das Problem der Mündlichkeit mittelalterlicher epischer Dichtung, or Ruth Finnegan’s Oral Poetry (1977). If we think of the studies of Emeneau (1958), and Kailasapathy (1968), or John Smith, 3 we must conclude that Dravidian and New Indo-Aryan literary traditions are thought to be more appropriate for an investigation along the lines of comparative oral poetics than their Sanskrit counterparts. In this respect the neglect of classical anonymous Sanskrit literature is understandable, if we think of puranic litera ture of which the written nature (Schriftlichkeit) has never been seriously ques tioned since Kirfel’s ‘Erschütterung’ of the ‘Hypothese von der Jahrhunderte langen mündlichen Tradition gr¨osserer Texte in Indien’ in the Introduction of&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Mokṣadharma 187 and 239–241 Reconsidered</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/10_moxadharma_187_and_239241_Reconsidered/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/10_moxadharma_187_and_239241_Reconsidered/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;∗ Hans ṬBakker &amp;amp; Peter C. Bisschop&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Preamble&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In his Untersuchungen zum Mokṣadharma (Die sāṁkhyistischen Texte) and in the chapter on Sāṁkhya of his Geschichte der indischen Philosophie Erich Frauwallner has shown chapters MBh 12.187 and MBh 12.239–241 of the Mokṣadharma in the Sāntiparvan ´ of the Mahābhārata to be of crucial importance for understanding the development of the Sāṁkhya-system. 1 The great Viennese scholar dealt with yet another chapter (MBhB 12.286), which however has been omitted in the critical edition, but is preserved in the critical apparatus to MBh 12.187. Conceived as different versions of one and the same ‘Grundtext’, they must, Frauwallner argued, have been held to be of great significance at the time and probably led an independent existence before they were included in the collection of doctrines of the Mokṣadharma. Frauwallner attempted a reconstruction of this ‘Grundtext’ by sorting out words and passages that were judged by him not to have belonged to this text originally. He succeeded in giving a clear description of a distinctive philosophy, which he denominated ‘die epische Urform des Sāṁkhya’. 2 An important conclusion of his reconstruction is that the so called ‘evolution theory’ had not yet been developed; according to Frauwallner the evolution theory was adopted by the Sāṁkhya later from circles that taught an evolution out of Brahman. 3&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 Dakṣiṇa Kosala</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/11_daxiNa_Kosala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/11_daxiNa_Kosala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Observations on the History and Culture of&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dakṣiṇa Kosala∗&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fifth to Seventh Centuries ad&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The historiography of the region called Dakṣiṇa Kosala, nowadays generally known as Chhattisgarh, is beset with difficulties of a predominantly chrono logical nature. Apart from quite a number of inscriptions, we do not possess written sources that can help us to unravel its early history. The chronological problems are due to the fact that, with one isolated exception, the charters of its kings are dated in regnal years. Moot questions, such as the dating of the kings of Sarabhapur, the relation, if any, between the Pān ´ . ḍava dynasties of Mekalā and Kosala, or the date of King Tīvaradeva, have been discussed again and again by a number of scholars during the last fifty years, a debate that has been dominated by three eminent Indian epigraphists, V.V. Mirashi, ḌC. Sircar, and A.ṀShastri. A first reading of this facinating corpus of learned articles gives the uncomfortable feeling that these three scholars dis agree among themselves on almost every issue. Only laborious study makes one realize that in this debate a large body of historical evidence has been dis closed and evaluated, as a result of which we know to date considerably more about the history and culture of this region than half a century ago. Still, many inscriptions await publication and this is, unfortunately, in particular true for those on stone. Unlike copperplate charters, stone epigraphs often inform us about particular historical circumstances and details beyond the official royal records. They are less formal and regulated, but they are usually more difficult to decipher and this may have hampered their publication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12 Somaśarman, Somavaṁśa and Somasiddhānta</title>
      <link>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/12_somasharman_somavaMsha_and_somasiddhAnta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vishvAsa.github.io/AgamaH/AryaH/hinduism/sAmya-vaiShamye/articles/Sacred-ground_Bakker/01_Early_Studies_19862000/12_somasharman_somavaMsha_and_somasiddhAnta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Somaśarman, Somavaṁśa and Somasiddhānta A Pāśupata tradition in seventh-century&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dakṣiṇa Kosala∗&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Studies in the Skandapurāṇa III&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Haraya Namah ¯ .&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first fruit of Minoru Hara’s life-task-project to clarify the early history of the Saiva religion appeared in the ´ Indo-Iranian Journal of 1958 under the title Nakulīśa–Pāśupata–Darśanam. This was followed by the submission of his dis sertation, Materials for the study of Pāśupata Saivism ´ , to the Department of Sanskrit and Indian Studies of Harvard University in 1966 (Hara 1967). Ever since, Hara has contributed to the research into the history of the Pāśupata religion by a continuous series of meticulous studies. 1 Thanks to these studies our knowledge of this enigmatic but fascinating branch of early Hinduism has significantly increased. Paucity of sources, however, has inevitably hampered our understanding of the process of origin and spread of this religious move ment. Hara, like other scholars before him, duly recognized that the puranic text corpus contains numerous references to the Pāśupata religioṇYet, due to inconsistencies of all sorts and uncertainty as to their exact dates, he consid ered, rightly, the use of these texts for historic purposes a hazardous affair and consequently assigned them to the periphery of historical research. That is to say, for the time being, since,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
